<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-10-24T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Move</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/10/24/move/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/10/24/move/</id>
    <published>2016-10-24T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-10-29T18:46:26+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All mankind is divided into three classes: those that are immovable, those that are movable, and those that move.
&lt;cite&gt;Benjamin Franklin&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t always know what to do. Where to focus, when to say yes, when to say no. One thing I do know is that I must do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. I must try. Experiment. Dabble. Try things out for size. Learn. Repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I am not is stationary. That’s the most dangerous state to be in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sitting. Idle. Watching the world go by. Criticising the movers or silently abdicating any participation. Either way, standing still is deadly. I don’t care whether it’s due to apathy or fear. If you stand still long enough you &lt;em&gt;will die&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We aren’t made to stand still. We’re made to explore. To learn, to grow, to conquer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are not static, you are alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The world&lt;/em&gt; may have pinned you down and put you in a box, but what &lt;em&gt;the world&lt;/em&gt; forgets is the miracle that you’re even here, housed in a skeleton, riding laps around a blazing ball of fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be one of the immovables. Life’s too short. Join us, the movers, as we wander the terrain, exploring, learning, growing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take action today. Start small. Do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. You were born to live.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Consistency</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/10/17/consistency/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/10/17/consistency/</id>
    <published>2016-10-17T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-10-25T21:12:03+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Consistency is one of the hardest things to achieve. Especially at the beginning. Creating a new habit, starting a new routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst it is tough, consistency is also key. Without consistency you won’t ever get anywhere. With consistency, you can make true progress towards your goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting is easy. The initial rush of a new idea, new possibilities. You’re fresh. Not worn down. It’s a blank slate. Exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The early days can be quite fun. Everything is new. Potential abounds. Launching can bring a little spike in traffic. Attention. Momentum. Vanity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the early days are over though, normality sets in. Routine appears, and it’s greyscale. It’s not what it was. The initial spotlight fades, numbers drop, the quick wins evaporate, and all that’s left is, hard work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the danger zone. The honeymoon period is over. You’re in a desert, losing water, eagles hovering overhead. Will you push through and find a way, or will you let the surroundings overwhelm you, stagnating, slowing, dying?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consistency was born for such a time as this. Keep plodding on. One foot after the other. The road moving under you. You’re reeling it in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consistency is boring. Unattractive. Mundane. It’s quiet, whispering to you, let’s keep going. We’ve got a place to be. Onwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This mundane, quiet voice whispers to you just as the noise increases. This is new. This isn’t what you expected. This is hard. This isn’t for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re out of your depth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s the point. That’s where consistency takes you. To places you’ve not been before. To challenges you’ve not faced before. To adventures you’ve never dreamt of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consistency leads you. You strain to hear it’s voice over the noise. You catch glimpses. You cherish these. You feed off these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you continue, you find the noise doesn’t disappear, but you get used to it. You gain small victories over it. You begin to bottle these victories, and use them as fuel to push you forwards. The noise loses it’s edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You tune your ear to the beat of the drum. Today. Tomorrow. Again. Again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Routine becomes habit. Habit becomes consistent. Consistent becomes us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You fly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You fly, over the noise, using it, and your victories over it, to keep you going. To stay aloft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your life is moving forwards. You’re making progress. You’re taking steps, each day. Each week you’ve moved on, each month, another stake in the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Months pass. Years. You look back. Who was that person? They look familiar, yet, strange. Similar, yet different. They look like you, but they’re not you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve changed.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>It's Hard</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/10/10/its-hard/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/10/10/its-hard/</id>
    <published>2016-10-10T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-10-17T16:56:28+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This past week Mike and I have been travelling through California. It’s been great to come out here, get some time away from the day job and our side projects and gain some new perspective on it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple months back we did something new: we started a podcast. It was something we’ve been thinking about doing for a while, and we finally decided to go for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We knew that it would be tough to start out, but the reality of a new routine is always different to the idea of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve spent nearly all of our spare time the past couple months on the podcast. We often each spend a few hours prepping the episode, then the same again recording it, to release a short 20 minute episode to our ~300 listeners at the end. Is this worth it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know the answer. Time spent on one thing is time not spent on another. Should we be spending more time on starting a startup or building an audience?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is the format of the show right? Can we optimise it to have a better ROI from our time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing how to spend our time is hard. Especially with new routines. The reality is we spend more time at the start for less return. If we keep podcasting for a year, and do a decent job of promoting it, we’ll have more listeners, more &lt;em&gt;engaged&lt;/em&gt; listeners, whilst spending less time on it, having gotten used to and optimised the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every project has some version of the &lt;a href="http://andrewchen.co/after-the-techcrunch-bump-life-in-the-trough-of-sorrow/"&gt;trough of sorrow&lt;/a&gt;. Once the initial buzz of launching wears off, you’re just left with the hard work of doing something new over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s normally a few months into a project that we start to feel this pressure. The quick wins are over, the initial momentum slows a little, the reality looks different to the dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to want to move on when a new habit takes longer to stick or is harder than we thought, but that’s only ever the answer if there’s truly something better to change &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt;. At some point we’ve got to stick at something, get good at it, and play the long game. No-one ever achieved anything great by continually restarting over and over. Restarts are useful only if they’re followed by commitment and hard work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;"Opportunity is missed by most people because it is dressed in overalls and looks like work."
&lt;cite&gt;Thomas Edison&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now it’s too early to tell. We’re still finding our feet podcasting, trying to find the format that works, the balance of quality and time spent. This experiment doesn’t have enough data to be statistically significant yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For us, it’s time to move onwards, to push through the post launch slump and continue the experiment, all the while asking, &lt;em&gt;"is this the best use of our time?".&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Am I Doing It Right?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/10/03/am-i-doing-it-right/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/10/03/am-i-doing-it-right/</id>
    <published>2016-10-03T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-10-29T18:47:23+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Am I on the right path? Am I making the &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; decisions? I wonder about this a lot. If you’ve any ambition then it’s probably one that goes around in your head, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem: there is no &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt;. We don’t have a plan that we simply need to follow step by step. At every stage there are decisions to be made. Little ones that come together to make up our day, and big ones, that drastically alter the course of our life, and the lives of those around us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But knowing this doesn’t abate the nagging. It’s still there. Gnawing at my ankles as I stumble forwards, are you on the &lt;em&gt;right path?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Direction is important. I might not be on the perfect path, but I can at head in the right direction. There are things we can all do to get closer to where we want to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Progress is the metric I’m really interested in. It’s hard to quantify, sort of an amalgamation of a bunch of smaller indicators. Am I making progress in life? Am I using the resources I have been given to move forwards, investing them to get a greater return, or burying them away for fear of the consequences should I use them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Progress can take many shapes and sizes, but it is something core to us as humans. We should always be learning, doing, growing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t done everything I could this year. I haven’t achieved all the goals I set out to. But I have done some important things. I may not have made the progress I’d like, but I’ve made progress nonetheless, and good progress too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m at a different place to this time last year, a better place. But still, in amongst new surroundings, new circumstances, new challenges, that feeling nags away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Am I doing it right? Is there something I’m missing?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is quite similar to last weeks. So if you liked this, you might like that: &lt;a href="/2016/09/26/discomfort/"&gt;Discomfort&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>discomfort</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/09/26/discomfort/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/09/26/discomfort/</id>
    <published>2016-09-26T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-10-29T19:26:19+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Discomfort. The lack of comfort. Not always as bad as it seems?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discomfort is healthy. As humans we need to regularly step outside our comfort zones. That’s where life is truly lived. But what if this discomfort isn’t momentary, but sticks around for weeks, months, years?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was chatting to a buddy the other day about him potentially quitting his great job at a top tech startup in a beautiful city to move home with his parents and work on his own stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to laugh at how good he had it, yet still felt like maybe this wasn’t where he should really be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often discomfort is there for a reason, trying to tell us something. It’s saying “there’s something more, come explore it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a similar experience a couple of years ago. I was working an interesting job with great people on something I was passionate about. I liked the area and was surrounded by a great bunch of people on a daily basis. Yet still something felt &lt;em&gt;not quite right&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feeling built up over months, nagging at me. “This isn’t your place anymore. This season is coming to an end, it’s time for something new.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deep down I knew this moment would come, I just didn’t know when. I certainly didn’t want to pre-emptively put it into motion when it wasn’t yet time. Leaving my job and life as it was before it was time would have made me truly sad. I didn’t want to be hasty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew I had desires I’d yet to see fulfilled, and areas I wanted to explore that I had yet to do, I just wasn’t sure &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I sat on the idea for months. I dwelt on it, weighing it up, feeling it from every angle. Is it really time for me to move on, or am I just taking the easy way out? Will I regret taking this step now, is it too early? How can I leave when it’s so good here?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, after over six months of deliberation, I decided to move on. I just knew in the depths of me that it was time. Time to step out into the next season. I didn’t know what that next season really looked like, other than a few marker points, but I took the step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d felt it from every direction, this was it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d work more on my own stuff. I’d learn some core skills that I’d need for the next step. I’d slow down a bit, and not rush too quick on exactly what it all looked like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I moved back to my parents. After five years away, I came back, slowed down, and started chipping away at what I thought this next season would be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Little by little I made progress. It wasn’t always easy, I didn’t always know whether to go down path A or path B. But I tried them out for size, and learnt as I went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I applied for jobs in Australia. I applied for a job in London. I got a job in London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job was all I’d wanted. It was doing the job I wanted to do, good pay, good location, interesting product, great people. I learnt a tonne from it. I got the job as a direct result of the work I’d been doing since leaving my old job. Without that I wouldn’t have got this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eighteen months on, that feeling came around again. Should I still be here? Is this my place? Is it time to move on? Pivot or persevere?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After feeling through the discomfort once more, it started to become clear that it was time for a change. I’d changed a lot in those 18 months. The company had changed a lot. We were both in different places with different needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discomfort struck again, and forced me to re-evaluate my plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, I dwelt on it for a few months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a step and announced my intention to move on within a couple of months. I wasn’t sure exactly what was next, I just knew it was time for next. This chapter was coming to a close, it was time to step out again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often that’s how it is. We don’t know what the next step is, we just know in the core of us what it’s not. It’s not about petulance or entitlement, it’s just a knowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The desires we’ve put off for tomorrow, are now for today. We can either choose to live in the past, in the known, or step out into what today has for us, trusting we’ll be able to work it out on the journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since making that decision my options became clearer and the right path ahead emerged. I left my old gig and am now in the place I know I should be, at least for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s something to be said for persevering through tough times, or even just through the mundane. I’m not advocating that we should jump from one thing to the next as soon as our rose tinted glasses lose their colour. The ability to stick at something over a long period is a key skill any entrepreneur has to master. Rome wasn’t built in a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, we aren’t made to do the same thing over and over and over and over. There comes a time when it’s time for a change. It’s just working out &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be hard to know when that time comes. Hard to decide between sticking it out and pushing through, and moving onto something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often the path ahead is unclear. Knowing what’s ‘right’ is no scientific endeavour. But often our discomfort can lead us, whispering to us over and over, “have you looked over here? It’s time now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each week I write a post and record a podcast episode. Get both in your inbox every Tuesday, free of charge. Sign up, no spam, I promise. &lt;a href="https://wearecontrast.com/signup"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes please&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>burnout</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/09/19/burnout/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/09/19/burnout/</id>
    <published>2016-09-19T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-09-27T09:34:20+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like listening? We recorded an episode of our brand new podcast on this very topic. &lt;a href="https://hitreply.co/3"&gt;Listen to it here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not letting one side outweigh and overpower the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work and life. Should these be balanced? Or should they be one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard a &lt;a href="http://www.vanschneider.com/worklife-balance-is-bullsht/"&gt;couple&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://designlife.fm/episode36/"&gt;opinions&lt;/a&gt; recently that attempting to achieve work-life balance is solving the wrong problem. When work and life go hand in hand, there’s no need to balance them right? If one succeeds, so does the other. It’s not a zero sum game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What then, are we to make of burnout?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is burnout only something that occurs when you’re working on something that doesn’t resonate with the rest of your life? Is it only when you’re working for The Man, be it your boss, or your VC, or even yourself?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we set ourselves unrealistic expectations, and drive ourselves to work every waking hour to get them done. For some of us, VC’s are putting an unspoken pressure on us that if we don’t work so hard that we sleep at our desks then we’re not really made for the entrepreneurial game. Sometimes our boss tells us of a hard deadline and we have to break ourselves just to get it done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been watching the latter first hand the past couple months. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mikeaag"&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt;, the guy I work with, co-founder, partner in crime extraordinaire, has been maxed out at work. He’s gone above and beyond his normal levels to fulfil a specific hard deadline at his day job. He’s running on empty, but feels like he needs to keep running to meet the requirements of his 9-5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike loves what he does, and enjoys our work on the side too. He’d go as far as to say that the work we do with &lt;a href="http://wearecontrast.com/"&gt;Contrast&lt;/a&gt; is a hobby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When your hobby is starting your own startup on the side, what does resting look like? Is it healthy to come home from an intense day at work and spend more time in the evening coding?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are questions that I’ve been thinking about lately, in a bid to avoid making things worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does it look like to be burnt out? I’ve not been there, but Mike’s pretty close. In this week’s episode of Hit Reply, I spoke with Mike about what it’s like from the inside, and our thoughts on whether it can be avoided, and if so, how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out: &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/hitreply/episode-3-burnout"&gt;https://soundcloud.com/hitreply/episode-3-burnout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each week I write a post and record a podcast episode. Get both in your inbox every Tuesday, free of charge. Sign up, no spam, I promise. &lt;a href="https://wearecontrast.com/signup"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes please&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
