<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Connecting Things</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/12/05/connecting-things/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/12/05/connecting-things/</id>
    <published>2016-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-12-06T10:37:16+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Solving problems is at the heart of any great product or business. Behind every shiny product or lightbulb idea is a real problem being solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When trying to solve a problem, there are two key activities we must undertake, data gathering and data connecting. The more data points you gather, the more you’ll have to connect together to form creative patterns. As Steve Jobs said, &lt;em&gt;“creativity is just connecting things.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to make the best data connections is to collect two types of data, specific and generic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specific data is the information you learn about the problem you’re trying to solve. So if you’re trying to help mechanics improve their day to day life, then you should spend time with some mechanics. Read a variety of mechanics books and magazines. Interview mechanics, asking them a bunch of open ended questions. Soak up all sorts of information about mechanics, why they do what they do, what they enjoy doing, what they dislike doing, what they struggle doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then once you’ve spent enough time getting into the head of the mechanics, you should start to see a pattern emerge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing this sort of investigating can be fun when you’re in the flow, other times it’s a bit of a drag but you plough on, but either way I find it easy to justify this time as work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other side to data gathering is the generic data points. This can come from anywhere. Reading about anything you’re interested in is a great way to collect generic data. Listening to podcasts or audio books and watching films and documentaries are more great ways to add depth and variety into our general data store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This generic data collection doesn’t feel like work at all, and it isn’t really, it’s just life. But the more non-specific data you collect the more interesting combinations you can make when you come to connect the data points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connecting the data points can happen anytime, anywhere. Often a good amount of this will happen hand in hand with gathering data points. As you’re learning about the people you’re looking to help and the problems they’re experiencing you’ll start to see threads appear between the different data points you’ve been gathering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often though, we need to get away from our normal surroundings to create the best connections. Have you ever noticed how many of our best ideas happen in the shower?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jonah Lehrer thinks its to do with quietening ourselves, stopping ourselves from being externally distracted to listen to our subconscious that’s already been making some of these connections:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“…so many insights happen during warm showers. For many people, it’s the most relaxing part of the day. It’s not until we’re being massaged by warm water, unable to check our e-mail, that we’re finally able to hear the quiet voices in the backs of our heads telling us about the insight. The answers have been their all along–we just weren’t listening.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Showers are a classic breeding ground for creative connections, but so are quiet, scenic walks. I find I’m often scribbling down insights (read: tweeting) that come to me as I go for a walk through a local field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But despite this increased creativity, I often find it hard to justify going on these walks, as it doesn’t &lt;em&gt;feel like&lt;/em&gt; work (don’t worry I shower every day). Every step I take outside of my door is a step away from my laptop, where I &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; I should be, &lt;em&gt;being productive&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Doing the work&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s an issue. If I’m to solve the most interesting problems in the most effective, creative ways, then I need to give myself time to breathe. To quieten myself. To not be distracted. I need to take the time to connect the dots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is as much work as data gathering. I have to discipline myself to step away from my laptop and relax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find the balance between focus and quiet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The balance between data gathering and data connecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Creativity is just connecting things. When you ask creative people how they did something, they feel a little guilty because they didn’t really do it, they just saw something. It seemed obvious to them after a while. That’s because they were able to connect experiences they’ve had and synthesize new things. And the reason they were able to do that was that they’ve had more experiences or they have thought more about their experiences than other people. Unfortunately, that’s too rare a commodity. A lot of people in our industry haven’t had very diverse experiences. So they don’t have enough dots to connect, and they end up with very linear solutions without a broad perspective on the problem. The broader one’s understanding of the human experience, the better design we will have.
&lt;cite&gt;Steve Jobs, Wired, February 1995&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>That's the problem</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/11/28/that-s-the-problem/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/11/28/that-s-the-problem/</id>
    <published>2016-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-29T09:47:57+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was looking through our problem/idea list recently, and a few ideas jumped out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of those was an idea for goal tracking for teams. It was born from a personal pain point as an employee at a company that used to set short, medium and long term goals. The only issue was, they never told us what they were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I got thinking. What if I built something to solve this problem?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution I had in mind was just a simple system of logging goals, sharing and viewing them. The pain point was getting everyone on the same page. And it turns out &lt;em&gt;that was the problem.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked about this in &lt;a href="http://startupfoundation.co/hashtag_startup/"&gt;Startup Chat&lt;/a&gt; recently, and someone mentioned how at her company of 30 they use a simple Google doc. No fancy software, just a simple shared doc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This surprised me. For a team of 30 I envisioned them using some purpose built tool with a few extra features, not a simple Google doc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then I remembered something &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mijustin"&gt;Justin Jackson&lt;/a&gt; said a while back in his post, &lt;a href="https://justinjackson.ca/we-are-not-normal-people/"&gt;we are not normal people&lt;/a&gt;. He was at his barbers, dreaming of how he could improve their scheduling setup. How he could build out a new software solution that would bring the hairdressers archaic paper system into the twenty-first century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out, his barber had already tried out a bunch of software solutions, likely from similar conversations had with other tech minded clients, and they were all horrible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One particular point of Justin’s story stands out. His barber said this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;"All the software I’ve tried just gets in the way."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is key. Software, far from being a knight in shining armour, was actually overkill for him. An unnecessary burden. It was a more complicated process than simply looking at a paper calendar and writing directly on that. It wasn’t a problem he was motivated to solve because the core of the pain point was solved in the simplest way possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any software solution might make gains on the periphery but the core issue was already solved for the one that mattered. The barber was the one who used the system and who decided how their businesses money would be spent, and they were not motivated to fix this problem because they didn’t see it as a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same goes for my company goal tracking idea. There could be some gains made by using a purpose built piece of software, but the core task of logging goals and being able to view them was already solved. It’s solved by whiteboards and it’s solved by shared docs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem, in my mind, was getting everyone &lt;em&gt;on the same page.&lt;/em&gt; The issue with this idea was that the tools they were using already did this, quite literally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In development terms, all I was looking to create was a glorified &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Create,_read,_update_and_delete"&gt;CRUD&lt;/a&gt;. Create goals. Read goals. Update goals. Delete goals. Whiteboards or shared docs are the best solution for this for a lot of companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a common problem. &lt;em&gt;The problem entrepreneurs have with problems.&lt;/em&gt; As creative entrepreneurial types, we’re always on the lookout for problems we can solve. Processes we can improve. Shiny things we can create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to try and create systems and solutions that are complex and beautiful but people just want the easiest, simplest way to get the job done. Often that’s using a tool they already have and know how to use. A new shiny interface isn’t a plus, it’s a hindrance.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Perfect</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/11/21/perfect/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/11/21/perfect/</id>
    <published>2016-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-22T09:10:02+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;But.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s flawed.&lt;br /&gt;
But there’s competitors.&lt;br /&gt;
But it’ll be hard.&lt;br /&gt;
But I don’t know how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s so easy to let but stop us. It stops us from taking steps forwards, for fear that it might not work out. Fear that we’ll waste our time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead, we wait for perfect. We wait for that moment when &lt;em&gt;the idea&lt;/em&gt; comes. We wait for &lt;em&gt;the one&lt;/em&gt;, that’s a sweet combination of unique genius, no competition, that requires nothing new from us, no new learning, everything is  known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wait. But the idea never comes. Nothing quite holds up. Everything has a reason to stop us pursuing it. But. But. But.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every idea starts out like this. I've yet to come across a problem that's not being solved &lt;em&gt;somehow&lt;/em&gt;, an idea that doesn't have some weaknesses, an idea that doesn't force me to do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; I've not done before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perfection freezes us in our tracks. It stops us from ever moving forwards. At some point we’ve got to leave perfection behind, and move ahead into the unknown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dance with the idea. Play with it. Try things out. Embrace the frailties, embrace the unknown. Embrace the likelihood of failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop waiting for the perfect moment.&lt;br /&gt;
Stop waiting for the perfect problem.&lt;br /&gt;
Stop waiting for the perfect team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>It's time for change</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/11/14/it-s-time-for-change/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/11/14/it-s-time-for-change/</id>
    <published>2016-11-14T09:16:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-15T09:41:06+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been said that to achieve great work you must kill your darlings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s what we’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past few months we’ve spent a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of time on our new podcast, &lt;a href="http://hitreply.co/"&gt;Hit Reply&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d spend a few hours prepping each episode, often more, and then a couple of hours each recording it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Podcasting is new for us. It’s different to our previous projects.  It’s taken time to get going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge has been how can we create as much value for our listeners in as little time for them? Could we provide the same amount of value in a compact 20 minute episode as a longer 45 minute episode?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were conscious of wanting to create something that had the highest return on investment for our listeners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the emphasis on not wasting people’s time, on trimming the fluff, has led to bloated time investment on our side. It’s led to a podcast that’s become almost a spoken blog post. &lt;em&gt;It’s not what we set out to do in the beginning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve spent the past month or so thinking through where we want to go, whether our goals are still the same as they were before, and whether our current activities are the best way to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, we’ve come to realise that the podcast’s not been the right &lt;a href="https://justinjackson.ca/want/"&gt;product/founder fit&lt;/a&gt; for us right now. It’s not been utilising our strengths, our unfair advantages, it’s not the most effective way to go from where we are now to where we want to be. It’s not been the best use of our time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, we’re going to focus on a new plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new plan is fairly simple. We’re going to talk to people about what they do and any struggles they have until we discover a problem worth solving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll prototype and develop. Test out ideas and learn. And we’ll go from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This all sounds rather fluffy. To combat that, we've set quarterly goals we'll aim to meet, and will be accountable to our &lt;a href="https://ryanbattles.com/post/what-is-a-mastermind-group"&gt;mastermind groups&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s painful to stop something we’ve invested a fair amount of time in already, something that’s already providing a certain amount of value. But if we’re to ever get to where we want to be, we’ve got to focus on the work that will help get us there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve got to &lt;a href="http://fredrivett.com/2016/10/31/create-your-own-path/"&gt;create our own path&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve got to kill our darlings.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Busy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/11/07/busy/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/11/07/busy/</id>
    <published>2016-11-07T13:28:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-07T13:29:58+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The days go by quicker now. It’s Monday again. Where did that week go?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The years go by quicker now. It’s New Years Eve again. Where did that year go?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re all so &lt;em&gt;busy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sometimes wonder about how we should best live our lives. We’re often so intent on cramming &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; into every crevice of our every day lives that we never take the time to simply be. To be present &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; that day. To take time &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; a moment. To pick our head up and look around, and just be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re too busy getting &lt;em&gt;there&lt;/em&gt;. Going to that &lt;em&gt;other place&lt;/em&gt;. Making sure we’re ready for it. Making sure that we’ll be prepared when it comes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it comes, and we’re busy. Too busy to notice. To realise that anything much is going on. Too numbed by constant movement to appreciate that the very moments we’re preparing for are passing us by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s so easy to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I’m being wise? If I stop being busy now, my future will be worse. There is definitely an element of truth to this. We cannot simply stop preparing for the future and live in today. Tomorrow will come too, we hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must strike the balance. Balance between creating the best future for tomorrow, whilst not repeatedly giving over all of today for it. We have to claim back some of today. We have to cash in some of our time. We have to budget for living, for being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we never stop to live, to breathe, to be, the next time we look up we’ll realise life has passed us by again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s be present in the moment. Be conscious of our blessings, and conscious of our challenges. Try to be thankful for what we’ve got, if we can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being present sounds like airy fairy rubbish, but it’s important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s set aside time when we’re not &lt;em&gt;busy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s be present.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Create Your Own Path</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/10/31/create-your-own-path/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/10/31/create-your-own-path/</id>
    <published>2016-10-31T08:27:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-07T13:31:12+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent the past six months thinking about this. It’s been on the back of my mind constantly, and at the front often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s something I care deeply about. Making the most of it. Making the best use of it. Not wasting it. My time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically, because I’ve cared so much about not wasting my time, I’ve done exactly that. I’ve been caught up in trying to &lt;em&gt;do it right&lt;/em&gt;. To do it all now. In analysis paralysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Is this the right path?”
“Am I doing it right”?
“Is this the most efficient way to get from here to there, to reach my goals?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These thoughts have been ever present. Every move questioned. Every step doubted. Every option over-analysed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s brought what was a nicely chugging vehicle to a near stand still. Progress has slowed to a halt. And it’s not even as if I’m getting any rest, it’s been exhausting. Wasteful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All because I missed something so simple. One simple truth that I knew but didn’t know. Something that only now has finally clicked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There isn’t &lt;em&gt;one path&lt;/em&gt; to take, there aren’t any. You’ve got to create your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent way too long working out if &lt;em&gt;this path&lt;/em&gt; was right, or &lt;em&gt;that path&lt;/em&gt;. I’ve tried to “do it right”, putting off my gut instincts and ignoring what I’m good at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No, there isn’t a “right way”, only best practices that work in some cases and not in others.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These best practices are important. They’re the general guidelines that have worked in the past, and will probably help in the future too. They help to shape our plans, but they shouldn’t drive them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, our plans should be driven by purpose, passion and intrigue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questioning is right, it’s healthy. But the questioning should never be about “what’s right” in a fixed sense, but what seems to make sense to do based on the data available to you now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to create your path is to collect data and try stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collecting that data involves listening to others stories, hearing about their successes, and their failures too. Picking out patterns and understanding the underlying principles behind it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating your own path isn’t shunning everyone else, being a closed off know it all. It’s the total opposite. It forces you to be &lt;em&gt;more open&lt;/em&gt; because you’ll never know when other people’s paths will help guide yours, and how your story will help shape theirs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why it’s so important to surround yourself. &lt;a href="https://learningtolaunch.co/read#6-surround-yourself"&gt;Surround yourself&lt;/a&gt; with great people. Surround yourself with learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Store it all up. Soak it all in. After a while it starts to paint a picture, and this picture can help guide you as you paint your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surround yourself with clever, creative, inspirational people. Surround yourself with &lt;a href="http://fredrivett.com/2016/10/24/move/"&gt;the movers&lt;/a&gt;. Help them create their path, and let them help you create yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allow yourself to dream. Think about how you want the world to be. Think about how you can make it more like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set big audacious long term goals that will stretch you, and specific, attainable, short term smart goals that will help take you there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell those you surround yourself with the dreams and tell them the goals. Let them be the ones to bring you back on path when you wander off, let them help you shake off the baggage and propel you forwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then move. Create. Try. Experiment. Do. Follow your inquisition, do what you’re good at. Do what you enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while you’ll be known for that. You’ll be the person that does X. The loud one. The quiet one. The &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll build an audience. A genuine bunch of people who like who you are and most of what you say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People gravitate towards those who are &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt;. Those who have integrity. We love transparency, we love vulnerability. Embrace all of this as you create your path. Bring others along for the journey, and in so doing help them to create theirs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this &lt;em&gt;because I’ve seen it&lt;/em&gt;. Just look at &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/pjrvs"&gt;Paul Jarvis&lt;/a&gt;. He’s, well, Paul. He does things his way and he’s not afraid to show it. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/levelsio"&gt;Pieter Levels&lt;/a&gt;. He’s controversial, outspoken, and he makes things happen. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dhh"&gt;DHH&lt;/a&gt; is similar. You can’t put him in a box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this &lt;em&gt;because I’ve felt it&lt;/em&gt;. I’ve experienced trying to find the “right path”, desperately searching for the industry approved short cuts, and I’ve found out that it doesn’t exist. It’s a myth. I’ve tried doing it this way, that way, the other way, and now I’m trying it my way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m gonna do me. And I encourage you, you do you. We’ll all embrace who we are and who we aren’t, and we’ll find our place. We’ll work hard, create value, all the while taking little steps towards our crazy dreams day by day. And at the end, we’ll look back at all the crazy things we did, every story gained and scar scabbed over, and say, “I did it my way. I did me. I gave it my all. I left my mark.”&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
