<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-10-03T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Am I Doing It Right?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/10/03/am-i-doing-it-right/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/10/03/am-i-doing-it-right/</id>
    <published>2016-10-03T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-10-04T08:53:27+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Am I on the right path? Am I making the &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; decisions? I wonder about this a lot. If you’ve any ambition then it’s probably one that goes around in your head, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem: there is no &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt;. We don’t have a plan that we simply need to follow step by step. At every stage there are decisions to be made. Little ones that come together to make up our day, and big ones, that drastically alter the course of our life, and the lives of those around us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But knowing this doesn’t abate the nagging. It’s still there. Gnawing at my ankles as I stumble forwards, are you on the &lt;em&gt;right path?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Direction is important. I might not be on the perfect path, but I can at head in the right direction. There are things we can all do to get closer to where we want to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Progress is the metric I’m really interested in. It’s hard to quantify, sort of an amalgamation of a bunch of smaller indicators. Am I making progress in life? Am I using the resources I have been given to move forwards, investing them to get a greater return, or burying them away for fear of the consequences should I use them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Progress can take many shapes and sizes, but it is something core to us as humans. We should always be learning, doing, growing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t done everything I could this year. I haven’t achieved all the goals I set out to. But I have done some important things. I may not have made the progress I’d like, but I’ve made progress nonetheless, and good progress too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m at a different place to this time last year, a better place. But still, in amongst new surroundings, new circumstances, new challenges, that feeling nags away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Am I doing it right? Is there something I’m missing?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is quite similar to last weeks. So if you liked this, you might like that: &lt;a href="/2016/09/26/discomfort/"&gt;Discomfort&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>discomfort</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/09/26/discomfort/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/09/26/discomfort/</id>
    <published>2016-09-26T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-09-27T15:08:33+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Discomfort. The lack of comfort. Not always as bad as it seems?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discomfort is healthy. As humans we need to regularly step outside our comfort zones. That’s where life is truly lived. But what if this discomfort isn’t momentary, but sticks around for weeks, months, years?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was chatting to a buddy the other day about him potentially quitting his great job at a top tech startup in a beautiful city to move home with his parents and work on his own stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to laugh at how good he had it, yet still felt like maybe this wasn’t where he should really be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often discomfort is there for a reason, trying to tell us something. It’s saying “there’s something more, come explore it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a similar experience a couple of years ago. I was working an interesting job with great people on something I was passionate about. I liked the area and was surrounded by a great bunch of people on a daily basis. Yet still something felt &lt;em&gt;not quite right&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feeling built up over months, nagging at me. “This isn’t your place anymore. This season is coming to an end, it’s time for something new.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deep down I knew this moment would come, I just didn’t know when. I certainly didn’t want to pre-emptively put it into motion when it wasn’t yet time. Leaving my job and life as it was before it was time would have made me truly sad. I didn’t want to be hasty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew I had desires I’d yet to see fulfilled, and areas I wanted to explore that I had yet to do, I just wasn’t sure &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I sat on the idea for months. I dwelt on it, weighing it up, feeling it from every angle. Is it really time for me to move on, or am I just taking the easy way out? Will I regret taking this step now, is it too early? How can I leave when it’s so good here?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, after over six months of deliberation, I decided to move on. I just knew in the depths of me that it was time. Time to step out into the next season. I didn’t know what that next season really looked like, other than a few marker points, but I took the step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d felt it from every direction, this was it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d work more on my own stuff. I’d learn some core skills that I’d need for the next step. I’d slow down a bit, and not rush too quick on exactly what it all looked like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I moved back to my parents. After five years away, I came back, slowed down, and started chipping away at what I thought this next season would be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Little by little I made progress. It wasn’t always easy, I didn’t always know whether to go down path A or path B. But I tried them out for size, and learnt as I went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I applied for jobs in Australia. I applied for a job in London. I got a job in London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job was all I’d wanted. It was doing the job I wanted to do, good pay, good location, interesting product, great people. I learnt a tonne from it. I got the job as a direct result of the work I’d been doing since leaving my old job. Without that I wouldn’t have got this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eighteen months on, that feeling came around again. Should I still be here? Is this my place? Is it time to move on? Pivot or persevere?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After feeling through the discomfort once more, it started to become clear that it was time for a change. I’d changed a lot in those 18 months. The company had changed a lot. We were both in different places with different needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discomfort struck again, and forced me to re-evaluate my plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, I dwelt on it for a few months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a step and announced my intention to move on within a couple of months. I wasn’t sure exactly what was next, I just knew it was time for next. This chapter was coming to a close, it was time to step out again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often that’s how it is. We don’t know what the next step is, we just know in the core of us what it’s not. It’s not about petulance or entitlement, it’s just a knowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The desires we’ve put off for tomorrow, are now for today. We can either choose to live in the past, in the known, or step out into what today has for us, trusting we’ll be able to work it out on the journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since making that decision my options became clearer and the right path ahead emerged. I left my old gig and am now in the place I know I should be, at least for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s something to be said for persevering through tough times, or even just through the mundane. I’m not advocating that we should jump from one thing to the next as soon as our rose tinted glasses lose their colour. The ability to stick at something over a long period is a key skill any entrepreneur has to master. Rome wasn’t built in a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, we aren’t made to do the same thing over and over and over and over. There comes a time when it’s time for a change. It’s just working out &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be hard to know when that time comes. Hard to decide between sticking it out and pushing through, and moving onto something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often the path ahead is unclear. Knowing what’s ‘right’ is no scientific endeavour. But often our discomfort can lead us, whispering to us over and over, “have you looked over here? It’s time now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each week I write a post and record a podcast episode. Get both in your inbox every Tuesday, free of charge. Sign up, no spam, I promise. &lt;a href="https://wearecontrast.com/signup"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes please&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>burnout</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/09/19/burnout/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/09/19/burnout/</id>
    <published>2016-09-19T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-09-27T09:34:20+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like listening? We recorded an episode of our brand new podcast on this very topic. &lt;a href="https://hitreply.co/3"&gt;Listen to it here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not letting one side outweigh and overpower the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work and life. Should these be balanced? Or should they be one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard a &lt;a href="http://www.vanschneider.com/worklife-balance-is-bullsht/"&gt;couple&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://designlife.fm/episode36/"&gt;opinions&lt;/a&gt; recently that attempting to achieve work-life balance is solving the wrong problem. When work and life go hand in hand, there’s no need to balance them right? If one succeeds, so does the other. It’s not a zero sum game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What then, are we to make of burnout?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is burnout only something that occurs when you’re working on something that doesn’t resonate with the rest of your life? Is it only when you’re working for The Man, be it your boss, or your VC, or even yourself?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we set ourselves unrealistic expectations, and drive ourselves to work every waking hour to get them done. For some of us, VC’s are putting an unspoken pressure on us that if we don’t work so hard that we sleep at our desks then we’re not really made for the entrepreneurial game. Sometimes our boss tells us of a hard deadline and we have to break ourselves just to get it done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been watching the latter first hand the past couple months. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mikeaag"&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt;, the guy I work with, co-founder, partner in crime extraordinaire, has been maxed out at work. He’s gone above and beyond his normal levels to fulfil a specific hard deadline at his day job. He’s running on empty, but feels like he needs to keep running to meet the requirements of his 9-5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike loves what he does, and enjoys our work on the side too. He’d go as far as to say that the work we do with &lt;a href="http://wearecontrast.com/"&gt;Contrast&lt;/a&gt; is a hobby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When your hobby is starting your own startup on the side, what does resting look like? Is it healthy to come home from an intense day at work and spend more time in the evening coding?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are questions that I’ve been thinking about lately, in a bid to avoid making things worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does it look like to be burnt out? I’ve not been there, but Mike’s pretty close. In this week’s episode of Hit Reply, I spoke with Mike about what it’s like from the inside, and our thoughts on whether it can be avoided, and if so, how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out: &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/hitreply/episode-3-burnout"&gt;https://soundcloud.com/hitreply/episode-3-burnout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each week I write a post and record a podcast episode. Get both in your inbox every Tuesday, free of charge. Sign up, no spam, I promise. &lt;a href="https://wearecontrast.com/signup"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes please&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>where are you going?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/09/12/where-are-you-going/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/09/12/where-are-you-going/</id>
    <published>2016-09-12T22:06:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-09-20T12:59:56+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like listening? We recorded an episode of our brand new podcast on this very topic. &lt;a href="https://hitreply.co/2"&gt;Listen to it here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of us desire control over how we spend our time. What output would produce this outcome? You could quit your job and live off benefits. You could work hard, become a contractor, and pick and choose when you work. Or you could start your own business, with a relatively self-sustaining income stream independent of how much time you put in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing where you’re going and how you plan on getting there is important. But how can you gauge your progress and make sure you’re on track?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years back some business consultants took my colleagues and I through a simple task that helped me to reshape how I see my time and money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They told us to think about any task we do from the lens of input, output and outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="input-what-are-you-spending-your-time-on"&gt;Input: What are you spending your time on?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost 2 years ago &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mikeaag"&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt; and I set ourselves a new challenge: to launch &lt;a href="https://blog.wearecontrast.com/introducing-sixbysix-217d608362"&gt;six projects in six months&lt;/a&gt;. This challenge had a primary input of time, an output of projects, and an outcome of getting better at shipping stuff, which is a key skill we needed to master if we were ever going to start our own startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the decisions we made when we started was to track our time on every task. We did this primarily out of curiosity, we were intrigued to see how long each project would take, and which parts would take the longest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was also a bit of a gimmick. We decided to share as much as possible during this time, blogging regularly and being transparent with our stats from every launch. That included time spent per project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were two noticeable effects of tracking our time almost religiously for that six month period. Firstly, we had the obvious benefit of having reports showing where our time was spent. This was an expected output. We also realised that the simple act of tracking our time helped keep us on track and productive during those times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="time-to-focus"&gt;Time To Focus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the clock was ticking, we were conscious that being distracted by Twitter or email would blur the statistics, making them less useful in the long run. This forced us to stay on track when the clock was on. Just as much, this gamified our time a little, leading us to want to spend more and more time on the things that were important to us, shipping side projects. We used &lt;a href="https://toggl.com/"&gt;Toggl&lt;/a&gt; to track our time, but there are other tools that can help give insight to where we spend our time, &lt;a href="https://www.rescuetime.com/"&gt;RescueTime&lt;/a&gt; being another popular one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pomodoro_Technique"&gt;Pomodoro technique&lt;/a&gt; on and off for the last few months, and it has a similar effect. It designates time to focus, 25 minutes on, 5 minutes off. In the 25 minutes of focus time, all distractions and thoughts that come to mind that are irrelevant to the task at hand are either quickly noted or ignored until later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a sense, the Pomodoro technique is a systemised way of procrastinating your procrastination. It leads you to think "ok I can do that in my 5 minutes off, its only 16 minutes away afterall".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to time tracking, seeing the count of Pomodoro’s achieved each day gamifies this, I aim to achieve 10 Pomodoro’s on the days I employ this method. That’s only 4 hours 10 minutes of actual work time, but is about the peak of output I can manage in any given day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often, the issue isn’t that we need to spend more time on important tasks, we just need to spend more &lt;em&gt;focused time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="go-deep"&gt;Go Deep&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m listening to a book on this right now, &lt;a href="http://www.audible.com/pd/Self-Development/Deep-Work-Audiobook/B0189PX1RQ/ref=a_search_c4_1_1_srTtl?qid=1473503170&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;Deep Work&lt;/a&gt;, which talks about the importance of focus, and techniques for achieving this deep state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It comes to a conclusion I’ve heard quite a lot recently: we all have a finite limit to how much concentration we can spend, and it's a lot less than we think it is. We don’t need to work longer hours, we need to work productively until we reach our limit, then take time off and refresh ourselves. Finishing work at 5 is late enough, too late by some standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deep Work mentions Charles Darwin’s routine. He used to wake up at 7, take a short walk, work from 8 until 12:15pm, which he considered the end of his working day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This flies directly in the face of the startup hustle culture we hear about so often: working through the night, sleeping less, or staying in the office until late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve Blank shared a story about this recently, about a CEO who was proud at how long his employees stayed in the office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This glorification of the ‘hustle’ is had its time. It’s outdated. &lt;em&gt;It’s not productive.&lt;/em&gt; You might force more through the funnel, but it will be of a lesser, diluted quality. You’d produce a better output (and therefore outcome) by spending around 4 hours of productive, focused time in Deep Work each day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, you need to do the work, and it can be scrappy at the start, but working long hours only says one thing: you don’t know how to prioritise and focus on the tasks that matter. You’re &lt;em&gt;inefficient.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you disagree with this statement and feel like you &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; need to work those long hours, I’d challenge you to track how much of your time is spent in true, deep, productive work, and how much is actually fluff that can be cut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="whats-your-output"&gt;What’s Your Output?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Measuring how much we output is a step in the right direction. Instead of simply tracking hours invested and wanting to invest more and more time, we can track what we’re achieving with that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since finishing SixBySix, we slowly stopped time tracking. We primarily tracked for the stats to share for each of the projects we made. It also came with a cost, of continually clocking on each time we did some work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days we track two key metrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is the most important: did we achieve our one key goal this week?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike and I have both recently joined a mastermind. A mastermind is simply a group of likeminded business people who get together each week and update each other on how the past week has gone for their business. Did we achieved our goal(s), what our goal(s) are for this week, and chat through any issues we may be having.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joining a mastermind a few months back was one of the best decisions I made this year. The accountability it brings to have to boil down all the ideas spinning around in my head to one key task to focus on each week is super important. Each week knowing I have to report back on whether I achieved this goal, and if not, why not, helps me stay on track. &lt;em&gt;It forces me to prioritise output over input, value over movement.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second metric we track is less important than our &lt;em&gt;one key goal&lt;/em&gt;, but gives a nice overview of our week’s achievements. It’s simply a list of all the tasks we did that week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our setup is simple: we have a Backburner where we capture the thoughts that occur to us in the shower, This Week for tasks we aim to complete this week, In Progress, and a weekly Done column.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each week we archive the tasks we achieved that week and create a fresh Done column, giving us an ever evolving history to look back on, should we ever want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two metrics combined help us to remain focused on our output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This setup works for us but you can track output however you like. If your goal is to learn, you could track number of books read, or number of discussions you’ve had with people of opposing views. If your goal is to help others, then you could set yourself a goal of helping someone every day, and have that as your key output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your key metric(s) can be whatever you’d like, just make sure it’s not the number of cat videos watched per week. Cats are great ‘n’ all, but probably not the key metric to help gauge whether you’re on track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="where-is-your-life-going"&gt;Where Is Your Life Going?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where do you want to be in 6 months time? In 5 years time? What are you working towards?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it to be physically fit? To raise a loving family? To get a promotion at work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For us, we want to start our own startup. Everything we do is centered on that. This desired outcome drives the outputs we look to achieve (shipping side projects, building a following etc.), which in turn drives the inputs we put into the machine (reading and writing, coding, designing, developing products, meeting other founders).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in the intro, there are many ways to achieve every goal we have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each of these examples, the inputs will be different. Starting a self-sustaining business is vastly different to contracting, and it goes without saying quitting your day job looks very different still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s where we often get this mixed up. We place too much focus on the input, little on the output, and nowhere near enough on the outcome. Rarely do we stop and weigh up whether what we’re doing is helping achieve the outcomes we desire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simon Sinek puts this well, in his &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sioZd3AxmnE"&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt; (and &lt;a href="https://www.startwithwhy.com/"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt;), Start With Why. In this talk, Simon shares how most of businesses are &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; focussed, selling customers on the specifics of &lt;em&gt;what they do&lt;/em&gt;. The best companies, however, talk about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;they’re doing it&lt;/em&gt;. Customers of Apple buy into the philosophy that Apple cares about everything they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly for us, we need to frame every &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; around our key &lt;em&gt;why’s&lt;/em&gt;. Every action we take should be initiated by the core &lt;em&gt;why’s&lt;/em&gt; of our life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we come to this place, the next step is really nailing, what are my why’s? What do I want from life? It’s here that a very simple exercise, The 5 Why’s, can help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 5 Why’s, simply asks "why?" five times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For us, we can ask, why do we want this outcome? Is the outcome really what we want, is there a higher motivation above this all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our example of desiring more control over how we spend our time, why is this? Is it because we hate our day job? Is it because we have desires to use our time in ways we can’t right now? To travel? If so, there may well be ways to achieve these higher outcomes without having full control over our time. We could take a sabbatical, saving frugally for years at a time, then spending six months travelling the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important point here isn’t the specifics of the example, but that knowing what we &lt;em&gt;really want&lt;/em&gt; is vital if we’re ever going to get it. If we’re truly honest with our desires and goals, we can start tweaking the machine to produce the life we desire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read a quote a couple years back from &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/nbashaw"&gt;Nathan Bashaw&lt;/a&gt; that’s continually stuck with me in the back of my mind since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;"When you look back 6 months from today and don’t feel embarrassed by your naiveté, there’s a problem."
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nbashaw"&gt;Nathan Bashaw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rrhoover/status/550308425972740096"&gt;https://twitter.com/rrhoover/status/550308425972740096&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter where you’re at right now. You can’t affect where you stand, or the circumstances around you. What matters is &lt;em&gt;whether you’re making progress towards where you want to be.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So take stock of your inputs, where you’re spending your time, but don’t glamourise how long you spend at the office, or even what you’re creating. Focus on the impact your work is having, on others, on yourself, and whether it’s moving you close to where you really want to be. That’s what really matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each week I write a post and record a podcast episode. Get both in your inbox every Tuesday, free of charge. Sign up, no spam, I promise. &lt;a href="https://wearecontrast.com/signup"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes please&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>launch</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/09/05/launch/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/09/05/launch/</id>
    <published>2016-09-05T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-09-06T12:49:56+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[You can also find this blog post &lt;a href="https://blog.wearecontrast.com/launch-c3968191a5b7"&gt;on Medium&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this week’s blog post I attempt to answer the questions: &lt;em&gt;What does it look like to launch from the inside?&lt;/em&gt; And &lt;em&gt;How on earth did we get to second on the Hacker News homepage?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like the sound of that, &lt;a href="https://hitreply.co/1"&gt;this weeks episode of our new podcast, Hit Reply, is all about launching&lt;/a&gt; (sound of that, get it, get it?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week we launched a new project that we’ve been discussing for a couple months, our first ever podcast, &lt;a href="http://hitreply.co/"&gt;Hit Reply&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hit Reply is a podcast that gives you an inside view on what it’s like to start a startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past two years, we’ve spent our evenings, weekends and holidays building and launching stuff. Before that, we weren’t very good at launching. In fact, we were awful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since doubling down on shipping side projects, &lt;a href="https://www.producthunt.com/@fredrivett/collections/things-i-ve-made"&gt;we’ve launched 9 in the last 2 years&lt;/a&gt;. Hit Reply, is our 10th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hit Reply is a bit different to the rest. Most projects have one main "we’re here!" launch, when the curtain comes down and the masses (hopefully) swell in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hit Reply though, is a podcast. We’ll be releasing a new episode &lt;em&gt;every week&lt;/em&gt;. Every Tuesday, we get another shot at another little release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Podcasts have been growing in popularity. New podcast episodes can now vie for a place on &lt;a href="http://www.producthunt.com/"&gt;Product Hunt’s homepage&lt;/a&gt;. As well as that, lots of the tech folks over at &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/"&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; listen to podcasts. A fact that we hadn’t quite fully realised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday the countdown to our first episode had just ticked over to &lt;em&gt;0 days, 0 hours, 0 minutes&lt;/em&gt;. It wasn’t live yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the week off work, and I’d had quite a relaxed morning, going through my new morning routine. 10 minutes meditation. 5 minutes free flow writing. 10 ideas. Exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d underestimated how long it would take to make the final edits to our first episode, and the tweaks that we’d need to make to the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About two and a half hours after our scheduled launch time, we were ready. &lt;a href="http://hitreply.co/"&gt;Episode 0: Yet Another Startup Podcast?&lt;/a&gt; was live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sent out our email to our weekly list, and that was that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, a little later than planned, we submitted our first little episode to Product Hunt. We were keen to see how much traffic Product Hunt sent to podcast episodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within half an hour or so, it was doing relatively well, even competing with YCombinator’s interview with Jessica Livingston (spoiler: they won).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a sort of side note, we submitted the episode to Hacker News. For us, Hacker News is much more of a mystery. Due to the free-for-all nature and size of the system, we’re never quite sure what will happen when we submit something to Hacker News. You can easily get lost in the masses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We submitted it, and left it at that. A few minutes later we started to see some upvotes trickle in. Who was that? People were upvoting &lt;em&gt;our podcast?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About fifteen minutes in, I stumbled onto the homepage by accident. Wait, what’s going on? We’re #4 on the homepage? This can’t be right!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Erm erm erm erm erm erm erm
We’re 4th on HN homepage? Am i reading this wrong?
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FredRivett/status/770987008793702400"&gt;Tweet on the Twitters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It was right.&lt;/em&gt; We were 4th on the Hacker News homepage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then 3rd 😦&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We’re now 3rd. THIRD. ON THE HACKERNEWS HOMEPAGE.
I don’t know whats happening anymore.
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FredRivett/status/770987971772375040"&gt;Another tweet hits the twitters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then 2nd 😱&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How is this getting evening happening
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FredRivett/status/770988331584851968"&gt;Tweets keep rollin'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our little podcast was second on Hacker News.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few minutes, it began to slide back down a few slots, and sat most of the day between 5th and 7th. A pretty handy place to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what did we learn from this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="launch-early"&gt;Launch early&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 80/20 rule states that, for many events, roughly 80% of the effects come from 20% of the causes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This rule applies to launching too. We can all get to a point where we have a website with our first episode recorded. &lt;strong&gt;It’s often the feeling that you need to have all your ducks in a row that leads you to delay launching, oftentimes, forever.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason? &lt;em&gt;You’ll never have all your ducks in a row.&lt;/em&gt; There will always be things that could be done better. Never has there been a to-do list that’s actually empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to launching is to tick off the big wins. Get a website up. Record an episode with whatever equipment you have. Then share it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s really that simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We specifically took shortcuts to get Hit Reply to launch now. Our website is a bunch of simple PHP files that I knocked together. It’s a systemised mess. Over the long term it will slow us down a little, but we can tweak on the journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CSS is just CSS, not Sass, which I’d normally use. This was due to a roadblock that we’d hit in a previous project, that took a while to get around. Doing it this way wasn’t as nice or as fast to develop, but got the job done so we could move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We launched without being on iTunes. We weren’t even in apps like &lt;a href="http://www.shiftyjelly.com/pocketcasts/"&gt;Pocket Casts&lt;/a&gt;. People were wanting to subscribe on their favourite podcast app, and we weren’t there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Did we launch too early?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No. I don’t think so. We had to get the ball rolling with the podcast, we knew it was time to launch. We planned to submit our podcast to iTunes after a few episodes, and honestly hadn’t heard of Pocket Casts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We forgot to add an RSS feed for people to use to subscribe on their platforms, but soon corrected this with some quick changes on launch day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Equally, with the unexpected masses flooding in, we added a quick &lt;a href="https://realtimeusers.bycontrast.co/"&gt;real time user counter&lt;/a&gt;, a project we’d worked on a couple months before, to the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FredRivett/status/770991865135005697"&gt;https://twitter.com/FredRivett/status/770991865135005697&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="where-are-we-at-now"&gt;Where are we at now?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, in the aftermath of the launch, what was the result?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The podcast episode has had over &lt;a href="http://hitreply.co/ep/0/yet-another-startup-podcast/"&gt;950 plays&lt;/a&gt;, far more than we could have hoped for our initial launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/hitreplypod"&gt;twitter account&lt;/a&gt; has its first 21 followers (thanks). A small start, but nice nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve had some great feedback and we now know that some people are interested in listening. This is a big plus and one of the key questions to ask yourself when you launch, does anyone care?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But one of the biggest gains, &lt;a href="http://hitreply.co/"&gt;our email list&lt;/a&gt; has had 57 new sign ups, boosting it up from 202 subscribers to 259. That’s a nice healthy jump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="where-do-we-go-from-here"&gt;Where do we go from here?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now’s where the real challenge kicks in. Shipping something is a milestone, an achievement of sorts. Our previous projects were the result of a challenge we set ourselves to get better at shipping stuff, but this is an ongoing project. Each week, a new episode. Consistency here is key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to see how this grows. Our first ‘proper’ episode, &lt;a href="https://hitreply.co/1"&gt;Episode 1, is all about launching&lt;/a&gt;. Give it a listen if you’ve got a mo, and if you do, please &lt;strong&gt;Hit Reply&lt;/strong&gt; and let us know what you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to keep up to date with the podcast? Get a &lt;a href="http://hitreply.co/"&gt;small, simple email every Tuesday announcing the new episode&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="http://feeds.soundcloud.com/users/soundcloud:users:245437295/sounds.rss"&gt;subscribe to our RSS&lt;/a&gt; in your favourite podcast player.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Healthy Pressure</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/08/29/healthy-pressure/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/08/29/healthy-pressure/</id>
    <published>2016-08-29T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-08-30T14:47:12+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Pressure is healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Healthy pressure is, at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without pressure we wouldn’t have diamonds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pressure can keep us on track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can push us to go further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/the-mission/a-breakthrough-is-nothing-without-the-followthrough-87021be7f9b5#.xb7cplqvi"&gt;To follow through&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a part of a mastermind, and every week there’s a pressure to answer the question, "what did you do last week". That pressure is healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have internal pressure. "You talk about startups a lot, you better back up that chat with some action". This pressure is healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every day I get home from my day job late at night and feel tired, with a long to-do list ahead of me. I remember what I’m trying to do and what my future looks like. This pressure is healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I share my goals in public. This pressure is healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all pressure is healthy. Sometimes it can weigh us down rather than spur us on. In those cases, you’ve gotta throw that pressure off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What pressure are you under right now? Is it weighing you down, or pushing you on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throw off the heavy weights, but use some of that healthy pressure to push you forwards. Your future will be better as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
