<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Perfect</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/11/21/perfect/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/11/21/perfect/</id>
    <published>2016-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-22T08:40:22+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;But.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s flawed.
But there’s competitors.
But it’ll be hard.
But I don’t know how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s so easy to let but stop us. It stops us from taking steps forwards, for fear that it might not work out. Fear that we’ll waste our time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead, we wait for perfect. We wait for that moment when &lt;em&gt;the idea&lt;/em&gt; comes. We wait for &lt;em&gt;the one&lt;/em&gt;, that’s a sweet combination of unique genius, no competition, that requires nothing new from us, no new learning, everything is  known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wait. But the idea never comes. Nothing quite holds up. Everything has a reason to stop us pursuing it. But. But. But.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perfection freezes us in our tracks. It stops us from ever moving forwards. At some point we’ve got to leave perfection behind, and move ahead into the unknown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dance with the idea. Play with it. Try things out. Embrace the frailties, embrace the unknown. Embrace the likelihood of failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop waiting for the perfect moment.
Stop waiting for the perfect problem.
Stop waiting for the perfect team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>It's time for change</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/11/14/it-s-time-for-change/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/11/14/it-s-time-for-change/</id>
    <published>2016-11-14T09:16:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-15T09:41:06+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been said that to achieve great work you must kill your darlings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s what we’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past few months we’ve spent a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of time on our new podcast, &lt;a href="http://hitreply.co/"&gt;Hit Reply&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d spend a few hours prepping each episode, often more, and then a couple of hours each recording it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Podcasting is new for us. It’s different to our previous projects.  It’s taken time to get going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge has been how can we create as much value for our listeners in as little time for them? Could we provide the same amount of value in a compact 20 minute episode as a longer 45 minute episode?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were conscious of wanting to create something that had the highest return on investment for our listeners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the emphasis on not wasting people’s time, on trimming the fluff, has led to bloated time investment on our side. It’s led to a podcast that’s become almost a spoken blog post. &lt;em&gt;It’s not what we set out to do in the beginning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve spent the past month or so thinking through where we want to go, whether our goals are still the same as they were before, and whether our current activities are the best way to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, we’ve come to realise that the podcast’s not been the right &lt;a href="https://justinjackson.ca/want/"&gt;product/founder fit&lt;/a&gt; for us right now. It’s not been utilising our strengths, our unfair advantages, it’s not the most effective way to go from where we are now to where we want to be. It’s not been the best use of our time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, we’re going to focus on a new plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new plan is fairly simple. We’re going to talk to people about what they do and any struggles they have until we discover a problem worth solving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll prototype and develop. Test out ideas and learn. And we’ll go from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This all sounds rather fluffy. To combat that, we've set quarterly goals we'll aim to meet, and will be accountable to our &lt;a href="https://ryanbattles.com/post/what-is-a-mastermind-group"&gt;mastermind groups&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s painful to stop something we’ve invested a fair amount of time in already, something that’s already providing a certain amount of value. But if we’re to ever get to where we want to be, we’ve got to focus on the work that will help get us there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve got to &lt;a href="http://fredrivett.com/2016/10/31/create-your-own-path/"&gt;create our own path&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve got to kill our darlings.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Busy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/11/07/busy/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/11/07/busy/</id>
    <published>2016-11-07T13:28:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-07T13:29:58+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The days go by quicker now. It’s Monday again. Where did that week go?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The years go by quicker now. It’s New Years Eve again. Where did that year go?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re all so &lt;em&gt;busy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sometimes wonder about how we should best live our lives. We’re often so intent on cramming &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; into every crevice of our every day lives that we never take the time to simply be. To be present &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; that day. To take time &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; a moment. To pick our head up and look around, and just be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re too busy getting &lt;em&gt;there&lt;/em&gt;. Going to that &lt;em&gt;other place&lt;/em&gt;. Making sure we’re ready for it. Making sure that we’ll be prepared when it comes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it comes, and we’re busy. Too busy to notice. To realise that anything much is going on. Too numbed by constant movement to appreciate that the very moments we’re preparing for are passing us by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s so easy to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I’m being wise? If I stop being busy now, my future will be worse. There is definitely an element of truth to this. We cannot simply stop preparing for the future and live in today. Tomorrow will come too, we hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must strike the balance. Balance between creating the best future for tomorrow, whilst not repeatedly giving over all of today for it. We have to claim back some of today. We have to cash in some of our time. We have to budget for living, for being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we never stop to live, to breathe, to be, the next time we look up we’ll realise life has passed us by again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s be present in the moment. Be conscious of our blessings, and conscious of our challenges. Try to be thankful for what we’ve got, if we can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being present sounds like airy fairy rubbish, but it’s important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s set aside time when we’re not &lt;em&gt;busy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s be present.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Create Your Own Path</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/10/31/create-your-own-path/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/10/31/create-your-own-path/</id>
    <published>2016-10-31T08:27:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-07T13:31:12+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent the past six months thinking about this. It’s been on the back of my mind constantly, and at the front often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s something I care deeply about. Making the most of it. Making the best use of it. Not wasting it. My time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically, because I’ve cared so much about not wasting my time, I’ve done exactly that. I’ve been caught up in trying to &lt;em&gt;do it right&lt;/em&gt;. To do it all now. In analysis paralysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Is this the right path?”
“Am I doing it right”?
“Is this the most efficient way to get from here to there, to reach my goals?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These thoughts have been ever present. Every move questioned. Every step doubted. Every option over-analysed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s brought what was a nicely chugging vehicle to a near stand still. Progress has slowed to a halt. And it’s not even as if I’m getting any rest, it’s been exhausting. Wasteful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All because I missed something so simple. One simple truth that I knew but didn’t know. Something that only now has finally clicked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There isn’t &lt;em&gt;one path&lt;/em&gt; to take, there aren’t any. You’ve got to create your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent way too long working out if &lt;em&gt;this path&lt;/em&gt; was right, or &lt;em&gt;that path&lt;/em&gt;. I’ve tried to “do it right”, putting off my gut instincts and ignoring what I’m good at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No, there isn’t a “right way”, only best practices that work in some cases and not in others.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These best practices are important. They’re the general guidelines that have worked in the past, and will probably help in the future too. They help to shape our plans, but they shouldn’t drive them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, our plans should be driven by purpose, passion and intrigue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questioning is right, it’s healthy. But the questioning should never be about “what’s right” in a fixed sense, but what seems to make sense to do based on the data available to you now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to create your path is to collect data and try stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collecting that data involves listening to others stories, hearing about their successes, and their failures too. Picking out patterns and understanding the underlying principles behind it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating your own path isn’t shunning everyone else, being a closed off know it all. It’s the total opposite. It forces you to be &lt;em&gt;more open&lt;/em&gt; because you’ll never know when other people’s paths will help guide yours, and how your story will help shape theirs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why it’s so important to surround yourself. &lt;a href="https://learningtolaunch.co/read#6-surround-yourself"&gt;Surround yourself&lt;/a&gt; with great people. Surround yourself with learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Store it all up. Soak it all in. After a while it starts to paint a picture, and this picture can help guide you as you paint your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surround yourself with clever, creative, inspirational people. Surround yourself with &lt;a href="http://fredrivett.com/2016/10/24/move/"&gt;the movers&lt;/a&gt;. Help them create their path, and let them help you create yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allow yourself to dream. Think about how you want the world to be. Think about how you can make it more like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set big audacious long term goals that will stretch you, and specific, attainable, short term smart goals that will help take you there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell those you surround yourself with the dreams and tell them the goals. Let them be the ones to bring you back on path when you wander off, let them help you shake off the baggage and propel you forwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then move. Create. Try. Experiment. Do. Follow your inquisition, do what you’re good at. Do what you enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while you’ll be known for that. You’ll be the person that does X. The loud one. The quiet one. The &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll build an audience. A genuine bunch of people who like who you are and most of what you say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People gravitate towards those who are &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt;. Those who have integrity. We love transparency, we love vulnerability. Embrace all of this as you create your path. Bring others along for the journey, and in so doing help them to create theirs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this &lt;em&gt;because I’ve seen it&lt;/em&gt;. Just look at &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/pjrvs"&gt;Paul Jarvis&lt;/a&gt;. He’s, well, Paul. He does things his way and he’s not afraid to show it. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/levelsio"&gt;Pieter Levels&lt;/a&gt;. He’s controversial, outspoken, and he makes things happen. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dhh"&gt;DHH&lt;/a&gt; is similar. You can’t put him in a box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this &lt;em&gt;because I’ve felt it&lt;/em&gt;. I’ve experienced trying to find the “right path”, desperately searching for the industry approved short cuts, and I’ve found out that it doesn’t exist. It’s a myth. I’ve tried doing it this way, that way, the other way, and now I’m trying it my way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m gonna do me. And I encourage you, you do you. We’ll all embrace who we are and who we aren’t, and we’ll find our place. We’ll work hard, create value, all the while taking little steps towards our crazy dreams day by day. And at the end, we’ll look back at all the crazy things we did, every story gained and scar scabbed over, and say, “I did it my way. I did me. I gave it my all. I left my mark.”&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Move</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/10/24/move/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/10/24/move/</id>
    <published>2016-10-24T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-10-29T18:46:26+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All mankind is divided into three classes: those that are immovable, those that are movable, and those that move.
&lt;cite&gt;Benjamin Franklin&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t always know what to do. Where to focus, when to say yes, when to say no. One thing I do know is that I must do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. I must try. Experiment. Dabble. Try things out for size. Learn. Repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I am not is stationary. That’s the most dangerous state to be in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sitting. Idle. Watching the world go by. Criticising the movers or silently abdicating any participation. Either way, standing still is deadly. I don’t care whether it’s due to apathy or fear. If you stand still long enough you &lt;em&gt;will die&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We aren’t made to stand still. We’re made to explore. To learn, to grow, to conquer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are not static, you are alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The world&lt;/em&gt; may have pinned you down and put you in a box, but what &lt;em&gt;the world&lt;/em&gt; forgets is the miracle that you’re even here, housed in a skeleton, riding laps around a blazing ball of fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be one of the immovables. Life’s too short. Join us, the movers, as we wander the terrain, exploring, learning, growing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take action today. Start small. Do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. You were born to live.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Consistency</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/10/17/consistency/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/10/17/consistency/</id>
    <published>2016-10-17T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-10-25T21:12:03+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Consistency is one of the hardest things to achieve. Especially at the beginning. Creating a new habit, starting a new routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst it is tough, consistency is also key. Without consistency you won’t ever get anywhere. With consistency, you can make true progress towards your goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting is easy. The initial rush of a new idea, new possibilities. You’re fresh. Not worn down. It’s a blank slate. Exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The early days can be quite fun. Everything is new. Potential abounds. Launching can bring a little spike in traffic. Attention. Momentum. Vanity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the early days are over though, normality sets in. Routine appears, and it’s greyscale. It’s not what it was. The initial spotlight fades, numbers drop, the quick wins evaporate, and all that’s left is, hard work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the danger zone. The honeymoon period is over. You’re in a desert, losing water, eagles hovering overhead. Will you push through and find a way, or will you let the surroundings overwhelm you, stagnating, slowing, dying?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consistency was born for such a time as this. Keep plodding on. One foot after the other. The road moving under you. You’re reeling it in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consistency is boring. Unattractive. Mundane. It’s quiet, whispering to you, let’s keep going. We’ve got a place to be. Onwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This mundane, quiet voice whispers to you just as the noise increases. This is new. This isn’t what you expected. This is hard. This isn’t for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re out of your depth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s the point. That’s where consistency takes you. To places you’ve not been before. To challenges you’ve not faced before. To adventures you’ve never dreamt of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consistency leads you. You strain to hear it’s voice over the noise. You catch glimpses. You cherish these. You feed off these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you continue, you find the noise doesn’t disappear, but you get used to it. You gain small victories over it. You begin to bottle these victories, and use them as fuel to push you forwards. The noise loses it’s edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You tune your ear to the beat of the drum. Today. Tomorrow. Again. Again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Routine becomes habit. Habit becomes consistent. Consistent becomes us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You fly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You fly, over the noise, using it, and your victories over it, to keep you going. To stay aloft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your life is moving forwards. You’re making progress. You’re taking steps, each day. Each week you’ve moved on, each month, another stake in the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Months pass. Years. You look back. Who was that person? They look familiar, yet, strange. Similar, yet different. They look like you, but they’re not you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve changed.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
