<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-08-04T00:29:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Fumbling Forwards</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/08/03/fumbling-forwards/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/08/03/fumbling-forwards/</id>
    <published>2016-08-04T00:29:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-08-07T19:10:20+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The other week &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@mijustin"&gt;Justin Jackson&lt;/a&gt; shared a quote, one that I desperately needed to hear. It was from a &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@pjrvs"&gt;Paul Jarvis&lt;/a&gt; post, with the basic premise that &lt;a href="https://medium.pjrvs.com/success-is-for-the-lucky-579e30576eb2#---0-112.sqaw038a0"&gt;success is no scientific endeavour&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is the only common thread with successful entrepreneurs: they keep trying different ideas until one sticks.
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mijustin/status/756736947926827010"&gt;@mijustin on twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No-one likes to feel like they don’t have a clue what they’re doing. But that’s pretty much what starting a startup is like 24/7. Every day you wake up, and work on a bunch of tasks you were never trained to do. You attempt to solve a bunch of questions that you’ve never answered before. None of us really know what we’re doing, but it never looks like that. You look up at those who’ve experienced success, and wonder, do they have something I don’t?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparing ourselves to others isn’t the answer. Sure, it’s great to learn lessons from those we admire, but expecting to be able to compare the inside view of me now, at this point in the journey, to those towards the top, towards the peak of theirs, is never going to be much use other than to stress us out and demotivate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to success isn’t having everything together with a five year plan of how you’re going to take over the world, but rather, it’s not letting the unknown, the new, put you off from moving forwards, instead using that as fuel, pushing you forwards into your next adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s not ok to feel like you’re blagging your way through your startup. It’s essential. Anything else is delusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no rules, you see. There are only best practices, that apply sometimes, not others, and evolve over time. It’s great to learn the basic rules of the game, but these will only serve to give you blurry guideposts to prompt further thought. There are no easily digestible ‘unpack and add water’ tips that will immediately push your startup forwards. There are just a bunch of ideas that have worked in the past and will probably give you a rough nudge in the right direction when you’re unsure which path you should be on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re all fumbling forwards in the darkness, desperately trying to find the path forwards. And most of the time we don’t even know where forwards is, with nothing more than a very general sense of direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your ducks will never be in order. You don’t one day graduate from startup school and receive a nice simple business where all the questions are answered and the path forwards is easy, simple and clear. The view from the top isn’t what it looks like from down here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t have less problems as you go forwards, you just have a different set. You graduate from one set of problems to the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re like us, searching for the right problem to solve and product to build, then listening, brainstorming, testing and iterating are huge. Later, should we get there, customer service, scaling, hiring and leading likely await. Each step has its own challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I feel pretty lame about where we’re at. We’re committed to &lt;a href="https://prodigo.co/"&gt;starting our own startup&lt;/a&gt;, and it being successful, but we don’t even know if what we’re working on now will be what we’re working on in three months time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we’re learning. Learning about the audience we want to serve, about problems we enjoy solving, about ourselves. That’s all that can be said. We’re in a better place now than we were six months ago, that’s what matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Progress is incremental, remember that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re struggling with your startup, understand you’re not alone. Be sure to get accountable with where you’re at. I highly recommend joining a mastermind group that meets weekly to discuss current successes, failures and issues. If you’re not in one already, having this accountability, support, and outside perspective will be huge for you and your business. Reach out to a few like minded people on a similar path to you and see if they’re up for it too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But most of all, don’t be ashamed of where you’re at, or what you’re doing. Be like us, just skeletons with flesh doing laps around the sun, desperately trying to work out what on earth we’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you struggling to keep on top of your startups monthly recurring expenses? We were, that’s why we’re building &lt;a href="https://prodigo.co/"&gt;prodigo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prodigo is a simple app that gives you actionable insights into the tools and services you’re paying for.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re early stage and would love to shape this with you. If you’re interested you can sign up at &lt;a href="https://prodigo.co/"&gt;prodigo.co&lt;/a&gt; ✍️  or &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FredRivett"&gt;say hi and we can chat&lt;/a&gt; 👋&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Make Stuff</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/06/08/make-stuff/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/06/08/make-stuff/</id>
    <published>2016-06-08T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-08-07T18:57:32+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A week ago &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/marckohlbrugge"&gt;Marc Köhlbrugge&lt;/a&gt; released a neat little side project. The premise was simple, pay to get featured on the site. We’ve seen this before, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.milliondollarhomepage.com/"&gt;The million dollar homepage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The twist here? The more you pay, the higher you’ll be featured on the leaderboard. This gamified the system, with individuals and companies paying more and more for the highest position. Marc managed to use his existing networks to bring the initial burst of traffic through, and pretty soon the ball was well and truly rolling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want some traffic to your site now would be a good time to participate: &lt;a href="https://highscore.money/"&gt;http://highscore.money&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you want some traffic to your site now would be a good time to participate: &lt;a href="https://highscore.money/"&gt;http://highscore.money&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/marckohlbrugge?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@marckohlbrugge on twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And by the end of the day Marc had done &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@marckohlbrugge/how-i-made-2-251-in-1-day-with-highscore-money-dd56b35b2681#.i58k99t77"&gt;pretty well&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sort of project clearly comes under the silly little side projects umbrella. It was an opportunistic attempt to make a quick buck, whilst providing value to those who paid for a slot and having fun along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As makers, quick side projects like this help flex our creative muscles. I don’t think Marc intended this to be a fully fledged business, he’s already focussed in on his main gig, BetaList, but that didn’t stop him spending a few days creating this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst following Marc’s launch day progress, one tweet from Marc struck me, and got me thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What's a good, privacy-friendly real-time website counter?
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/marckohlbrugge/status/737388891246891008?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@marckohlbrugge on twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the second time I’d seen a request for some form of user facing site stats. A few weeks before, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mijustin"&gt;Justin Jackson&lt;/a&gt; had written &lt;a href="https://justinjackson.ca/webmaster/"&gt;I’m a fucking webmaster&lt;/a&gt;, and wrote &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=11685868"&gt;this comment on his Hacker News post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;BTW: does anyone know of a lightweight, retro “hit counter” that can grab my GA stats and display them at the bottom?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pattern was forming here, enough for me to mention to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mikeaag"&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt; that this might be something for us to explore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike and I have been working on side projects for years, but only recently have we got into the habit of actually launching them. Having set ourselves the challenge to launch &lt;a href="https://blog.wearecontrast.com/introducing-sixbysix-217d608362#.gpqkok2i1"&gt;six projects in six months&lt;/a&gt; at the end of 2014, we’ve launched &lt;a href="https://www.producthunt.com/@mikeaag/collections/i-made-that"&gt;8 side projects since&lt;/a&gt;, including writing our first book about the whole process, &lt;a href="https://learningtolaunch.co/"&gt;Learning to Launch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More recently though, we’ve been focussing on thinking through problems we want to solve, areas of tech we’re interested in, potential markets we’d enjoy helping. We’ve been thinking a lot about the startup we want to build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to get stuck in analysis paralysis. It’s important that we keep moving forwards. That’s why, this past weekend, we spent most of it hacking together a small side project, inspired by Marc’s tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="introducing-real-time-users"&gt;Introducing Real Time Users&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you’ve gotta have some fun and build stuff. That’s what Marc did, and that’s what we decided to do, too. Real Time Users is a little side project that makes us smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real Time Users is vulnerable, it exposes the truth of how popular your site is. Go to it anytime, and you’ll likely be greeted by the fact you’re the only person on the internet there. That’s both beautiful to know, that you are alone on this piece of internet real estate, and, as a creator, leaves me feeling slightly exposed. You know how popular my site is. For us at least, that’s a new level of transparency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Partially inspired by Marc’s leaderboard, we’ve included &lt;a href="https://realtimeusers.bycontrast.co/leaderboard"&gt;one of our own&lt;/a&gt;. If you take the 60 seconds and add Real Time Users to your site, you’ll likely take up one of the top 10 slots, until at least 8 others add it to their sites too. You’ll be able to see whether anyone ever adds this to their site, simply by tracking whether those top 10 slots ever fill up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m proud of it, proud because, having discussed it a few times during the week, we only really got to work on it this past weekend, and by Sunday evening we were pretty much ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a walk with Mike the other night I asked him, how long would it have taken us to launch Real Time Users pre-SixBySix? His answer: &lt;em&gt;we’d have never shipped it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s right &lt;em&gt;(don’t tell him that)&lt;/em&gt;. We wouldn’t have. We would have added feature after feature, built with needless shiny technology, and delayed launching month by month as we strived to build the next Google Analytics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since SixBySix, we’re much quicker to launch, and the quality has improved too. Our first project, &lt;a href="http://howsitgo.in/"&gt;HowsItGoin&lt;/a&gt; took 250 hours to ship. Real Time Users took under 15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what we’ve learnt, these past eighteen months. Ship stuff. Keep moving forwards. Learn as you go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Building and launching stuff is a skill, a habit, a muscle. The more you do it, the better you get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spending the past month or so thinking through what we want to be focussing on, the business we want to build, has been an essential step. But sometimes we need to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FredRivett/status/737384708024238084"&gt;step away from the magic whiteboards&lt;/a&gt; and get back to making stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who knows what’ll come of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This broadcast was brought to you by We Are CONTRAST Ltd. If you enjoyed this show, you may enjoy similar offerings, such as &lt;a href="https://blog.wearecontrast.com/why-you-don-t-have-to-quit-your-job-to-get-started-but-not-having-a-life-helps-ea9bdb230bcd#.tyo5zi1wt"&gt;Why You Don’t Have to Quit Your Job to Get Started (But Not Having a Life Helps)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://blog.wearecontrast.com/how-a-tweet-inspired-a-christmas-hackathon-ed2973ff0689#.55f0z9q63"&gt;How a Tweet Inspired a Christmas Hackathon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://blog.wearecontrast.com/10-easy-steps-to-launching-your-side-project-bbff783b08a8#.d5lsoac46"&gt;10 Easy Steps to Launching Your Side Project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://learningtolaunch.co/"&gt;Did we mention we wrote a book. It’s free. Like, totally free. You should read it 👀 📖&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
