<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-01-09T08:43:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>What are you optimising for?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/01/09/what-are-you-optimising-for/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/01/09/what-are-you-optimising-for/</id>
    <published>2017-01-09T08:43:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-09T09:07:01+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I'd just shaved and was cleaning up the inevitable beard hair related aftermath. As I was doing so a question came to mind: How much water would I use to wash the hair away?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's quicker to wash the hair down the sink with more water, but more water will be used. What's more important, time or water used?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all face questions like this regularly. It's a part of every day life. Will I get a taxi or walk? Will I buy on credit or wait and save? Will I be honest or lie?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, we all have to decide how much time we'll trade for money. There's a balance to be found, we need both, and we each have to work out our own tipping point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In amongst it all, is the underlying question: what are you really optimising for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question reminded me of a quote from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jasonlk"&gt;Jason Lemkin&lt;/a&gt; (paraphrased for clarity):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;~ "it's not healthy but it's what it takes to win." &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mijustin/status/810731396360568832"&gt;(see full quote here)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My immediate response was: win what? Certainly not life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It begs the question, are we optimising to win at business or win at life, win at family? What does our success criteria look like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For us, we're still in the stage of optimising primarily for learning. That may never change. If its a choice between learning now or money now, learning is often the best route as it enables us to earn more money later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We're in a fortunate place where we earn in our day jobs and work on our own stuff in the evenings and weekends. As a result, when opportunities come along that benefit us in terms of learning more than money, we can remember that learning is what we're optimising for, so despite a business being built on financials, it may well be the right path to take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mikeaag"&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt; and I were walking and talking and came onto the subject of a seed of an idea Mike had. At first glance it seemed like a bit of a distraction from our current focus. It seemed like an itch that was tempting to scratch but one we should be ignoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having spoken it through though it turned out to be much more of a contender than first thought. It aligned with the direction we want to go in, there was a big overlap in terms of what we'll learn in the project to what we'll need to learn in our main focus, and it is notably smaller than our big vision. It could well be the small slice of an idea we've been looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that if we go ahead with it, regardless of whether it will make us money, it will at least enable us to learn. We'll be in a better place to achieve our goals by taking this path, and at the worst it will just delay us a little.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our big goal is still to be financially independent, to support ourselves from our business. But despite that, the key for us is learning, not money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's a balance to be struck here. In business, the best type of learning &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; money. That's the validation that really matters. But despite that, what we care about, at least for now, is learning. Whether it comes from money or elsewhere, learning is still key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than focus on whether we think we'll get a direct financial ROI from our time invested in the project, we're asking ourselves, if nothing else, is this the best way to learn?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We've got a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; to learn, so we're optimising for that.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>2016&amp;#58; A year of learning</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/01/01/2016-a-year-of-learning/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/01/01/2016-a-year-of-learning/</id>
    <published>2017-01-01T21:26:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-03T10:51:33+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;2016 has been a year with good moments and bad moments. Overall, it wasn't my favourite year, but despite some sadness in how it's gone, there's been a lot to be thankful for. That's what I'll focus on in this years review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this review I cover:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Books I've read and listened to and my thoughts on each.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How our side projects have gone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Places I've visited.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fitness update.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Best purchases of the year.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A few of my goals for 2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="books"&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year Mike and I both decided to try out listening to audio books. I spend a fair amount of time commuting to and from work, which makes audio books ideal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that I also bought a Kindle and enjoyed reading both to unwind at night and to relax when travelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's the books I read and listened to in 2016, and my brief thoughts on each:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="books-ive-read-7"&gt;Books I've read (7)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B0165X8WN2/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;btkr=1"&gt;When Breath Becomes Air&lt;/a&gt; by Paul Kalanithi&lt;br /&gt;
★★★★½ — &lt;em&gt;Superbly written, humbling read about a man taken before his time. Recommended.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Naked-Economics-Undressing-Science-Revised-ebook/dp/B003NX6TYC/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1482832677&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=naked+economics"&gt;Naked Economics&lt;/a&gt; by Charles Wheelan and Burton G. Malkiel&lt;br /&gt;
★★★★☆ — &lt;em&gt;Nice simple insight into economics, my first foray into the topic and learnt a lot. An important book that gives a pathway for understanding the basics of economics, which more than ever is a hot topic worldwide.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.intercom.com/books/jobs-to-be-done"&gt;Intercom on Jobs-To-Be-Done&lt;/a&gt; by Intercom&lt;br /&gt;
★★★½☆ — &lt;em&gt;A key book for any product person to read, helps to shape how we see the products we create from the viewpoint of the user.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://uibreakfast.com/audit/"&gt;The UI Audit&lt;/a&gt; by Jane Portman&lt;br /&gt;
★★★☆☆ — &lt;em&gt;A nice short read for founders looking to get their head around the basics of their UI. A good guideline and useful resource.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/I-Am-Zlatan-Ibrahimovic-ebook/dp/B00DH4BL4U/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1482832724&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=i+am+zlatan"&gt;I am Zlatan Ibrahimovic&lt;/a&gt; by Zlatan Ibrahimovic&lt;br /&gt;
★★★☆☆ — &lt;em&gt;A relatively short autobiography with an interesting insight into one of the bigger characters in world football.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.miraclemorning.com/"&gt;The Miracle Morning&lt;/a&gt; by Hal Elrod&lt;br /&gt;
★★★☆☆ — &lt;em&gt;As with most self-help books, some useful points, all rather obvious but a nice prompt to put them into action.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.intercom.com/books/customer-engagement"&gt;Intercom on Customer Engagement&lt;/a&gt; by Intercom&lt;br /&gt;
★★½☆☆ — &lt;em&gt;A decent book on an important topic for any product person, but a little premature read for me so it didn't quite stick.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="books-i-listened-to-24"&gt;Books I listened to (24)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2016 I listened to 24 audio books, with a total listening time of over 202 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Ready-Player-One-Unabridged-Part-1-Audiobook/B007PR58RQ"&gt;Ready Player One&lt;/a&gt; by Ernest Cline &lt;em&gt;(15h 40m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★★½ — &lt;em&gt;Captivating throughout, had me listening intently and thinking about it when not. Despite not being much of a fiction man, this was my favourite book of 2016.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Deep-Work-Unabridged-Audiobook/B01D0E32T8"&gt;Deep Work&lt;/a&gt; by Cal Newport &lt;em&gt;(7h 44m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★★☆ — &lt;em&gt;An important piece for a society that has little time for focus. Not just theory, the author shares how the tactics he espouses have had a direct, positive impact on what he has achieved and how he has lived whilst doing so. Recommended.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/The-Power-of-Habit-Unabridged-Part-1-Audiobook/B007AK4V62"&gt;The Power of Habit&lt;/a&gt; by Charles Duhigg &lt;em&gt;(10h 56m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★★☆ — &lt;em&gt;A superb insight into how habits are formed and the power they wield in our lives. Recommended.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Business/The-Chimp-Paradox-Audiobook/B006VE4P6E"&gt;The Chimp Paradox&lt;/a&gt; by Prof. Steve Peters &lt;em&gt;(9h 45m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★★☆ — &lt;em&gt;The first book of the year and a great one to start on. A very accessible book on how the brain works, shedding light on some of our more irrational behaviours. Has helped me to gain greater control of my thoughts and behaviour.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Fiction/Nineteen-Eighty-Four-Audiobook/B016E6KWA6"&gt;1984&lt;/a&gt; by George Orwell &lt;em&gt;(12h 22m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★★☆ — &lt;em&gt;A classic that lived up to its billing. Harrowing how accurately it portrays elements of modern life.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/The-Fault-in-Our-Stars-Unabridged-Audiobook/B006T45PHO"&gt;The Fault in Our Stars&lt;/a&gt; by John Green &lt;em&gt;(7h 14m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★★☆ — &lt;em&gt;An enticing read, that drew me in and had me hooked. Very much enjoyed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Biographies-Memoirs/Steve-Jobs-Audiobook/B005XOXIPM"&gt;Steve Jobs: The Exclusive Biography&lt;/a&gt; by Walter Isaacson &lt;em&gt;(25h 7m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★★☆ — &lt;em&gt;An enjoyable, balanced view into the life of one of the most creative men of the past half a century.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Elon-Musk-Unabridged-Part-1-Audiobook/B01EI50RAU"&gt;Elon Musk&lt;/a&gt; by Ashlee Vance &lt;em&gt;(13h 23m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★★☆ — &lt;em&gt;An insightful look into one of the worlds most intriguing men helping to shape our collective future.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Business/The-Phoenix-Project-Audiobook/B00VB034GK"&gt;The Phoenix Project&lt;/a&gt; by Gene Kim, Kevin Behr and George Spafford &lt;em&gt;(11h 53m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★½☆ — &lt;em&gt;An enjoyable novel with useful lessons about how to run a business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Rich-Dad-Poor-Dad-Unabridged-Audiobook/B008BT35R2"&gt;Rich Dad Poor Dad&lt;/a&gt; by Robert T. Kiyosaki &lt;em&gt;(6h 9m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★½☆ — &lt;em&gt;Useful for anyone wanting to get a better grasp of their finances.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Hitchhikers-Guide-to-the-Galaxy-Unabridged-Audiobook/B0093Q1NFS"&gt;Hitchiker's Guide to the Galaxy&lt;/a&gt;  by Douglas Adams &lt;em&gt;(5h 51m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★½☆ — &lt;em&gt;An enjoyable listen with many moments where simple sentences are slightly tweaked in humerous ways. Didn't captivate but amused.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/The-Restaurant-at-the-End-of-the-Universe-Unabridged-Audiobook/B00AAZBFRC"&gt;The Restaurant at the End of the Universe&lt;/a&gt; by Douglas Adams &lt;em&gt;(5h 47m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★½☆ — &lt;em&gt;As above.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Mostly-Harmless-Unabridged-Audiobook/B00AJEBICQ"&gt;Mostly Harmless&lt;/a&gt; by Douglas Adams &lt;em&gt;(6h 32m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★½☆ — &lt;em&gt;As above.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/The-Art-of-Negotiating-the-Best-Deal-Part-1-Audiobook/B00JLJBW6C"&gt;The Art of Negotiating the Best Deal&lt;/a&gt; by Prof. Seth Freeman &lt;em&gt;(12h 45m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★½☆ — &lt;em&gt;A useful introduction from a university professor on a topic important for any business person. Already come in use.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Rise-of-the-Robots-Unabridged-Audiobook/B01CGURY8C"&gt;Rise of the Robots&lt;/a&gt; by Martin Ford &lt;em&gt;(10h 17m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★½☆ — &lt;em&gt;An evermore important topic, well covered, a good grounding for anyone concerned or interested in what the future may look like and the societal challenges we may face.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Anything-You-Want-Unabridged-Audiobook/B00563GVYA"&gt;Anything You Want&lt;/a&gt; by Derek Sivers &lt;em&gt;(1h 31m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★½☆ — &lt;em&gt;A nice short listen with counterintuitive tips that make you question the considered wisdom of how to run a business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Sprint-Unabridged-Audiobook/B01BXB2KQQ"&gt;Sprint&lt;/a&gt; by Jake Knapp &lt;em&gt;(6h 9m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★½☆ — &lt;em&gt;A handbook on how to drastically speed up innovation by getting answers to the big questions quickly. Certainly worthwhile reading for those interested in product development.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Drive-Unabridged-Audiobook/B004N1UIAY"&gt;Drive&lt;/a&gt; by Daniel H. Pink &lt;em&gt;(5h 58m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★☆☆ — &lt;em&gt;A useful yet not overly notable look at what motivates people.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Oversubscribed-Unabridged-Audiobook/B013KCG5DA"&gt;Oversubscribed&lt;/a&gt; by Daniel Priestley &lt;em&gt;(5h 16m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★☆☆ — &lt;em&gt;Sheds insight into the benefits of making people wait, and how to make the most of scarcity, whether real or artificial.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Growth-Hacker-Marketing-Unabridged-Audiobook/B018H9EGKA"&gt;Growth Hacker Marketing&lt;/a&gt; by Ryan Holiday &lt;em&gt;(2h 17m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★☆☆ — &lt;em&gt;A decent introduction to the mentality of the growth hacker.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Smarter-Faster-Better-Unabridged-Audiobook/B01BX8RZ1Y"&gt;Smarter Faster Better&lt;/a&gt; by Charles Duhigg &lt;em&gt;(10h 22m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★☆☆ — &lt;em&gt;A collection of useful tips on how to improve our business lives, yet due to the scattered nature of the book didn't leave me with notable takeaways.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Business/Purple-Cow-Audiobook/B004EW53FM"&gt;Purple Cow&lt;/a&gt; by Seth Godin &lt;em&gt;(2h 58m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★★☆☆ — &lt;em&gt;A simple book that drives home one important message, marketing is all about standing out from the crowd.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Mans-Search-for-Meaning-Unabridged-Audiobook/B004EVQKKK"&gt;Man's Search For Meaning&lt;/a&gt; by Victor E. Frankl &lt;em&gt;(4h 47m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★½☆☆ — &lt;em&gt;An important topic, but quite monotonous at times and tough to stick with. Potentially says more about my attention span than the books content.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Business/People-over-Profit-Audiobook/B00WFINV4W"&gt;People over Profit&lt;/a&gt; by Dale Partridge &lt;em&gt;(3h 5m)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
★★☆☆☆ — &lt;em&gt;A decent message but the book didn't captivate. Nothing offensive but never offering anything too notable, won't be rushing to recommend.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="side-projects"&gt;Side projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the turn of the year &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mikeaag"&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt; and I were half way through writing our book, Learning To Launch, and had ambitions to focus on one project, in an attempt to move from simply launching side projects to building a business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year didn't quite take the shape we'd hoped it to, but we made progress nevertheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="learning-to-launchhttplearningtolaunchco-the-book"&gt;&lt;a href="http://learningtolaunch.co/"&gt;Learning To Launch&lt;/a&gt; (the book)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out writing a book isn't all that easy. We kinda knew that before embarking on it, but now we &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; that in a more tangible way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After writing over 20,000 words, we deleted almost half of it and ended up shipping the book at the end of March. It &lt;a href="https://www.producthunt.com/posts/learning-to-launch"&gt;went down well on Product Hunt&lt;/a&gt; but wasn't a project we intended to heavily focus on, and as a result we haven't pushed it much since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a cycle we've been in for a while, one we purposefully put ourselves into a couple of years ago to get us into the habit of shipping, and is one we're now looking to level up on, shipping still, but then growing a product from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing the book was a goal in and of itself for us, and I'm glad we did it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="real-time-users"&gt;Real Time Users&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In June we launched &lt;a href="https://realtimeusers.bycontrast.co/?ref=producthunt"&gt;Real Time Users&lt;/a&gt;. Having launched 8 tech projects in 2015, RTU was our only tech launch of 2016. RTU was inspired by a couple of comments from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/marckohlbrugge"&gt;Marc Köhlbrugge&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mijustin"&gt;Justin Jackson&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We built and launched it in a weekend, primarily to get back into the swing of things, and it felt good to ship something again. We also learnt a good amount about the basics of running our own analytics app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.wearecontrast.com/make-stuff-ff82f78cf5a9#.jtmt05woe"&gt;You can read the story behind Real Time Users here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="mastermind"&gt;Mastermind&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've appreciated the benefits of community and accountability for a while, it played a big part in our (comparative) success of 2015. This year I took it up a notch and joined a mastermind group. We meet up online each Monday night for an hour and check in on our successes and failures from the past week, and what our goal(s) are for the week to come. We also have a rotating hotseat, that gives one person each week a chance to go deep on a topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since joining the mastermind earlier this year I've already seen superb results, with each member making good, if not great progress towards their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With it being our first half year together, I'm excited to see where we go individually and collectively in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="the-podcast"&gt;The podcast&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest projects we undertook in 2016 was starting up a new podcast, &lt;a href="http://hitreply.co/"&gt;Hit Reply&lt;/a&gt;. We started it with the aim of creating a high quality, relatively short podcast to help founders get an inside view at another startup, from pre-launch through to scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, after getting 8 episodes in, and receiving listening numbers far higher than we expected (over 4,500 listens), we realised this wasn't a good fit for us. Each episode was taking up nearly all our time that week, and the audience we were building wasn't one we wanted to focus on in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, we stopped the podcast to focus on other endeavours. That said, it might be something I'd look to revisit in the future. There's certainly some benefits to podcasting over other content methods like blogging, and with &lt;a href="https://www.producthunt.com/podcasts"&gt;Product Hunt&lt;/a&gt; promoting podcast episodes it's an interesting avenue to explore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="sold-founderskithttpfounderskitco"&gt;Sold &lt;a href="http://founderskit.co/"&gt;FoundersKit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.producthunt.com/posts/founderskit"&gt;Having launched FoundersKit over 16 months earlier&lt;/a&gt;, we decided it wasn't a project we wanted to pursue. It didn't really fit with our plans moving forwards and we knew it would work better in someone else's hands. We reached out to Leon at Startup Foundation in early December and happily agreed for him to acquire FoundersKit a few weeks later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;note: As part of the deal, FoundersKit has been rebranded to Startup Deals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="relaunched-fredrivettcom"&gt;Relaunched fredrivett.com&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a prompt from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tranhelen"&gt;Helen Tran&lt;/a&gt;, I finally got round to launching a new site for myself, &lt;a href="http://fredrivett.com/"&gt;fredrivett.com&lt;/a&gt;. It's a simple setup, with &lt;a href="https://middlemanapp.com/"&gt;Middleman&lt;/a&gt; generating static files and hosting them on Github pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="weeks-straight-of-weekly-blogging"&gt;21 weeks straight of weekly blogging&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In August I set out to up my writing game, and set myself the challenge of publishing weekly. On top of hitting publish, I started sending a small email to our list with a heads up about the new post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've definitely improved as a writer in that time, or at least in my ability to actually write. I now find it easier to sit down at my laptop, collect my thoughts and write a post. There's a real benefit to regularly taking a mind dump. It always brings more clarity to my thoughts and I often find things in there that I wasn't consciously aware of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure if it's a goal I'll continue in 2017, but I want to continue to take a seed of a thought and expand it out to see what else is there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="spent-way-too-long-trying-to-do-it-right"&gt;Spent way too long trying to do it &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of all though, &lt;a href="http://fredrivett.com/2016/10/03/am-i-doing-it-right/"&gt;we spent way too long trying to do it right&lt;/a&gt;. We knew that we had to change tact from 2015, but we ended up swinging the pendulum from "silly little side projects" way too far over to "serious business thing".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to find something we could commit 3, 6, 12 months to, and spent too long trying to find the perfect idea. This part is hard. We did a lot right (we spent a good amount of time working out who we wanted to serve and what we enjoyed doing) but I'm sure we could have cut out a lot of wasted time. Hindsight is beautiful though, and the main thing is we made progress in the end, despite frustrations on the journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="started-contracting"&gt;Started contracting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big change for me was going from permanent work to contracting. In September I left my role of 18 months at &lt;a href="https://store.tpo.com/"&gt;TPO&lt;/a&gt; and signed my first contract with &lt;a href="http://spoke.law/"&gt;Spoke&lt;/a&gt;. It's been a good move for me, taking me into the next step professionally. I'm enjoying working in a small team on an interesting project, being paid to get further experience in the early stages of a new product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, I've been working 4 days a week which has been a nice stepping stone, giving me more time to focus on our side projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="visited-4-countries-10-cities-9-new"&gt;Visited 4 countries (10 cities, 9 new)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="barcelona"&gt;Barcelona&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April, I headed out to Barcelona for a quick weekend trip with a couple of friends. We booked everything up on the Friday, flew out Saturday morning and back on Sunday night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main purpose of the flight was a trip to Camp Nou, arguably one of the greatest football stadiums, home to one of the best teams and one of the best players in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's definitely something to be said for quick weekend trips like this, they're a great way to explore new places and make memories without spending too much time or money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="valencia"&gt;Valencia&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May, after the success of the Barcelona trip, a couple of us headed out to Valencia for a long weekend. The Airbnb we booked was new and hadn't any reviews, so it was a bit of a risk. Fortunately it turned out to be a great shout, with the flat, host and location (opposite Valencia beach) perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made sure to catch a game at the famous Mestalla stadium, home to the steepest stands in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="paris-lyon--st-etienne"&gt;Paris, Lyon &amp;amp; St Etienne&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June, we headed out to France for Euro 2016. We started up in Paris, heading to the fanzone under the Eiffel tower. On the day of England Wales we arrived in central Paris early in the day England shirts on show. Unfortunately we didn't plan for a downpour, and got totally soaked. Straight from there we headed to the fanzone, where the fans were embracing the wet weather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few days in Paris, we got an overnight coach (an experience) down to Lyon. We spent a few days there, heading down to St Etienne to watch England Slovakia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it was great to visit Lyon and St Etienne, two new cities for me, and experience the tournament atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="berlin"&gt;Berlin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In September I headed out to Berlin, my first visit to the capital of Germany. I met up with a few friends out there and enjoyed getting a grasp of both the historical and current sides of this great city. Will certainly return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="san-francisco-la-san-diego--new-york"&gt;San Francisco, LA, San Diego &amp;amp; New York&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October Mike and I headed out for a Californian road trip with a few days in New York on the way back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We landed in San Francisco, spent 4 days in the city and the Bay Area. I enjoyed cycling the Golden Gate Bridge over to Sausalito, a beautiful little town just ten minutes away from the city. Stanford was a superb experience too, a real world class place to study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After San Francisco, we spent 3 days driving down the coast through Big Sur, before arriving at LA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We only spent a couple of days in LA, but more than enough time to have a few stories that we won't be forgetting in a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After LA, we drove down to San Diego, staying the night in La Jolla, a beautiful little area on the outskirts of San Diego.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we flew from San Diego to New York. With it being our first time in New York, we spent most of it seeing the sights and being a nondescript tourist. A cool city, one I plan to visit again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="fitness"&gt;Fitness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2016 was a decent year for fitness. I definitely made progress, if nothing remarkable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the turn of the year I'd put on a bit of unwanted weight, so decided to try out Intermittent Fasting. I didn't follow any specific version of IF, simply skipping breakfast and lunch on Tuesdays and Thursdays, effectively creating two 24 hour windows where I didn't eat each week (dinner 'til dinner).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people speak of health benefits to IF beyond simple calorie restriction. Personally those health benefits were just a bonus if true, with IF providing a simple way to limit calorie intake either way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally find this method of calorie restriction far easier than more standard diets, as I pretty much ate as I pleased outside of these two periods. Another bonus has been my significantly reduced appetite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 52 weeks of fasting, I'm happy with how it's worked out, having lost a good amount of body fat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside fasting I swam on and off and stepped up doing bodyweight exercises (read: chin ups and push ups).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having started the year unable to do a chin up, I can now do 10 in a row, which just goes to show the progress that can be made with a little effort every now and then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the progress, I've still got some way to go with some of my fitness goals, namely to get running and playing football again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="best-purchases-this-year"&gt;Best purchases this year&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm generally quite frugal with my money, only buying something when I know I want it and will benefit from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of the three main purchases this year were ones I'd thought about for months before deciding to take the plunge. I'm happy with all three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="bose-qc35"&gt;Bose QC35&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bose.co.uk/en_gb/products/headphones/over_ear_headphones/quietcomfort-35-wireless.html"&gt;These headphones are very good&lt;/a&gt;. The sound quality is decent, certainly good enough yet nothing remarkable, but combined with the excellent noise cancelling these are superb headphones for anyone who's regularly in noisy environments (think commuting and open plan offices).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefit of getting a bit of headspace is hard to put into money. The fact these headphones are wireless is a really nice touch too. Very happy with these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="kindle-paperwhite"&gt;Kindle Paperwhite&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been wanting to get a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Amazon-Kindle-Paperwhite-6-Inch-4GB-E-Reader/dp/B00QJDO0QC"&gt;Kindle&lt;/a&gt; for a little while, but the stack of paper books at the side of my bed has kept me from rushing out to get one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2016 I finally got involved and I'm very happy I did. The reading experience is great. Primarily due to the distraction free nature of the device, mimicking the paper counterpart, coupled with the portability and a few little niceties. I particularly enjoy the subtle backlight and reading stats (% through book, minutes left in chapter).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="fitbit-flex-2"&gt;Fitbit Flex 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final purchase of note was a &lt;a href="https://www.fitbit.com/uk/flex2"&gt;Fitbit Flex 2&lt;/a&gt; in November. Mike's been a Fitbit fan since the summer and with the Flex 2 release I was happy to jump on the bandwagon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Flex 2 is my type of wearable: minimal. I'm not a watch wearer so this little device has been a good stepping stone. I'm also looking forward to testing out the swim mode in the new year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="looking-ahead-to-2017"&gt;Looking ahead to 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've not yet fully thought out my goals for 2017, but here's a few I want to target:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sort out my legs to get running and playing football again.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get a stranger on the internet to pay us a monthly fee for a product we make.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visit a new continent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've got a fair few stretch goals, and a few personal goals on top of this, but if I only achieve those three it won't have been a bad year.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Being you</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/12/19/being-you/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/12/19/being-you/</id>
    <published>2016-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-12-20T10:09:59+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“People travel to wonder
at the height of the mountains,
at the huge waves of the seas,
at the long course of the rivers,
at the vast compass of the ocean,
at the circular motion of the stars,
and yet they pass by themselves
without wondering.”&lt;br /&gt;
— Saint Augustine of Hippo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isn't it remarkable how little we're truly ourselves. We're often so afraid that anyone will see us as we see ourselves that we wear masks and project our best version at every available opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As humans we are prone to over analysing how others see us. Ever noticed how we pay so much attention to one negative comment but ignore ten positive ones? We're desperate to know what people &lt;em&gt;really think&lt;/em&gt;. Are they telling the truth whilst the others are just saying what I want to hear?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's easy to sugarcoat everything we do in an attempt to avoid judgement and criticism, to stop the negative comments having a chance to outweigh the positive ones. No place is this more prevalent than on Facebook. Every post shows the side we want to show, whilst our Instagram feed paints a picture of how wonderful our life is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, most people just want to fit in. To be a part of the crowd, to never stand out. That's fine, but it's not how you build a business. It's not how you draw an audience. It's not how you make deep friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a business to ever work it has to stand out. That is the whole premise of marketing. The ability to gain attention by being different to your competitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For friendship to work, you have to be real. No-one wants to be friends with the average of everyone's perceived socially acceptable human being. No-one has 2.5 kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Respect and admiration are built upon appreciating the similarities and differences we have. This is true both in business and in life. Some of my best friends are markedly different to me. I've learnt so much from these people. Heck, we even named our business Contrast in reference to the fact &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mikeaag"&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt; and I are so different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not everyone will like you or agree with you, and that's fine. You will be wrong sometimes, make mistakes, and be human. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FredRivett/status/761484340417167361?lang=en"&gt;You are a work in progress, after all&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's important we try to be real. To be us. People buy from those they trust and they trust those who are real. You're far more likely to make a sale if you acknowledge some of the downsides of your offering than if you pretend that everything is perfect. People are wary of perfection, nothing is perfect. If you're up front with the downsides then people will feel they have a better picture of what you're offering and more confidence in the rest of what you're saying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honesty and integrity (being you) then, are good for both business and life. But regardless of this, they're actually healthy. They're freeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's not easy, but we don't have to go all in. We need only take baby steps, moving forwards little by little. Evolving and growing over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You’re a ghost driving a meat coated skeleton made from stardust. What do you have to be afraid of?” — unknown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all get one shot at life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much better to be loved for who we are than liked for who we're not.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>North star</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/12/12/north-star/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/12/12/north-star/</id>
    <published>2016-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-12-13T10:33:05+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Knowing where you’d like to go is important. It helps us frame the decisions we make now that move us towards where we want to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our book, &lt;a href="https://learningtolaunch.co/"&gt;Learning To Launch&lt;/a&gt;, we described how we strike the balance between the long term and short term:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Have long term goals in mind, and short term goals in focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means knowing where you’re trying to go and having that as a constant reference point in the back of your mind. &lt;strong&gt;A North Star that you use to guide you on the journey.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Mike and I, that North Star is freedom. Freedom from the 9-5. Freedom from selling our time. Free to choose how to spend it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the commitments we have, after doing some napkin maths, we’ve worked out we roughly need to be taking in £100k a year. We’ll likely be selling in dollars, so in reality that will be roughly $120k/year, or $10k MRR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That feels a long way off. We’ve launched &lt;a href="http://wearecontrast.com/"&gt;a few different things&lt;/a&gt; in the past, and &lt;a href="http://founderskit.co/"&gt;one of those&lt;/a&gt; is making a small amount of money, but we don’t have an easy pathway on how we’re going to get from here to there. There are so many unknowns, we’d never be able to predict the path we will take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s ok. Despite that, we’ve taken our best guess at breaking down the big goal into smaller, more attainable goals. Instead of trying to get to financial freedom now, we’re focussed on simply finding a problem that interests us, that we’d like to spend a few months finding out more about and attempting to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not to say any problem that we’d like to solve will do. There are other checks that have to be met, which fall under the broad heading of “how well placed are we to solve this?”. We’re not attempting to solve world hunger just yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge with a goal so seemingly unattainable as financial freedom is that it can cripple us from moving forwards. If we focus too heavily on “will this idea ever earn $10k a month?” then we may never take that step and launch a product that can make us $100 a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to strike the right balance. &lt;a href="http://fredrivett.com/2016/08/29/healthy-pressure/"&gt;Some pressure is healthy&lt;/a&gt;. A little pressure can help bring clarity to what matters, but too much can stop us dead in our tracks. We need a pressure valve that we can tweak to keep us motivated without feeling overwhelmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For us, having that smaller, more attainable “find a problem that we’re interested in solving” goal helps lower the pressure. We can chip away at this and see progress take shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we attempt to move towards our goal, progress will never be linear. There will be times when we make great progress, and times when we feel we’re taking two steps forward and three steps back. This up and down journey leads to great highs and low lows, which is why we have to view progress over a greater period of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have I made progress this past six months? This year, 2016, did I move towards where I want to be, or have I stagnated? Am I on the right path, or do I need to make a change?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, as we look back, we’ve not made the progress we’d hoped to. I’m just being honest. We’ve made some, we’re in a better place now than we were twelve months ago, but we’ve wasted too much time going round in circles, &lt;a href="http://fredrivett.com/2016/10/03/am-i-doing-it-right/"&gt;stuck in analysis paralysis&lt;/a&gt;. We’re attempting to learn from that now and not make that same mistake again in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you look back over this year, take time to consider the highs and lows, and take time to think about whether where you want to go has changed, or whether you’ve lost track of your North Star. Recalibrate yourself to live 2017 with intentionality. Set a big ambitious goal and break it down into smaller attainable steps on the journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our plans never stay fully static, they always evolve and change as we move towards them, as they should. But having that North Star to look up to when the times are tough is important, else we wander, round and round, moving, but never actually getting anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Connecting Things</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/12/05/connecting-things/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/12/05/connecting-things/</id>
    <published>2016-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-12-06T10:37:16+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Solving problems is at the heart of any great product or business. Behind every shiny product or lightbulb idea is a real problem being solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When trying to solve a problem, there are two key activities we must undertake, data gathering and data connecting. The more data points you gather, the more you’ll have to connect together to form creative patterns. As Steve Jobs said, &lt;em&gt;“creativity is just connecting things.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to make the best data connections is to collect two types of data, specific and generic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specific data is the information you learn about the problem you’re trying to solve. So if you’re trying to help mechanics improve their day to day life, then you should spend time with some mechanics. Read a variety of mechanics books and magazines. Interview mechanics, asking them a bunch of open ended questions. Soak up all sorts of information about mechanics, why they do what they do, what they enjoy doing, what they dislike doing, what they struggle doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then once you’ve spent enough time getting into the head of the mechanics, you should start to see a pattern emerge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing this sort of investigating can be fun when you’re in the flow, other times it’s a bit of a drag but you plough on, but either way I find it easy to justify this time as work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other side to data gathering is the generic data points. This can come from anywhere. Reading about anything you’re interested in is a great way to collect generic data. Listening to podcasts or audio books and watching films and documentaries are more great ways to add depth and variety into our general data store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This generic data collection doesn’t feel like work at all, and it isn’t really, it’s just life. But the more non-specific data you collect the more interesting combinations you can make when you come to connect the data points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connecting the data points can happen anytime, anywhere. Often a good amount of this will happen hand in hand with gathering data points. As you’re learning about the people you’re looking to help and the problems they’re experiencing you’ll start to see threads appear between the different data points you’ve been gathering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often though, we need to get away from our normal surroundings to create the best connections. Have you ever noticed how many of our best ideas happen in the shower?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jonah Lehrer thinks its to do with quietening ourselves, stopping ourselves from being externally distracted to listen to our subconscious that’s already been making some of these connections:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“…so many insights happen during warm showers. For many people, it’s the most relaxing part of the day. It’s not until we’re being massaged by warm water, unable to check our e-mail, that we’re finally able to hear the quiet voices in the backs of our heads telling us about the insight. The answers have been their all along–we just weren’t listening.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Showers are a classic breeding ground for creative connections, but so are quiet, scenic walks. I find I’m often scribbling down insights (read: tweeting) that come to me as I go for a walk through a local field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But despite this increased creativity, I often find it hard to justify going on these walks, as it doesn’t &lt;em&gt;feel like&lt;/em&gt; work (don’t worry I shower every day). Every step I take outside of my door is a step away from my laptop, where I &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; I should be, &lt;em&gt;being productive&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Doing the work&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s an issue. If I’m to solve the most interesting problems in the most effective, creative ways, then I need to give myself time to breathe. To quieten myself. To not be distracted. I need to take the time to connect the dots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is as much work as data gathering. I have to discipline myself to step away from my laptop and relax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find the balance between focus and quiet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The balance between data gathering and data connecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Creativity is just connecting things. When you ask creative people how they did something, they feel a little guilty because they didn’t really do it, they just saw something. It seemed obvious to them after a while. That’s because they were able to connect experiences they’ve had and synthesize new things. And the reason they were able to do that was that they’ve had more experiences or they have thought more about their experiences than other people. Unfortunately, that’s too rare a commodity. A lot of people in our industry haven’t had very diverse experiences. So they don’t have enough dots to connect, and they end up with very linear solutions without a broad perspective on the problem. The broader one’s understanding of the human experience, the better design we will have.
&lt;cite&gt;Steve Jobs, Wired, February 1995&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>That's the problem</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/11/28/that-s-the-problem/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/11/28/that-s-the-problem/</id>
    <published>2016-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-29T09:47:57+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was looking through our problem/idea list recently, and a few ideas jumped out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of those was an idea for goal tracking for teams. It was born from a personal pain point as an employee at a company that used to set short, medium and long term goals. The only issue was, they never told us what they were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I got thinking. What if I built something to solve this problem?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution I had in mind was just a simple system of logging goals, sharing and viewing them. The pain point was getting everyone on the same page. And it turns out &lt;em&gt;that was the problem.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked about this in &lt;a href="http://startupfoundation.co/hashtag_startup/"&gt;Startup Chat&lt;/a&gt; recently, and someone mentioned how at her company of 30 they use a simple Google doc. No fancy software, just a simple shared doc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This surprised me. For a team of 30 I envisioned them using some purpose built tool with a few extra features, not a simple Google doc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then I remembered something &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mijustin"&gt;Justin Jackson&lt;/a&gt; said a while back in his post, &lt;a href="https://justinjackson.ca/we-are-not-normal-people/"&gt;we are not normal people&lt;/a&gt;. He was at his barbers, dreaming of how he could improve their scheduling setup. How he could build out a new software solution that would bring the hairdressers archaic paper system into the twenty-first century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out, his barber had already tried out a bunch of software solutions, likely from similar conversations had with other tech minded clients, and they were all horrible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One particular point of Justin’s story stands out. His barber said this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;"All the software I’ve tried just gets in the way."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is key. Software, far from being a knight in shining armour, was actually overkill for him. An unnecessary burden. It was a more complicated process than simply looking at a paper calendar and writing directly on that. It wasn’t a problem he was motivated to solve because the core of the pain point was solved in the simplest way possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any software solution might make gains on the periphery but the core issue was already solved for the one that mattered. The barber was the one who used the system and who decided how their businesses money would be spent, and they were not motivated to fix this problem because they didn’t see it as a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same goes for my company goal tracking idea. There could be some gains made by using a purpose built piece of software, but the core task of logging goals and being able to view them was already solved. It’s solved by whiteboards and it’s solved by shared docs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem, in my mind, was getting everyone &lt;em&gt;on the same page.&lt;/em&gt; The issue with this idea was that the tools they were using already did this, quite literally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In development terms, all I was looking to create was a glorified &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Create,_read,_update_and_delete"&gt;CRUD&lt;/a&gt;. Create goals. Read goals. Update goals. Delete goals. Whiteboards or shared docs are the best solution for this for a lot of companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a common problem. &lt;em&gt;The problem entrepreneurs have with problems.&lt;/em&gt; As creative entrepreneurial types, we’re always on the lookout for problems we can solve. Processes we can improve. Shiny things we can create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to try and create systems and solutions that are complex and beautiful but people just want the easiest, simplest way to get the job done. Often that’s using a tool they already have and know how to use. A new shiny interface isn’t a plus, it’s a hindrance.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
