<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2021-01-01T18:58:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>2020&amp;#58; Letting go</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2021/01/01/2020-letting-go/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2021/01/01/2020-letting-go/</id>
    <published>2021-01-01T18:58:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-01T18:58:29+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;They say hindsight is 20-20. Looking back, it's been quite the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone knows the macro, the events that have affected us all. All the ways we've been shut away from each other, the pain, the suffering, the ensuing perspective. So I won't spend too much time writing about that which we all already know. We've lived through it, each of us. We've all been boats in the same storm. Some of us have had the luxury of boats well equipped, feeling the storm as a minor inconvenience, and irritant, whilst others have faced severe heartbreak and challenge, and far more beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'll be honest. I've been very fortunate that the virus, and all that came with it, has been inconvenient, undesirable, in many ways unenjoyable, but nothing compared to how it has affected many others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've not relished the shape life has taken in 2020, but life in 2020 was far from the difficulties others have unexpectedly been faced with. My heart goes out to them, to you, if you were on of those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big theme this year for us all has been perspective. All the things we took for granted being snatched away, us left sitting inside our homes with nothing to do except ponder, mourn and watch yet another Netflix series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of the macro, the events we've all lived through, 2020 for me has been a real mixture of a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even before everything kicked off with the pandemic, it was one of the most challenging I'd faced. And in other ways, it was one marked with progress, with achievement, and with maturation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the big theme has been a shift in perspective, the more personal one has been letting go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Letting go of control, of my belief that I can do what I want, when I want, that I'm the master of my own destiny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Letting go of those I've loved. Both my nan, who passed away peacefully at a good old age, and a relationship, that no matter how I tried, just wouldn't work out how I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Letting go of my twenties, of my "youth", of the perspective that life is infinite, that death is just a story but not one that I will ever really have to face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's been good things too. The maturity that only adversity can bring. The progress I've made in my physical health, losing weight and putting on some muscle. &lt;a href="https://yaha.fyi/"&gt;Building my first solo app&lt;/a&gt;. Finally sorting out my teeth, and the confidence boost that has brought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's been beautiful moments too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be it cycling around London with my sister, brother-in-law and niece. Be it &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CDBSxP6nRZj/"&gt;impromptu picnics with the sunset painting a beautiful backdrop to the skyline of the city that I love&lt;/a&gt;. Be it late night chats by the Thames until the early hours. The &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/B9wiWhfnAhw/"&gt;wandering hikes through nature&lt;/a&gt;. The trips, to &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CDHi4SeHQ3t/"&gt;Switzerland&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/B9YtUU9HEjC/"&gt;Vienna&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/B9rh_YYHVco/"&gt;Lake District&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CFzMretHDmr/"&gt;Cotswolds&lt;/a&gt;. Beautiful sunsets through winding British countryside after a day exploring the coast with friends. Be it chats with the parents and hearing more of their life stories, that puts my inconveniences into perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been very blessed. I really have no standing to complain, and yet despite that, the highs don't simply negate the lows. Both exist, both were experienced and lived through, and both have made their mark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I've come to learn, which sounds awfully cliché, is the power of love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can influence it, choosing what and upon whom to focus it, feeding it so it grows, or starving it so it diminishes, but we cannot simply control it. Love isn't something that is under our control, in our domain, it is a force that is above us and beyond us, not that which we can dominate as we see fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love is out there, and when we are open and allow it, is what comes to live within us. It is the force that connects us one to another, that gives life its meaning and makes everything else fade away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I sat in the sheer beauty of the Swiss Alps in the summer just gone, it was love that drew my mind back to a bench in East London. Despite being surrounded by the majesty of nature, it was a shoddy old bench, overlooking an unpleasant tower block, in a run down area of East London, where I really wished I was, where I'd have swapped it all for in a instant. A shared memory that I yearned to live again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all just goes to show, the external, the career, the achievements, the travel, they are not the goal for which we search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love is the purpose of our lives. It is only in the connection to those we love, that we are truly fulfilled, that we are truly home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2020 has been one hell of a year. Here's hoping that the experiences each of us have been through, the stormy seas that we've had to weather, those we've shared and those unique to each of us, will help us find our way home in 2021 and beyond. I hope all of that for me, and for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>2019&amp;#58; Deeper relationships</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2020/01/01/2019-deeper-relationships/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2020/01/01/2019-deeper-relationships/</id>
    <published>2020-01-01T22:43:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-01-02T10:39:16+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;2019 has been a year of highs and lows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started off with uncertainty and challenge. Having decided to leave The Dot at the end of last year, the startup I was on path to co-found from &lt;a href="https://foundersfactory.com"&gt;Founders Factory&lt;/a&gt;'s London incubator, I was left with a void to fill. But doing something for something's sake makes no sense, so I spent the first couple of months working out what I wanted, and feeling out the different opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I considered remote roles, part-time roles, contract and perm. But in the end I really liked the folks I met at &lt;a href="https://octopuswealth.com"&gt;Octopus Wealth&lt;/a&gt;, and the idea of having one less variable in my day to day life, so decided to take a permanent role as a Senior Software Engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team was small, just the 4 of us, the Head of Engineering, a couple of junior developers and myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end I wasn't at Octopus Wealth for long. Things didn't end up working out, as the business model didn't play out as the owners had hoped, and so after just 5 months the entire tech team were laid off and the business pivoted away from a tech-led model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed my time there though, the two more junior engineers progressed a lot in that time and I developed more skills in leadership as well as technically, using TypeScript and Redux for the first time. Plus working right next to St Paul's Cathedral, one of my favourite buildings in London, was a daily treat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-job-hunt-round-2"&gt;The job hunt: round 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon hearing I was being made redundant, I was suddenly back where I was at the start of the year, working out what I wanted in a role, 5 months on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again the main dilemma was between going the contract route or taking a permanent role, despite the lack of "permanence" in the role that had just ended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end I decided to take another perm role. The extra money and flexibility of contracting was tempting, but the company I ended up joining, and the fit of the role to my skillset and interests was too much to pass up in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general when making life decisions, those decisions that are bigger and weightier, and have a sizeable effect on the direction my life takes, I try to take a longer-term view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What decision now is most likely to have the best payback for me in 5-10 years time? Of course I have no idea of what life will look like then, but optimising for future Fred is preferable than focussing on what my bank balance will look like 6 months from now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In actuality that means looking at what skills and experiences I'd gain from each path, and which type of doors that may open up down the line. Sometimes taking a pay cut in the short-term is the most likely way to gain the highest financial returns in the mid-to-long. And financial returns certainly aren't the only, or even main, measurement to live by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondarily, a big theme over the past year has been "optimise for the least regret". This has gradually evolved over time, but has come into focus this year as I've made some bigger decisions at regular intervals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew this was a role I wanted to take on as it was a relatively unique opportunity, and gave me a chance to play a part in a startup with big ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="moving-home"&gt;Moving home&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another of those decisions was to leave my one bed flat in Hoxton. I left before I was made aware of being made redundant, and had no next place lined up. I'm fortunate that my parents live only an hour outside London, so I briefly stayed there whilst finding where next I'd call home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up moving to Limehouse, in a flat share, and 6 months in I'm so happy with my decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/B6F7hooFlVa/"&gt;It's a lovely area&lt;/a&gt;, with the River Thames a thirty second walk away, the park fifteen seconds away and Limehouse dock &amp;amp; canals a minute or two away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transport wise it's ideal too, just fifteen minutes on the train into central London, and a fifteen minute walk into Canary Wharf, London's financial district.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canary Wharf, it turned out, is where my new office would be. This was an unexpected blessing, having moved into the Limehouse flat before being made redundant and starting the new role. Having a fifteen minute walk along the Thames with views over the city is a daily blessing, and I'd argue that I've got to have one of the best commutes in London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been at the new company for a few months now. We're pre-launch and don't have too much to say about what we're up to yet, but the high level goal is to improve how information is stored and retrieved on the internet. If that sounds interesting, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fredrivett"&gt;my DM's are open&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="deeper-relationships"&gt;Deeper relationships&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I wrote about in my &lt;a href="https://fredrivett.com/2019/01/01/2018-change-of-plans/"&gt;last year in review&lt;/a&gt;, 2018 was all about a change of direction, from being intensely focussed on work and my ambitions to run my own startup, to realising that as humans we have needs that go beyond just food and drink, that we're made for connection and community too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result I stopped travelling and settled back in London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then my focus has been primarily on working on the neglected areas of my life, building up a community of friends to "do life" with. As we all know, these things take time, especially in a city as big and busy as London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having only spent six months of 2018 in London, 2019 was a year of moving beyond the shallow into deeper relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest example of that was a calculated risk, starting a relationship with my best friend in London. It all came about organically, and snuck up on me if I'm honest, but we ended up hanging out a lot and realised we liked each other quite a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm someone who takes these things very seriously, not wanting to be reckless with my heart or the heart of others. But we were such close friends and the possibility of something more was a risk we were both willing to take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end after five months together we decided to just be friends, but both came out of the relationship blessed and she's still a close friend of mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel at peace about the whole thing, as we made the best decision we could at the time, and in line with my philosophy of optimising for the least regret, I hand on heart have no regrets that we gave it a shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite having peace about the decision to be friends, it always hurts to lose a level of intimacy with someone you love, and it's been a process to readjust to what life looks like without that closeness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That process continues on in 2020, but I feel like I've grown and been blessed through it, despite the inevitable pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="writing-on-the-daily"&gt;Writing on the daily&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start of the year I decided to begin a new habit, writing 300 words a day. It was a spur of the moment decision, lying in bed at 10pm on January 1st, seeing that &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ow/status/1079396926515220482"&gt;Owen Williams had launched a platform for developing a daily writing habit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kept the habit up for longer than I'd banked on, writing daily until the middle of May, 131 days in a row, almost 60,000 words in total.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The habit was a healthy one, helping me convert thoughts and feelings, often unconscious, into words swiftly. This helped me understand what was going on inside of me, and certainly flowed easier over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After over 4 months I decided to let it go though, as I'd gained more than I'd hoped for from the start and the discipline of a daily habit not paying enough back for me to justify the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="adventure"&gt;Adventure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2019 I travelled a decent amount without feeling like I was away all that much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early in the year I headed to Scandinavia for the first time, with &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BucLUC4gGjO/"&gt;a quick trip over to Stockholm&lt;/a&gt;. It was pretty cold, and having booked the trip about 9 hours before the flight was due to take off the next morning, not taking a coat turned out to be a mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the lingering snow on the ground I enjoyed my time in the Swedish capital. Wandering the streets of a new city with my thoughts is one of my favourite things to do, and I loved eating good food and exploring the beautiful, &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Buvs-FUA1BA/"&gt;peaceful underground world that is Stockholm's subway&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon after that I popped out to the South of Spain, to see &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/martinstellar"&gt;@martinstellar&lt;/a&gt;, a good friend who I hadn't met IRL until then. I spent a bit of time in Malaga on my own before heading east to his place, and we had a good time eating good food and drinking good wine, seeing the local area and zip-lining across the countryside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up was a quick weekend trip away with the family, seeing my brother who'd popped back over from Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the Easter weekend I then &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BwhjCItAwd5/"&gt;went away to a lovely cottage with some close friends for a few days&lt;/a&gt;. It was a really nice time chilling out in the countryside under the sun. It was the first time I'd driven in a few years too, thankfully I hadn't forgotten how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that came a &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/B3nZObdnrHi/"&gt;wild camping trip up in Scotland&lt;/a&gt;. I'd only ever visited Scotland twice before, never going further north than Edinburgh, so an opportunity to spend some quality time in the scenic highlands was one I was well up for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was expecting good scenery, but the beauty I encountered up there went above and beyond anything I'd been hoping for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was such a beautiful time with good friends that will live long in the memory. Despite the challenges, camping on hard ground, putting up tents and airbeds in fading light and rain, there's nothing quite like the pure adventure of setting off with a tent and no real plan, and just following your nose. My favourite trip of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not long after Scotland, it was off to Italy with some friends to celebrate the girlfriend's birthday. We had a beautiful time in Puglia, were very fortunate with the warm weather despite it being October, and came back with hearts full, blessed by our time away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the final month of the year I used my new found spare time to visit a good mate of mine in Dortmund, Germany. I shot a proper gun for the first time, and though I have no love for guns it was a good experience to feel just how powerful these weapons are. We &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/B53tfSwHU3X/"&gt;played 3D indoor glow-in-the-dark minigolf&lt;/a&gt;, ate good food, had deep chats and laughed well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final trip of the year was a domestic one, popping up north to see some old friends, celebrating a 30th birthday, and getting some space to take stock of another year come and gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="in-summary"&gt;In summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall this year has been great, despite not really achieving &lt;a href="https://fredrivett.com/2019/01/01/2018-change-of-plans/#my-goals-for-2018-were"&gt;any of the goals I set last year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hit the gym more than any year before, experienced a new depths of love and intimacy in relationships, worked two jobs where I learnt a lot and saw quite a few new places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the challenges of the end of the year, I feel extremely blessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It reminds me that in life storms come to us all, and our goal shouldn't be to try to avoid them. We often can't predict when or where a storm will come from, but instead should focus on putting in place solid foundations, so that when the storms come, and they will, we won't crumble and fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my track record of setting goals not being that great, I'm not going to put many specifics down on what 2020 will hold for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going through a break up can be healthy though, giving a chance to take stock of life and use the energy for good. I've started down that path, going to the gym on the way to work, and want to continue to build healthy habits over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One current idea is to look to use my ability to work remotely more, with a very tentative idea of aiming for one trip a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally I'd like to ship a side project next year too. I've not had the energy, capacity or motivation to work on any in the past couple years, since focussing my energies on other areas of life, but the itch came back for the first time last year, and I finally feel some capacity to get my feet wet again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm aware of my limited energy for this though, so will be looking to work on something sufficiently small enough that I can get it out there without a significant push pre-launch. I've already started dabbling on a couple things, so we'll see what comes of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of all, I want to continue on the path I've been on. To continue to love, to risk, to be vulnerable. To continue to optimise for the least regret, to optimise for experiences, for learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 2020 bringing up the big 30 for me this year, it's a good opportunity to take stock and make the most of the time I have on this planet we call home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of us know how long we have, and as George Bernard Shaw once put it, "youth is wasted on the young". I want to do my best not to waste the blessings I've been given.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final point, is on the closing of a decade. It's been a fantastic ten years. There's been unexpected challenges, time's when I didn't know how I would get through and time's of joy I did not expect to have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are things I would do differently if I had my time again, but most of all I'm grateful for the undeserved blessings in my life. The decade has had too much to write about now, but maybe I'll write another post on that down the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I'm glad to enter 2020. I'm entering it as a human with fears and vulnerabilities, but confidence and excitement too at the new adventures that lie ahead. And I'm determined to work on my posture and perspective, so that as and when opportunities come, I'll be ready to grab onto them with both hands.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Symphony of Life</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2019/09/03/the-symphony-of-life/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2019/09/03/the-symphony-of-life/</id>
    <published>2019-09-03T11:30:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2019-09-03T11:33:14+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A diversity of focus is a contradiction of terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No-one can focus on multiple things at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do so is to focus on nothing at all, to be pulled this way and that, like
spaghetti, intertwined, messy, unstructured, meaningless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lack of focus disturbs our soul. A lack of focus necessarily leads to a lack
of purpose. Purpose comes when we have a meaning to our lives, when we're
working towards something. And we cannot work towards that which we cannot see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We like to keep life in tidy little boxes. Relationships here, work there,
worldview here, passions there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life isn't like that though. And life conspires, at times, to remind us of
that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tidy little boxes get flung up into the air, and we watch in slow motion,
as we fearfully wonder how it'll all land together again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life shows itself as messy in these times. It shows itself as the complicated
beast it is, with its insides exposed, the truth on show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it's not the whole picture. It's just the messy one. It's just the only one
we can see right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life can be messy, but it can also be pure. It can also be meaningful. It can
also be clear. It can be messy and all of these things at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference between confusion, stress &amp;amp; anxiety and clarity, peace &amp;amp;
hope, is often in our perspective, not in the things themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As humans we need stories. We need to understand how things fit together, how
each moment is part of a bigger whole. It's how we make sense of what we see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when everything gets thrown up in the air, that's when our stories break
down, and when the noise returns to overwhelm the signal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peace returns only when we start piecing the parts together again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It comes when we learn to see life not as separate boxes, not as parts to be
tamed, but as a chorus, as a symphony of noises, each playing their part, each
no longer simply a noise, but a melody, a song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's when focus can resume. When the distinct parts of our lives that felt so
separate, so unsure, so anxiety inducing, come together to form the symphony of
our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's where the magic happens. That's where beauty resides. That's when we
flow again. It's where we come alive.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Digging in the Dirt</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2019/04/18/digging-in-the-dirt/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2019/04/18/digging-in-the-dirt/</id>
    <published>2019-04-18T18:40:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2019-05-06T20:08:27+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you've ever tried to build a business, you'll know what I'm talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That slow, painful growth, where things move forwards step by step but in slow
motion, when you're putting in a tonne of work but not yet seeing the fruits of
your labour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In SaaS businesses this is felt tenfold, and has come to be known as the &lt;a href="https://baremetrics.com/blog/long-slow-saas-ramp-of-death"&gt;Slow
Ramp of Death&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's upwards trajectory, but it's so slow that many die on these straits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the weekly mastermind call I'm a part of, we were chatting about the
realities of starting a business, and my buddy
&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/bendell"&gt;Ben&lt;/a&gt; mentioned something that stood out to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Slow Ramp of Death kills many, but there's something before that, something
just as important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pre-Slow Ramp of Death Ramp of Death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's that time before you're even on the Slow Ramp of Death, when you're
wrestling with other challenges that all have to come before you even get a
solid foot on the incline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's that time when you're working out what you really want from life, what's
really motivating you, when you're getting a grasp of what makes you tick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's that time when you're learning to make space for something new. When
you're setting up foundations before you even begin the real building work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And these times are essential. Glamorous no, but essential nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not everyone will experience them to the same degree. For some the foundations
will fall into place without too much conscious effort, but simply as a
by-product of the path they've been on. But others have to purposefully
cultivate the ground before being ready to plant the seed and grow the tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've experienced these times before, and I'm experiencing them again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2009, I stopped working on my own business goals to focus on other areas of
my life. This was not something I wanted to do, but in hindsight set me up well
for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2016, I stopped working on my immediate goal of building a business (with my
buddy &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mikeaag"&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt;) to work on our ability to ship
anything at all. I didn't want to do this, setting aside six months felt like a
lifetime. But it was the best six months of our business building progression,
and as it turns out, six months isn't that long after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then again in 2018, I stopped working on building a business to take care
of myself, to focus on other important parts of life that I'd neglected for
years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years I worked nearly every waking hour. It didn't feel like work. I
enjoyed it. But whether you enjoy it or not, spending &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of your time on one
thing leads you to being lopsided, and it did for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I made an adjustment, I stepped back. Now, in Spring of 2019, 16 months on,
I'm still in that Pre-Slow Ramp of Death Ramp of Death. I'm still not out of
that pre-slope slope. But I'm making progress. I'm moving forwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's a frustrating place to be, tbh. Having goals and aspirations, but not the
drive to pursue them, not the desire to make them happen right now. Having
other more important priorities that need tending to first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's hard when you build an identity in being a certain type of someone, and
then stop taking any surface actions towards that path. It's quite humbling to
leave behind something you've been building for years, not knowing if you'll
ever pick it back up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My focus has been elsewhere, honestly. It's been looking after the human Fred.
On setting foundations for &lt;em&gt;life&lt;/em&gt;, not just for business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The journey hasn't been one I sought out to go on. But it's one I felt I needed
to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The steps I took last year were into the unknown. Stepping away from
&lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; into, well who knows what.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But sometimes we have to make room. Sometimes we've got to make space for the
new, before we can expect it to come forth, before we even know what &lt;em&gt;it is&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that's been my life the past 16 months or so. And I'm still there. Making
room for whatever process I need to go through, for however long that might
take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's funny looking back. I see how each time I took what looked like a
backwards step I came back far stronger. I traded in some time for something I
didn't &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to do, but felt I needed to. I worked on my weak spots
specifically, instead of simply doing what looked like the most business-y
thing to do, the best surface level actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So having spent over a year in this latest step back, it came as a welcome
surprise when, this weekend, I caught the first glance of a breakthrough, a
glimpse of the season ahead. The first ray of sunshine breaking through the
clouds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first time in 16 months, I actually wanted to work on a side project. I
didn't even work on one, but for the first time in almost 500 days, that old
drive peeked its head above the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd forgotten what that felt like if I'm honest. Since the turn of the last
year, I've &lt;em&gt;wanted to want to&lt;/em&gt; work on side projects. I've wanted to force
myself back on the treadmill, back into "productivity". But I've not &lt;em&gt;wanted&lt;/em&gt;
to be there, back on that path. Not until this Saturday just past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've just not felt I've had the capacity for it. Everyone has limited brain
space, and I've just needed to allocate more resources to other parts of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure what it all means. I'm not sure what tomorrow holds, whether the
drive and desires of previous Fred will return. And I'm doing my best to be ok
with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what I do know is this: we're more than just business building machines,
and the challenges don't start post-launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's a battle that starts long before that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As any architect worth their salt knows, great skyscrapers are built on solid
foundations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don't have to justify why we're digging in the ground and not putting up
shiny things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We've all got our own journey to go on. Sometimes we have to take a step back
before we can take several strides forwards.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>2018&amp;#58; A change of plans</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2019/01/01/2018-change-of-plans/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2019/01/01/2018-change-of-plans/</id>
    <published>2019-01-01T12:44:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-01-01T13:13:11+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;2018 reiterated to me the feeling that life isn't always predictable as we sometimes think. The path I've taken isn't quite what &lt;a href="http://fredrivett.com/2018/01/01/2017-a-year-of-two-halves/"&gt;I planned on this time last year&lt;/a&gt;, with different challenges and opportunities than expected, but I'm thankful for it as I've grown as a person through the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start of the year I was in Australia, visiting my sister and her family having spent Christmas with them after a few months of travelling through Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Australia had been the last stop in my route, a date in the calendar I knew I was going to hit. Before then I planned loosely, up to a month in advance, but always had the certainty of Christmas in Australia. So as Christmas and New Years passed, I began wondering where next? What does the future hold?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After doing some research I settled on Bali, having heard lots of good stuff about it, and planned on spending 1-2 months working solidly, doing a little paid work but mostly attempting to build up a business with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mikeaag"&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt;. I even bought an extended visa upon arrival in Bali, so I didn't have to leave after a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fredrivett/status/952929626019446784"&gt;But as I sat in Bali&lt;/a&gt;, and even as I was leaving my sister and her family behind in Australia, I felt quite lost. Where should I be in the world? What should I be doing? Am I living my "best life"?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess you could say I had my own late-twenties life crisis. Some of the best months of my life were those I had just lived, travelling alone through Japan, Hong Kong, Malaysia and more, but deep down I sensed living solo wasn't right for me, not now at least. I needed to settle down somewhere, at least for a little while, and find my community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="change-of-plan-back-to-england"&gt;Change of plan, back to England&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in late January, after a short stint in Bali, I arrived back in the UK. I had a friend's wedding to attend which I was glad (and surprised) I was able to make having expected to miss it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wedding came and went, and I still wasn't entirely sure where home should be. Honestly, I felt quite lost at this time, and spent a couple of months staying with friends whilst working remotely and trying to figure out my next steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was during this process I made one of the hardest decisions of my (relatively easy) life, to step away from working on building a business with Mike. This took a couple of months of wrestling with, as a big part of me wanted to keep doing what we'd set out to do 10 years before (build a business together), but I couldn't shake the feeling I needed to make space with a clean slate for what would come next. I wasn't to know it but this decision gave me room for what would come next. (Shoutout to Mike here, the way he handled the process and the strength of our friendship since is testament to how much of a good guy he is.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn't until a brief trip out to Madrid that I gained some perspective. As the plane was descending to land at Madrid airport, I felt a sense of peace that I should move back to London. Those of us that believe there's more to life than matter might say God was speaking to me, others could put it down to the dots finally connecting and the path ahead revealing itself. Either way, I felt I had my answer, I was to move to London and settle down, at least for the next 6-12 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Madrid, I had a quick stop off in Berlin to see my friend &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/_niwilai"&gt;Nico&lt;/a&gt;, and headed back to London. After a couple days of frantic flat hunting, I found a place and put down a deposit. A month later, after another quick last minute trip around the world to see my bro in Canada and sister in Australia, I arrived back ready to move in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After deciding to move to London I contacted those I knew from working in the city before in case anyone knew of any opportunities. One of those I spoke with was &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/pace"&gt;Barry&lt;/a&gt;, who unexpectedly pitched me on starting a startup with him, as part of an incubator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wasn't an offer I was expecting, but after a couple of weeks of weighing it all up, I decided I was in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="starting-a-startup"&gt;Starting a startup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main reasons for agreeing to join the incubator was to work with Barry. I'd worked with Barry before, and admired his product skills. As an aspiring founder myself, product was an area I wanted to develop in, so getting to work alongside him was a big pull.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The role itself was outside my comfort zone, as prospective CTO. As someone who comes from a front-end background, I hadn't really considered myself as the CTO-type. I thought that CTO's were backend developers who enjoyed architecting server setups in their spare time. But after chatting to some CTO's I knew and some I didn't, they convinced me that this was a role I could grow with. After all to start with I'd be the Chief Technical Officer of one, me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since taking on the role, I've learnt a lot. Technically, working with React Native for the first time and getting my feet wet with AWS; from a product perspective, going through the process of discovery with Barry; and understanding myself and my motivations and strengths/weaknesses better as a founder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set out to work on building a mobile news app for younger folks (18-24yo). The premise being, how can we take what we know from the world of habit building products like Snapchat and build habit loops in the news? &lt;a href="https://thedot.news"&gt;The Dot&lt;/a&gt; was our first stab at this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past 6 months have been a real learning opportunity and I've enjoyed living outside my comfort-zone and testing myself. I'm grateful for the opportunity &lt;a href="https://foundersfactory.com"&gt;Founders Factory&lt;/a&gt; have given me and I'm proud of the work we've done so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="my-goals-for-2018-were"&gt;My goals for 2018 were:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id="run-10k"&gt;✅ Run 10k&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This I achieved, and it was actually quite a bit easier than I expected. &lt;a href="https://www.strava.com/activities/1453090541"&gt;I started running in early March&lt;/a&gt;, and although &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fredrivett/status/975683244116074497"&gt;progress wasn't noticeable early on&lt;/a&gt;, things didn't take long to pick up. 57 days after I started training, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fredrivett/status/993094110516039682"&gt;I ran my first 10k&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This timeframe isn't recommended, I went from running 5k to 10k in one swoop of excitement at hitting my goal, and later in the year paid the price with an achilles injury. But this is to say that we humans are far more capable than we think, running a 10k felt almost impossible for me after years of physical issues, but was actually far more within my grasp than I realised. For years I placed a ceiling above what I could do, this year I smashed through that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="k-mrr"&gt;❌ 10k MRR&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This goal I didn't hit, having stepped away from any personal business projects when I had the hit-the-reset-button moment at the start of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="travel-visit-5-new-countries"&gt;❌ Travel (visit 5 new countries)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one was a fail too, when my plans changed from travelling to settling down I left this one behind. That said I still visited four new cities (Melbourne, Madrid, Honolulu and Edinburgh) as well as heading back to Sydney, Vancouver and Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="my-goals-for-2019"&gt;My goals for 2019:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having thought at length about my goals for 2019, I realised my project this year is me. My goal is a healthy Fred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've read others online who have gone through therapy, and at times earlier in the year I realised I'd bottled up some emotions rather than dealing with them at source. Some say everyone should do therapy at least once in their life, so this year I want to give therapy a shot, even a minor increase in peace/happiness/health is worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondarily I want to take my fitness goals to the next level. Running 10k was about getting my legs moving again after a years of physical issues and feeling limited by them. This year I want to be playing football again regularly, as well as get in better physical shape (stronger, leaner, more flexible). To do this I'm going to put my money where my mouth is and work with some professionals who can help guide me in how best to achieve the outcomes I'm going after. Some of these specific goals will probably change after discussing with professionals, but for now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To have at least one month (4 sessions) therapy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To be playing football regularly again&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To be able to touch my toes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To be able to see my abs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gain 5kg in muscle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well that's a wrap, folks. Here's hoping 2019 is the best year yet for you, that you live life like never before and come out of it with no regrets. Let's do this 💪&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>2017&amp;#58; A year of two halves</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/01/01/2017-a-year-of-two-halves/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/01/01/2017-a-year-of-two-halves/</id>
    <published>2018-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-02T05:17:29+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;2017 has been the hardest year of my life. It started with an overhang that had been building up in the final moments of 2016, which finally exploded in spectacular style. Most of why this year has been the hardest of my (comparatively easy) life so far is personal and involves others, so I won't go into much detail, but suffice it to say, it's been challenging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="act-1-we-are-fragile"&gt;Act 1: We are fragile&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A family member had quite serious mental health challenges this year, which put a big strain on both themselves and the family as we tried to support them. Mental health is slowly becoming less taboo to talk about and gladly so, and being a little open about the challenges we've faced is my attempt to play my part in that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't know how close to breaking point I was, but it's the closest I've come. When someone in your family goes through fundamental challenges that affects the core of how they think and act it puts a strain on all those close to them, those who love them and want to help, but are often unable to, at least in the quick fix manner we'd like. All we can do is walk alongside them, have patience and do our best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are fragile human beings, more so than we'd like to admit. The whole situation was one of fragile humans trying to help fragile humans and in doing so almost breaking themselves. A big lesson I've learnt is that we have to look after ourselves. I have to look after myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They advise adults to fit their oxygen mask before their child's for good reason. We desire to fit the child's mask first but in doing so we risk damaging ourselves into a state where we can't help at all. There's no bravery in running ourselves into the ground trying to help others. We must take care of ourselves, at least keeping our head above water, so we can continue to help others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the storm was at its strongest, I had no choice but to take time out. I started a daily habit of meditation, deliberately taking time for myself to slow down, breathe and just be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, along with being brutally honest with two close friends, was the best thing I did. When things are tough it's super important to spread the weight as much as possible, and simply talking about the issues helps ease the pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside this, I found out I had a growth and would need surgery. Having never been knocked out before I was a pretty apprehensive. Would I wake up? What if something went wrong? Thankfully nothing did, and I can't speak highly enough of the surgeons, nurses and doctors who helped me this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running alongside this were further serious issues that came out of the blue that aren't appropriate to go into here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three of the biggest challenges of my life hit all at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year was so damn brutal, being attacked on every side at once, that in one sense I couldn't help but laugh and applaud 2017 for being so outrageously co-ordinated in its attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.makeameme.org/created/im-not-even-okwpfs.jpg" alt="not even mad" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="act-2-im-off-to-see-the-world"&gt;Act 2: I'm off to see the world&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite all the challenges this year, we came through them as a family and the second half of the year I have been ridiculously blessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A goal I set at the start of the year was to visit a new continent. I've wanted to explore the world and have my eyes opened to new cultures for over 4 years. This year, after recovering from surgery, I finally got myself together and headed for Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've spent the past 12 weeks moving around 7 countries, meeting lots of different folks, eating lots of different food and seeing lots of different cultures. I realise I am beyond blessed to be able to travel and work at the same time and try daily to not take it for granted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I was quite apprehensive about travel. I'm naturally introverted and despite being far from socially awkward, I am more comfortable in the company of good friends or on my own, than chit chat with strangers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feared that travel, with the constant flow of new people, would be overwhelming, and that despite my dreams, I would in fact quickly realise it wasn't the idyllic picture I'd painted and I'd swiftly return to England and my comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully I've thoroughly enjoyed it so far. Yes, there are challenges, there are things I miss, mainly having a group of friends I can "do life" with day to day, but setting off on my travels has been the best decision I've made in a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I've come to realise is that solo travel is actually easier for the introvert than the extrovert. As an introvert, you're largely self-sustaining. Everyone needs an element of community, but introverts need it less so than extroverts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've spent the vast majority of my time on my own, exploring cities by walking them whilst listening to an audio book. I've loved being able to set my own schedule, exploring when I'm up for it, resting when I'm not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FredRivett/status/933573040222248960"&gt;I've loved eating when I want, not when I traditionally should&lt;/a&gt;. At one stage I got into the habit of only eating one main meal a day at around 3:30-4:30pm. By this time restaurants are super quiet and there's no queue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've found the time to think and ponder really valuable. When you're on your own you have time to properly grapple with things. Travel has taught me a lot about myself, what I need and what I don't.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ending the year at my sisters place in Australia has been perfect. It's been great to spend time with her and her family over Christmas and New Years. Everyone's family is different, but family is an important part of my life. I'm so blessed to have been able to spend the end of the year here making memories with those I love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="progress-but-slower-than-id-like"&gt;Progress (but slower than I'd like)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big part of my life right now is working towards financial freedom, where our business supports both &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mikeaag"&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt; and myself. We've made progress this year launching &lt;a href="http://usercompass.com/"&gt;UserCompass&lt;/a&gt; and gaining our first couple of paying customers. Things have moved slower than I'd like though, which is partially due to the challenges at the start of the year, and the travels in the second half. Mike has also been working full time, which has slowed things quite a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike has now left his full-time job and we'll both be focussing on the business this year. My challenge will be balancing a bit of client work to cover costs, some travel and the focus on our work. It's a good problem to have though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another area I've been experimenting with is &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FredRivett"&gt;daily tweetlogging, or twogging for short&lt;/a&gt;. I'm still not entirely sold on the idea, but hope that over time the thread will become an interesting insight into the day to day of building a business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="a-few-highlights-from-2017"&gt;A few highlights from 2017&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id="places"&gt;Places:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Greece: Earlier in the year I was fortunate to spend 2 weeks on a small Greek island. I loved how relaxed it was, being able to get to know the locals was a nice change from most holidays. It's here I decided I'd set off for Asia.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Japan (Tokyo + Kyoto especially): This is a mysterious place to me, with great food and a unique culture. To sum it up in one line: The ATMs are from the 80's and the toilets are from the future.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hong Kong and Taipei: Two cities with a mix of amazing food and beautiful landscapes. I hope to return to both.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id="books"&gt;Books:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.audible.com/pd/Bios-Memoirs/Shoe-Dog-Audiobook/B01CRM17MS"&gt;Shoe Dog by Phil Knight&lt;/a&gt;: A great insight into the reality of starting a global brand and the luck required along the way.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.audible.com/pd/Nonfiction/Ghost-in-the-Wires-Audiobook/B005H3FYR4"&gt;Ghost in the Wires by Kevin Mitnick&lt;/a&gt;: A thrilling insight into the life of one of the worlds most wanted hackers in the 1980's.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.audible.com/pd/Business/Principles-Audiobook/B074B29GQJ"&gt;Principles by Ray Dalio&lt;/a&gt;: A thought-provoking handbook that challenges long held ideas about how to run a successful company.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.audible.com/pd/Business/Principles-Audiobook/B074B29GQJ"&gt;Masters of Doom&lt;/a&gt;: A topsy-turvy true story of how two John's revolutionised the gaming industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="goals-recap--2018-goals"&gt;2017 goals recap &amp;amp; 2018 goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id="my-goals-for-2017httpfredrivettcom201701012016-a-year-of-learning-were"&gt;&lt;a href="http://fredrivett.com/2017/01/01/2016-a-year-of-learning/"&gt;My goals for 2017&lt;/a&gt; were:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sort out my legs to get running and playing football again.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get a stranger on the internet to pay us a monthly fee for a product we make.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visit a new continent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I achieved 2/3, but again neglected and procrastinated on sorting out my health. It was a high level goal that I never took seriously with day to day actions. This year I'm determined to do what I can to get my legs sorted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike mentioned to me his desire to get running in 2018, and we've both decided to commit to running a 10k in 2018. 10,000 metres isn't far, but for two guys who have hardly ran the past 10 years, it's a goal that's hopefully achievable yet will still be a huge change for us. Whatever it takes, I need to get myself out there and redeem my health. Life's too short to procrastinate on something so important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="my-three-goals-for-2018"&gt;My three goals for 2018:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get my legs sorted so they're strong and healthy (run a 10k)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Support ourselves from product work (napkin maths says around $8k+ MRR)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Travel as much as I can (visit at least 5 new countries)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
