<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-08-11T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Super Powerful</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/08/11/super-powerful/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/08/11/super-powerful/</id>
    <published>2016-08-11T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-08-21T12:05:34+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It had happened again. We had failed, again. Just over two years ago, we had tried to create a website builder specifically aimed at plumbers. But after working on it for over three months, we threw in the towel. Yet again we'd failed to launch anything at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why were we so hopeless at launching?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="tell-someone"&gt;Tell Someone&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting goals can be powerful. You set your mind on getting into shape each new year, and for the first few weeks you do quite well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then, your progress falls away, the habit doesn't stick and you go back to your old ways. Until next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can we increase our chances of following through on our goals? Thankfully there's one relatively simple step you can take that's proven to significantly increase your chances of following through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tell someone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sharing your goal with others is powerful. As soon as you tell someone you're going to do something, your inner desire to be true to your word kicks in. This inner drive then competes with your procrastinating, lazy, Homer Simpson drive, and oftentimes wins, leading you to override your old habits and achieve your goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The science backs this up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;"Prompting people to monitor their progress can help them to achieve their goals, but some methods of monitoring are better than others. Specifically, we would recommend that people be encouraged to record, report or make public what they find out as they assess their progress."
&lt;cite&gt;Psychological Bulletin, Vol 142(2), Feb 2016, 198-229.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="regular-public-goals-are-super-powerful"&gt;Regular public goals are super powerful&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nbashaw"&gt;Nathan Bashaw&lt;/a&gt; shared a video where he talked about &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PS6-B_eFF-Q"&gt;the power of regular, public goals&lt;/a&gt; and it really resonated with me. He explains how not only are regular, public goals beneficial for you, but they also help to set expectations for your audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your audience knows that each week or month you’re going to deliver, they know you’re taking this seriously, and can decide whether they want to get involved. Much better than simply saying "sign up to hear when I’ve got something to say."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the key:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Regular goals are powerful, public goals are powerful and regular, public goals are &lt;em&gt;super powerful&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, this was a key lesson we had to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="how-we-went-from-never-launching-to-launching-six-projects-in-eight-months-due-to-regular-public-goals"&gt;How we went from never launching to launching six projects in eight months due to regular public goals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important changes we made after our latest failure a couple years back was to get serious with deadlines. To stop messing around working on projects with no real end in sight, but instead to set short-term, regular, attainable deadlines for shipping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We'd grown so tired of continually failing to launch that we were desperate. We knew this was a lesson that we had to ingrain deep into the core of how we worked, so rather than aim to launch one project in one month, we set ourselves the goal of launching &lt;a href="https://blog.wearecontrast.com/introducing-sixbysix-217d608362#.jeqjudq9a"&gt;six projects in six months&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of setting this goal we decided to share our progress, blogging regularly about how we were getting on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, these two ingredients, setting regular goals and sharing them, were the single biggest changes we made, and they have had a huge impact on our productivity since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since setting that goal we've launched &lt;a href="https://wearecontrast.com/"&gt;9 new projects&lt;/a&gt;, including &lt;a href="https://learningtolaunch.co/"&gt;a book that shares what we learnt from the whole process&lt;/a&gt;, nearly all of that whilst working full-time jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We're now able to launch &lt;a href="https://blog.wearecontrast.com/make-stuff-ff82f78cf5a9#.i7ilu5kan"&gt;new side projects from scratch over a weekend&lt;/a&gt; when previously we'd spend months and have nothing to show for it at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re nothing special. Others have done this with far greater success than us. Just look at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/levelsio"&gt;Pieter Levels&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Levels set himself a goal to launch &lt;a href="https://levels.io/12-startups-12-months/"&gt;12 startups in 12 months&lt;/a&gt; a few months before we set out on our goal. How'd he do? He's now on ~$30k MRR from these projects. Not bad if you ask me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can't speak for Levels, but I know for us, the combination of setting regular goals and sharing them publicly drastically increased our output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regular public goals have been super powerful.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="but-now-its-time-to-up-my-game"&gt;But now, it’s time to up my game&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a few months and here I am, ready to take the next step. To step out with my latest, regular, public goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal this time? Writing. I want to write more. As well as this, Mike and I are also starting a new podcast in the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's no good saying we'll podcast when we want – we have to set ourselves regular goals. The same goes with my writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's why, for both these goals, we're committing to shipping weekly. Every week we'll ship a podcast episode. Every week, I'll ship a new blog post. Every week, we'll have people waiting to receive our &lt;a href="https://wearecontrast.com/"&gt;weekly email in their inbox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here I am, telling you. Telling you we're about to do something we've never done before, and do it regularly. Pretty intimidated by that fact, as I write this on my train home from my day job. Scared we'll flop publicly and make a fool of ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I know the power of regular public goals, so I'll harness it for all its worth. It's time to step out again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="where-do-you-want-to-be"&gt;Where do you want to be?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where do you want to be in six months time? What do you need to change in order to get there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's time to get serious. I challenge you: set at least one regular, attainable goal this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write a blog post &lt;em&gt;and share it&lt;/em&gt;. Or if that's too much, hit reply to this post and let &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd love to hear it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Fumbling Forwards</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/08/03/fumbling-forwards/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/08/03/fumbling-forwards/</id>
    <published>2016-08-04T00:29:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-08-21T12:05:35+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The other week &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@mijustin"&gt;Justin Jackson&lt;/a&gt; shared a quote, one that I desperately needed to hear. It was from a &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@pjrvs"&gt;Paul Jarvis&lt;/a&gt; post, with the basic premise that &lt;a href="https://medium.pjrvs.com/success-is-for-the-lucky-579e30576eb2#---0-112.sqaw038a0"&gt;success is no scientific endeavour&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is the only common thread with successful entrepreneurs: they keep trying different ideas until one sticks.
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mijustin/status/756736947926827010"&gt;@mijustin on twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No-one likes to feel like they don’t have a clue what they’re doing. But that’s pretty much what starting a startup is like 24/7. Every day you wake up, and work on a bunch of tasks you were never trained to do. You attempt to solve a bunch of questions that you’ve never answered before. None of us really know what we’re doing, but it never looks like that. You look up at those who’ve experienced success, and wonder, do they have something I don’t?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparing ourselves to others isn’t the answer. Sure, it’s great to learn lessons from those we admire, but expecting to be able to compare the inside view of me now, at this point in the journey, to those towards the top, towards the peak of theirs, is never going to be much use other than to stress us out and demotivate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to success isn’t having everything together with a five year plan of how you’re going to take over the world, but rather, it’s not letting the unknown, the new, put you off from moving forwards, instead using that as fuel, pushing you forwards into your next adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s not ok to feel like you’re blagging your way through your startup. It’s essential. Anything else is delusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no rules, you see. There are only best practices, that apply sometimes, not others, and evolve over time. It’s great to learn the basic rules of the game, but these will only serve to give you blurry guideposts to prompt further thought. There are no easily digestible ‘unpack and add water’ tips that will immediately push your startup forwards. There are just a bunch of ideas that have worked in the past and will probably give you a rough nudge in the right direction when you’re unsure which path you should be on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re all fumbling forwards in the darkness, desperately trying to find the path forwards. And most of the time we don’t even know where forwards is, with nothing more than a very general sense of direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your ducks will never be in order. You don’t one day graduate from startup school and receive a nice simple business where all the questions are answered and the path forwards is easy, simple and clear. The view from the top isn’t what it looks like from down here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t have less problems as you go forwards, you just have a different set. You graduate from one set of problems to the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re like us, searching for the right problem to solve and product to build, then listening, brainstorming, testing and iterating are huge. Later, should we get there, customer service, scaling, hiring and leading likely await. Each step has its own challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I feel pretty lame about where we’re at. We’re committed to &lt;a href="https://prodigo.co/"&gt;starting our own startup&lt;/a&gt;, and it being successful, but we don’t even know if what we’re working on now will be what we’re working on in three months time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we’re learning. Learning about the audience we want to serve, about problems we enjoy solving, about ourselves. That’s all that can be said. We’re in a better place now than we were six months ago, that’s what matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Progress is incremental, remember that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re struggling with your startup, understand you’re not alone. Be sure to get accountable with where you’re at. I highly recommend joining a mastermind group that meets weekly to discuss current successes, failures and issues. If you’re not in one already, having this accountability, support, and outside perspective will be huge for you and your business. Reach out to a few like minded people on a similar path to you and see if they’re up for it too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But most of all, don’t be ashamed of where you’re at, or what you’re doing. Be like us, just skeletons with flesh doing laps around the sun, desperately trying to work out what on earth we’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you struggling to keep on top of your startups monthly recurring expenses? We were, that’s why we’re building &lt;a href="https://prodigo.co/"&gt;prodigo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prodigo is a simple app that gives you actionable insights into the tools and services you’re paying for.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re early stage and would love to shape this with you. If you’re interested you can sign up at &lt;a href="https://prodigo.co/"&gt;prodigo.co&lt;/a&gt; ✍️  or &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FredRivett"&gt;say hi and we can chat&lt;/a&gt; 👋&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Make Stuff</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/06/08/make-stuff/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/06/08/make-stuff/</id>
    <published>2016-06-08T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-08-07T18:57:32+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A week ago &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/marckohlbrugge"&gt;Marc Köhlbrugge&lt;/a&gt; released a neat little side project. The premise was simple, pay to get featured on the site. We’ve seen this before, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.milliondollarhomepage.com/"&gt;The million dollar homepage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The twist here? The more you pay, the higher you’ll be featured on the leaderboard. This gamified the system, with individuals and companies paying more and more for the highest position. Marc managed to use his existing networks to bring the initial burst of traffic through, and pretty soon the ball was well and truly rolling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want some traffic to your site now would be a good time to participate: &lt;a href="https://highscore.money/"&gt;http://highscore.money&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you want some traffic to your site now would be a good time to participate: &lt;a href="https://highscore.money/"&gt;http://highscore.money&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/marckohlbrugge?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@marckohlbrugge on twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And by the end of the day Marc had done &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@marckohlbrugge/how-i-made-2-251-in-1-day-with-highscore-money-dd56b35b2681#.i58k99t77"&gt;pretty well&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sort of project clearly comes under the silly little side projects umbrella. It was an opportunistic attempt to make a quick buck, whilst providing value to those who paid for a slot and having fun along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As makers, quick side projects like this help flex our creative muscles. I don’t think Marc intended this to be a fully fledged business, he’s already focussed in on his main gig, BetaList, but that didn’t stop him spending a few days creating this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst following Marc’s launch day progress, one tweet from Marc struck me, and got me thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What's a good, privacy-friendly real-time website counter?
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/marckohlbrugge/status/737388891246891008?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@marckohlbrugge on twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the second time I’d seen a request for some form of user facing site stats. A few weeks before, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mijustin"&gt;Justin Jackson&lt;/a&gt; had written &lt;a href="https://justinjackson.ca/webmaster/"&gt;I’m a fucking webmaster&lt;/a&gt;, and wrote &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=11685868"&gt;this comment on his Hacker News post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;BTW: does anyone know of a lightweight, retro “hit counter” that can grab my GA stats and display them at the bottom?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pattern was forming here, enough for me to mention to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mikeaag"&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt; that this might be something for us to explore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike and I have been working on side projects for years, but only recently have we got into the habit of actually launching them. Having set ourselves the challenge to launch &lt;a href="https://blog.wearecontrast.com/introducing-sixbysix-217d608362#.gpqkok2i1"&gt;six projects in six months&lt;/a&gt; at the end of 2014, we’ve launched &lt;a href="https://www.producthunt.com/@mikeaag/collections/i-made-that"&gt;8 side projects since&lt;/a&gt;, including writing our first book about the whole process, &lt;a href="https://learningtolaunch.co/"&gt;Learning to Launch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More recently though, we’ve been focussing on thinking through problems we want to solve, areas of tech we’re interested in, potential markets we’d enjoy helping. We’ve been thinking a lot about the startup we want to build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to get stuck in analysis paralysis. It’s important that we keep moving forwards. That’s why, this past weekend, we spent most of it hacking together a small side project, inspired by Marc’s tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="introducing-real-time-users"&gt;Introducing Real Time Users&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you’ve gotta have some fun and build stuff. That’s what Marc did, and that’s what we decided to do, too. Real Time Users is a little side project that makes us smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real Time Users is vulnerable, it exposes the truth of how popular your site is. Go to it anytime, and you’ll likely be greeted by the fact you’re the only person on the internet there. That’s both beautiful to know, that you are alone on this piece of internet real estate, and, as a creator, leaves me feeling slightly exposed. You know how popular my site is. For us at least, that’s a new level of transparency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Partially inspired by Marc’s leaderboard, we’ve included &lt;a href="https://realtimeusers.bycontrast.co/leaderboard"&gt;one of our own&lt;/a&gt;. If you take the 60 seconds and add Real Time Users to your site, you’ll likely take up one of the top 10 slots, until at least 8 others add it to their sites too. You’ll be able to see whether anyone ever adds this to their site, simply by tracking whether those top 10 slots ever fill up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m proud of it, proud because, having discussed it a few times during the week, we only really got to work on it this past weekend, and by Sunday evening we were pretty much ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a walk with Mike the other night I asked him, how long would it have taken us to launch Real Time Users pre-SixBySix? His answer: &lt;em&gt;we’d have never shipped it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s right &lt;em&gt;(don’t tell him that)&lt;/em&gt;. We wouldn’t have. We would have added feature after feature, built with needless shiny technology, and delayed launching month by month as we strived to build the next Google Analytics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since SixBySix, we’re much quicker to launch, and the quality has improved too. Our first project, &lt;a href="http://howsitgo.in/"&gt;HowsItGoin&lt;/a&gt; took 250 hours to ship. Real Time Users took under 15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what we’ve learnt, these past eighteen months. Ship stuff. Keep moving forwards. Learn as you go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Building and launching stuff is a skill, a habit, a muscle. The more you do it, the better you get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spending the past month or so thinking through what we want to be focussing on, the business we want to build, has been an essential step. But sometimes we need to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FredRivett/status/737384708024238084"&gt;step away from the magic whiteboards&lt;/a&gt; and get back to making stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who knows what’ll come of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This broadcast was brought to you by We Are CONTRAST Ltd. If you enjoyed this show, you may enjoy similar offerings, such as &lt;a href="https://blog.wearecontrast.com/why-you-don-t-have-to-quit-your-job-to-get-started-but-not-having-a-life-helps-ea9bdb230bcd#.tyo5zi1wt"&gt;Why You Don’t Have to Quit Your Job to Get Started (But Not Having a Life Helps)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://blog.wearecontrast.com/how-a-tweet-inspired-a-christmas-hackathon-ed2973ff0689#.55f0z9q63"&gt;How a Tweet Inspired a Christmas Hackathon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://blog.wearecontrast.com/10-easy-steps-to-launching-your-side-project-bbff783b08a8#.d5lsoac46"&gt;10 Easy Steps to Launching Your Side Project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://learningtolaunch.co/"&gt;Did we mention we wrote a book. It’s free. Like, totally free. You should read it 👀 📖&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How To Start Out When You're Just Starting Out By Someone Just Starting Out</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/05/17/how-to-start-out-when-you-re-just-starting-out-by-someone-just-starting-out/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/05/17/how-to-start-out-when-you-re-just-starting-out-by-someone-just-starting-out/</id>
    <published>2016-05-17T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-08-07T20:38:02+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: This post consists of a brain dump of my current thoughts about how to best start a startup when doing it for the first time (which I currently am). I do not expect there to be only one way of doing this, this post is intended to spark discussion, so I would love to hear others opinions on this to see similarities / differences.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id="find-interesting-problems-whether-funserious-and-try-to-solve-them"&gt;1. Find interesting problems (whether fun/serious) and try to solve them&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my experience, it’s a fair whack easier to try and solve problems &lt;em&gt;you’re intimately aware of&lt;/em&gt;, than to try and observe and fix problems &lt;em&gt;other people&lt;/em&gt; are experiencing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might sound obvious, but my approach to moving from where I am right now to where I want to be is &lt;em&gt;incremental&lt;/em&gt;. For a long time I used the approach of &lt;em&gt;shooting for the stars from day one&lt;/em&gt; and for a long time &lt;a href="http://wearecontrast.com/2014/11/introducing-sixbysix/"&gt;I failed to ship anything at all&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, it makes sense to me to keep things as simple as possible, all the while making progress. That means trying to solve a problem you’re experiencing, before trying to solve someone else’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of similarities between the two, but solving your own problems trims away the burden of observing other users and learning what their problems look like. Keep it simple. Start now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="build-quick-and-dirty-mvp"&gt;2. Build quick and dirty MVP&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what I’ve spent 90% of my spare time doing for the past year, along with my &lt;em&gt;partner-in-crime&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://medium.com/u/67a4475456c"&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt;. We realised our problem was trying to make a fully-featured perfect product from day one. We’ve learnt the hard way, spending years before learning this lesson. &lt;em&gt;It doesn’t work like that.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, we committed to going from zero launches ever (unless you count &lt;a href="http://arethensawatchingme.com/"&gt;that silly little site&lt;/a&gt;) to &lt;a href="https://www.producthunt.com/@fredrivett/collections/things-i-ve-made"&gt;six in six months&lt;/a&gt;. We overshot on this by a few months, due to complications in the final project, but &lt;em&gt;learnt a tonne&lt;/em&gt; in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having the ability to take an idea, build it and launch it in the least time possible is a hugely important skill for wannabe entrepreneurs to learn. In my experience it has opened up a world of possibilities, knowing I can take an idea from concept to launch in a matter of weeks changes how I see potential projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the fact we’re &lt;em&gt;solving our own problem&lt;/em&gt;, customer research here can be minimal at best. We built &lt;a href="http://flashtabs.co/"&gt;FlashTabs&lt;/a&gt; in a weekend, fixed the bugs in the evenings of the week following, then shipped it. We knew the problem, so quickly built a solution and put it in front of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In reality, this part is where most of us fall down. We have this grand vision, start building it, but then somewhere down the line, with no end in sight, we give up. Mike and I know this intimately having lived there for many years. As a result of that, and our progress since, we’ve spent the last few months writing a book on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There are so many “gotcha’s” that can cause our work to never see the light of day that we wanted to put it down in words so others can learn from some of the mistakes we’ve made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We’re releasing it online, &lt;strong&gt;for free&lt;/strong&gt;, for anyone to read. Take a look. We’d love your feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Read: &lt;a href="https://learningtolaunch.co/read"&gt;learningtolaunch.co/read&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id="launch-it"&gt;3. Launch it&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put it out there. Push it out to people who might find it useful. Find communities where they hang out and share it there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve built your thing, it’s time to share it. &lt;em&gt;This step is not optional.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it something the early adopter tech community might be interested in? Look at how you can get it on &lt;a href="https://www.producthunt.com/"&gt;Product Hunt&lt;/a&gt;, and post it up on &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/"&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;. Is there a &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/reddits/"&gt;sub-reddit&lt;/a&gt; where these people hang out? Post it there, explaining how you’re trying to solve a problem you’re experiencing and that you think they might be too. Write an introductory post on Medium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it more niche? Think of a few places they hang out and go there. Just be sure to get some of your potential target market to get their eyeballs on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="see-who-gravitates-towards-it"&gt;4. See who gravitates towards it&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve built and launched your product, you should hope to see some users start to gravitate towards it. This might be a handful, or it might be hundreds, depending on what you’re building and how easily you can reach that market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Equally, depending on what you’re building will dictate how much variety you’ll find in the audience that gathers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re building a relatively generic product, like a time tracker app, then you may find a variety of different types of users start using it, and each may have their own reasons for doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, it makes sense that if what you’ve built is clearly aimed at a more specific use case, then there will likely be less variety in the crowd that gathers and less variety in their needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://howsitgo.in/"&gt;HowsItGoin&lt;/a&gt; was launched as a very simple, generic web app to set and answer questions, tracking your results as you go. After launching we found a wide variety of ways people were using it, from fitness tracking, to journalling, to productivity tracking. There were many routes we could go and many problems we could focus on solving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://founderskit.co/"&gt;FoundersKit&lt;/a&gt;, however, was a specific product aimed at a specific market. We knew exactly the type of user we wanted to attract before even we’d launched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, take stock of the crowd that you draw, and look at the different groups that form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="gather-feedback"&gt;5. Gather feedback&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve launched, and you’ve got a bunch of people using your product, you should be actively looking to gather feedback on how it’s being used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s here you’ll want to focus on what problems your users are trying to solve and how well your current product is solving these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From our experience you can get a small initial batch of feedback (5–20 responses) from having a simple, prominent feedback call-to-action on your site. Tools like &lt;a href="https://www.typeform.com/"&gt;Typeform&lt;/a&gt; are perfect for this, taking minutes to setup and providing a simple UX for your users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If users were prompted to enter their email address in the registration process then you can look into reaching out to your user base and talking to as many of them as are willing to jump on a call with you. If they aren’t happy to jump on a call, then you can fall back on emailing your questions or pointing them to your survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking to your users and hearing how they describe their problems and their thoughts on how well your product solves this (and vitally where it’s lacking) is invaluable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="consider-whether-this-is-a-market-you-want-to-address"&gt;6. Consider whether this is a market you want to address&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might sound obvious, but just because a bunch of people are using your thing, you still need to work out if that’s a market you want to address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For us, with FlashTabs, we’ve got a whole bunch of self-motivated, relatively tech savvy individuals looking to learn a new skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do we want to target the B2C market? Do we still find this problem interesting enough to want to work on it and build it out? Can we ever see this making enough money to warrant the time invested in it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For us these are questions we’ve mulled over a lot. We could spin off a different product aimed at the same niche (web software for education), we could leave FlashTabs on auto pilot as is, or we could double down on it for a while and see if we can take this to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this stage you must decide, should I pivot or persevere?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For more on this, be sure to read the staple twenty-first century entrepreneurs handbook, &lt;a href="http://theleanstartup.com/"&gt;The Lean Startup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id="niche-down-hone-in-on-their-problems"&gt;7. Niche down, hone in on their problems&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve got your product out in the wild, you’ve found a market that resonates with it, it’s time to hone in on the problems your users are facing and solve these as best you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, I’m &lt;em&gt;massively&lt;/em&gt; oversimplifying this, a lot of blood, sweat and tears will be invested here, but now you’ve got a product and a market to work with. You’ve made a great start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to solve a specific problems before considering whether to expand or not. This is the famed, elusive &lt;a href="http://www.startup-marketing.com/the-startup-pyramid/"&gt;product/market fit&lt;/a&gt; that every startup is so desperately searching for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If at any stage you seriously consider whether this product and this niche can ever achieve your goals (which you probably will), it’s time to revisit point 6 above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="grow"&gt;8. …Grow?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve found that all elusive product/market fit, the real question is, what’s next? 99% of the time, in the startup world, that answer is grow grow grow. Take off. Shoot for the stars. And that’s a perfectly valid answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, it’s not always the route every entrepreneur wants to take. Not every entrepreneur envisions their life working 80 hour weeks, holding board meetings (growth requires capital requires investors) and taking their company public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every company is a lifestyle company, because surely you’re building a company because you want to live the lifestyle that comes with it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the kids say, &lt;a href="https://media.giphy.com/media/FuvVKU8Jxq1CE/giphy.gif"&gt;#yolo&lt;/a&gt;. If you don’t want to live the life of a big-time CEO of the next unicorn, &lt;em&gt;then don’t build that company.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, I want to create a great product, that helps people live better lives, and supports me and my family for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That might come in the form of running a large organisation, or it might come running a small, two person business for the rest of my life. Both (and everything in between) are viable options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Want to learn to launch? Tired of never shipping your side projects? This book is for you. &lt;a href="https://learningtolaunch.co/read"&gt;Head over and read it, for free&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>10 Easy Steps To Launching Your Side Project</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/02/22/10-easy-steps-to-launching-your-side-project/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/02/22/10-easy-steps-to-launching-your-side-project/</id>
    <published>2016-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-08-07T22:29:37+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h4 id="choose-the-most-ambitious-idea-you-can-possibly-think-of"&gt;1. Choose the most ambitious idea you can possibly think of&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll likely have a few different ideas of what you could work on. Always choose the most ambitious project of the lot. The bigger the project, the more money you’ll make, so be sure to shoot for the stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picture dreams of you launching this and becoming a billionaire soon after. Do this and you’re halfway there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, there’ll be some hard work on the way, but you’ve got a great idea right? And that’s gotta be worth &lt;em&gt;a lot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="brainstorm-every-feature-that-could-possibly-ever-be-useful-and-add-that-to-your-must-have-before-i-ever-launch-list"&gt;2. Brainstorm every feature that could possibly ever be useful, and add that to your ‘must have before I ever launch’ list&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone knows that all the successful websites started with fully featured perfectly designed sites, right? Every feature you dream up will play a vital part in your success, so don’t even think of launching without them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="reinvent-the-wheel-at-every-opportunity"&gt;3. Reinvent the wheel at every opportunity&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the point in using ready-made solutions when you can make your own? &lt;em&gt;Spoiler: there isn’t&lt;/em&gt;. Be sure to build everything from scratch. This will make it much easier when it comes to selling your idea for billions down the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="work-endlessly-with-no-deadline"&gt;4. Work endlessly with no deadline&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deadlines are for wimps. Are you a wimp? Then don’t set deadlines. What are you, a corporate manager? You’re a &lt;em&gt;creative&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/gAYL5H46QnQ"&gt;you won’t be a part of their system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="spend-as-much-time-and-money-as-possible-on-every-little-detail"&gt;5. Spend as much time and money as possible on every little detail&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortcuts are for losers. If you’ve got a few options in terms of how something could be done, always choose the most time consuming, expensive idea of the lot. Remember, your aim is to create the next Facebook, Snapchat or Peach (&lt;a href="https://blog.bufferapp.com/peach"&gt;Peach, anyone?&lt;/a&gt;). Do you think Mark Zuckerberg started Facebook by choosing the ‘quickest, most cost efficient option’? Of course not. Spend time and spend money at every opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="build-in-stealth-mode"&gt;6. Build in stealth mode&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to never speak to anyone about what you’re working on, because everyone will realise &lt;em&gt;how great your idea is&lt;/em&gt; and will surely steal it. Everyone else is starved of ideas and on the hunt for new ideas to steal. Your idea is &lt;em&gt;original&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;unique&lt;/em&gt;, no-one else could have thought of this because no-one else is you. Whatever you do, &lt;em&gt;do not share it&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="never-speak-to-any-potential-users-about-what-youre-working-on"&gt;7. Never speak to any potential users about what you’re working on&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users are dumb and have no place giving you feedback. There are two types of people, great visionaries like you, and low-life peons, the everyday users. What the user wants is irrelevant, you’re the ideas person, and you’ll be the one to decide whether your idea is the best thing since sliced bread or not. Thankfully you already have, it is, so it’s case closed on this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering ‘real world applications’ is a sure fire way to make your idea &lt;em&gt;lame&lt;/em&gt;. Are you lame? Then don’t contaminate your idea with the lame juice of lame people. That’d be lame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="be-sure-to-never-consider-why-youre-doing-this-in-the-first-place"&gt;8. Be sure to never consider &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you’re doing this in the first place.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most successful people in the world just do stuff, they don’t ever consider why. Who cares why? Why you’re doing something and your aims for it won’t influence what you’re doing. Instead, regularly take time to dream up new features that would make this &lt;em&gt;even better&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="stick-religiously-to-your-original-idea"&gt;9. Stick religiously to your original idea.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pivoting is for wimps. Since when did watering down your idea pay off? Instead, make sure to stick religiously to your idea, making sure to execute it exactly as you originally imagined. We’ve no time for compromises, the idea you had at the start was perfect and flawless, adapting it now is a sure fire recipe for &lt;em&gt;failing&lt;/em&gt; and becoming a &lt;em&gt;failure&lt;/em&gt; like all those users out there. You don’t want to be one of them, you’re the visionary, part of the elite, so stick rigidly to your idea, no matter what.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="except-nothing-less-than-perfect"&gt;10. Except nothing less than perfect&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you’ve been doing this a while, you may be thinking, &lt;em&gt;should I launch?&lt;/em&gt; Thankfully, the answer is simply. &lt;em&gt;No.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How could you launch now? You’ve not added that vital feature that everybody will use. Every time you near launch, remind yourself of the high standards of the unicorn elite. You’ve only got one shot at this launch, so it better be &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have realised by now, the tips above are a little &lt;em&gt;tongue-in-cheek.&lt;/em&gt; But you know what? That’s how a lot of us work, or at least how we start out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know for us, &lt;a href="https://medium.com/u/67a4475456c"&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; I used to follow the tips above almost religiously, never realising we &lt;em&gt;were doing it wrong.&lt;/em&gt; Thankfully these days we’ve learnt a few lessons. Just over twelve months ago, we’d never launched anything despite spending years working on side projects. Twelve months later, we’ve launched &lt;a href="https://www.producthunt.com/@mikeaag/collections/i-made-that"&gt;seven projects&lt;/a&gt;, rank inside the top 100 makers on &lt;a href="https://www.producthunt.com/"&gt;Product Hunt&lt;/a&gt;, had 72,000 users through to our projects and made thousands of dollars as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learnt that there were a few simple rules could turn an endless never ending cycle of doom into repeatable launch process. So we’re writing a book, sharing our story and what we’ve learnt, to help you get your launch game on too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to learn to launch? Tired of never shipping your side projects? This book is for you.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://learningtolaunch.co/?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=14-steps-never-launch"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up at learningtolaunch.co&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;to be the first to hear when we’re ready.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;FYI: This post took a combined total of 3h 16m to write, review &amp;amp; edit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
