<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-09-19T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>burnout</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/09/19/burnout/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/09/19/burnout/</id>
    <published>2016-09-19T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-09-20T13:00:31+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like listening? We recorded an episode of our brand new podcast on this very topic. &lt;a href="https://hitreply.co/3"&gt;Listen to it here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not letting one side outweigh and overpower the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work and life. Should these be balanced? Or should they be one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard a &lt;a href="http://www.vanschneider.com/worklife-balance-is-bullsht/"&gt;couple&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://designlife.fm/episode36/"&gt;opinions&lt;/a&gt; recently that attempting to achieve work-life balance is solving the wrong problem. When work and life go hand in hand, there’s no need to balance them right? If one succeeds, so does the other. It’s not a zero sum game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What then, are we to make of burnout?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is burnout only something that occurs when you’re working on something that doesn’t resonate with the rest of your life? Is it only when you’re working for The Man, be it your boss, or your VC, or even yourself?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we set ourselves unrealistic expectations, and drive ourselves to work every waking hour to get them done. For some of us, VC’s are putting an unspoken pressure on us that if we don’t work so hard that we sleep at our desks then we’re not really made for the entrepreneurial game. Sometimes our boss tells us of a hard deadline and we have to break ourselves just to get it done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been watching the latter first hand the past couple months. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mikeaag"&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt;, the guy I work with, co-founder, partner in crime extraordinaire, has been maxed out at work. He’s gone above and beyond his normal levels to fulfil a specific hard deadline at his day job. He’s running on empty, but feels like he needs to keep running to meet the requirements of his 9-5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike loves what he does, and enjoys our work on the side too. He’d go as far as to say that the work we do with &lt;a href="http://wearecontrast.com/"&gt;Contrast&lt;/a&gt; is a hobby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When your hobby is starting your own startup on the side, what does resting look like? Is it healthy to come home from an intense day at work and spend more time in the evening coding?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are questions that I’ve been thinking about lately, in a bid to avoid making things worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does it look like to be burnt out? I’ve not been there, but Mike’s pretty close. In this week’s episode of Hit Reply, I spoke with Mike about what it’s like from the inside, and our thoughts on whether it can be avoided, and if so, how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out: &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/hitreply/episode-3-burnout"&gt;https://soundcloud.com/hitreply/episode-3-burnout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each week I write a post and record a podcast episode. Get both in your inbox every Tuesday, free of charge. Sign up, no spam, I promise. &lt;a href="https://wearecontrast.com/signup"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes please&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>where are you going?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/09/12/where-are-you-going/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/09/12/where-are-you-going/</id>
    <published>2016-09-12T22:06:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-09-20T12:59:56+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like listening? We recorded an episode of our brand new podcast on this very topic. &lt;a href="https://hitreply.co/2"&gt;Listen to it here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of us desire control over how we spend our time. What output would produce this outcome? You could quit your job and live off benefits. You could work hard, become a contractor, and pick and choose when you work. Or you could start your own business, with a relatively self-sustaining income stream independent of how much time you put in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing where you’re going and how you plan on getting there is important. But how can you gauge your progress and make sure you’re on track?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years back some business consultants took my colleagues and I through a simple task that helped me to reshape how I see my time and money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They told us to think about any task we do from the lens of input, output and outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="input-what-are-you-spending-your-time-on"&gt;Input: What are you spending your time on?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost 2 years ago &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mikeaag"&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt; and I set ourselves a new challenge: to launch &lt;a href="https://blog.wearecontrast.com/introducing-sixbysix-217d608362"&gt;six projects in six months&lt;/a&gt;. This challenge had a primary input of time, an output of projects, and an outcome of getting better at shipping stuff, which is a key skill we needed to master if we were ever going to start our own startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the decisions we made when we started was to track our time on every task. We did this primarily out of curiosity, we were intrigued to see how long each project would take, and which parts would take the longest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was also a bit of a gimmick. We decided to share as much as possible during this time, blogging regularly and being transparent with our stats from every launch. That included time spent per project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were two noticeable effects of tracking our time almost religiously for that six month period. Firstly, we had the obvious benefit of having reports showing where our time was spent. This was an expected output. We also realised that the simple act of tracking our time helped keep us on track and productive during those times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="time-to-focus"&gt;Time To Focus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the clock was ticking, we were conscious that being distracted by Twitter or email would blur the statistics, making them less useful in the long run. This forced us to stay on track when the clock was on. Just as much, this gamified our time a little, leading us to want to spend more and more time on the things that were important to us, shipping side projects. We used &lt;a href="https://toggl.com/"&gt;Toggl&lt;/a&gt; to track our time, but there are other tools that can help give insight to where we spend our time, &lt;a href="https://www.rescuetime.com/"&gt;RescueTime&lt;/a&gt; being another popular one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pomodoro_Technique"&gt;Pomodoro technique&lt;/a&gt; on and off for the last few months, and it has a similar effect. It designates time to focus, 25 minutes on, 5 minutes off. In the 25 minutes of focus time, all distractions and thoughts that come to mind that are irrelevant to the task at hand are either quickly noted or ignored until later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a sense, the Pomodoro technique is a systemised way of procrastinating your procrastination. It leads you to think "ok I can do that in my 5 minutes off, its only 16 minutes away afterall".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to time tracking, seeing the count of Pomodoro’s achieved each day gamifies this, I aim to achieve 10 Pomodoro’s on the days I employ this method. That’s only 4 hours 10 minutes of actual work time, but is about the peak of output I can manage in any given day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often, the issue isn’t that we need to spend more time on important tasks, we just need to spend more &lt;em&gt;focused time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="go-deep"&gt;Go Deep&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m listening to a book on this right now, &lt;a href="http://www.audible.com/pd/Self-Development/Deep-Work-Audiobook/B0189PX1RQ/ref=a_search_c4_1_1_srTtl?qid=1473503170&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;Deep Work&lt;/a&gt;, which talks about the importance of focus, and techniques for achieving this deep state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It comes to a conclusion I’ve heard quite a lot recently: we all have a finite limit to how much concentration we can spend, and it's a lot less than we think it is. We don’t need to work longer hours, we need to work productively until we reach our limit, then take time off and refresh ourselves. Finishing work at 5 is late enough, too late by some standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deep Work mentions Charles Darwin’s routine. He used to wake up at 7, take a short walk, work from 8 until 12:15pm, which he considered the end of his working day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This flies directly in the face of the startup hustle culture we hear about so often: working through the night, sleeping less, or staying in the office until late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve Blank shared a story about this recently, about a CEO who was proud at how long his employees stayed in the office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This glorification of the ‘hustle’ is had its time. It’s outdated. &lt;em&gt;It’s not productive.&lt;/em&gt; You might force more through the funnel, but it will be of a lesser, diluted quality. You’d produce a better output (and therefore outcome) by spending around 4 hours of productive, focused time in Deep Work each day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, you need to do the work, and it can be scrappy at the start, but working long hours only says one thing: you don’t know how to prioritise and focus on the tasks that matter. You’re &lt;em&gt;inefficient.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you disagree with this statement and feel like you &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; need to work those long hours, I’d challenge you to track how much of your time is spent in true, deep, productive work, and how much is actually fluff that can be cut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="whats-your-output"&gt;What’s Your Output?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Measuring how much we output is a step in the right direction. Instead of simply tracking hours invested and wanting to invest more and more time, we can track what we’re achieving with that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since finishing SixBySix, we slowly stopped time tracking. We primarily tracked for the stats to share for each of the projects we made. It also came with a cost, of continually clocking on each time we did some work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days we track two key metrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is the most important: did we achieve our one key goal this week?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike and I have both recently joined a mastermind. A mastermind is simply a group of likeminded business people who get together each week and update each other on how the past week has gone for their business. Did we achieved our goal(s), what our goal(s) are for this week, and chat through any issues we may be having.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joining a mastermind a few months back was one of the best decisions I made this year. The accountability it brings to have to boil down all the ideas spinning around in my head to one key task to focus on each week is super important. Each week knowing I have to report back on whether I achieved this goal, and if not, why not, helps me stay on track. &lt;em&gt;It forces me to prioritise output over input, value over movement.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second metric we track is less important than our &lt;em&gt;one key goal&lt;/em&gt;, but gives a nice overview of our week’s achievements. It’s simply a list of all the tasks we did that week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our setup is simple: we have a Backburner where we capture the thoughts that occur to us in the shower, This Week for tasks we aim to complete this week, In Progress, and a weekly Done column.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each week we archive the tasks we achieved that week and create a fresh Done column, giving us an ever evolving history to look back on, should we ever want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two metrics combined help us to remain focused on our output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This setup works for us but you can track output however you like. If your goal is to learn, you could track number of books read, or number of discussions you’ve had with people of opposing views. If your goal is to help others, then you could set yourself a goal of helping someone every day, and have that as your key output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your key metric(s) can be whatever you’d like, just make sure it’s not the number of cat videos watched per week. Cats are great ‘n’ all, but probably not the key metric to help gauge whether you’re on track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="where-is-your-life-going"&gt;Where Is Your Life Going?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where do you want to be in 6 months time? In 5 years time? What are you working towards?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it to be physically fit? To raise a loving family? To get a promotion at work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For us, we want to start our own startup. Everything we do is centered on that. This desired outcome drives the outputs we look to achieve (shipping side projects, building a following etc.), which in turn drives the inputs we put into the machine (reading and writing, coding, designing, developing products, meeting other founders).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in the intro, there are many ways to achieve every goal we have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each of these examples, the inputs will be different. Starting a self-sustaining business is vastly different to contracting, and it goes without saying quitting your day job looks very different still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s where we often get this mixed up. We place too much focus on the input, little on the output, and nowhere near enough on the outcome. Rarely do we stop and weigh up whether what we’re doing is helping achieve the outcomes we desire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simon Sinek puts this well, in his &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sioZd3AxmnE"&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt; (and &lt;a href="https://www.startwithwhy.com/"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt;), Start With Why. In this talk, Simon shares how most of businesses are &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; focussed, selling customers on the specifics of &lt;em&gt;what they do&lt;/em&gt;. The best companies, however, talk about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;they’re doing it&lt;/em&gt;. Customers of Apple buy into the philosophy that Apple cares about everything they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly for us, we need to frame every &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; around our key &lt;em&gt;why’s&lt;/em&gt;. Every action we take should be initiated by the core &lt;em&gt;why’s&lt;/em&gt; of our life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we come to this place, the next step is really nailing, what are my why’s? What do I want from life? It’s here that a very simple exercise, The 5 Why’s, can help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 5 Why’s, simply asks "why?" five times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For us, we can ask, why do we want this outcome? Is the outcome really what we want, is there a higher motivation above this all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our example of desiring more control over how we spend our time, why is this? Is it because we hate our day job? Is it because we have desires to use our time in ways we can’t right now? To travel? If so, there may well be ways to achieve these higher outcomes without having full control over our time. We could take a sabbatical, saving frugally for years at a time, then spending six months travelling the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important point here isn’t the specifics of the example, but that knowing what we &lt;em&gt;really want&lt;/em&gt; is vital if we’re ever going to get it. If we’re truly honest with our desires and goals, we can start tweaking the machine to produce the life we desire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read a quote a couple years back from &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/nbashaw"&gt;Nathan Bashaw&lt;/a&gt; that’s continually stuck with me in the back of my mind since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;"When you look back 6 months from today and don’t feel embarrassed by your naiveté, there’s a problem."
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nbashaw"&gt;Nathan Bashaw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rrhoover/status/550308425972740096"&gt;https://twitter.com/rrhoover/status/550308425972740096&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter where you’re at right now. You can’t affect where you stand, or the circumstances around you. What matters is &lt;em&gt;whether you’re making progress towards where you want to be.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So take stock of your inputs, where you’re spending your time, but don’t glamourise how long you spend at the office, or even what you’re creating. Focus on the impact your work is having, on others, on yourself, and whether it’s moving you close to where you really want to be. That’s what really matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each week I write a post and record a podcast episode. Get both in your inbox every Tuesday, free of charge. Sign up, no spam, I promise. &lt;a href="https://wearecontrast.com/signup"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes please&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>launch</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/09/05/launch/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/09/05/launch/</id>
    <published>2016-09-05T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-09-06T12:49:56+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[You can also find this blog post &lt;a href="https://blog.wearecontrast.com/launch-c3968191a5b7"&gt;on Medium&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this week’s blog post I attempt to answer the questions: &lt;em&gt;What does it look like to launch from the inside?&lt;/em&gt; And &lt;em&gt;How on earth did we get to second on the Hacker News homepage?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like the sound of that, &lt;a href="https://hitreply.co/1"&gt;this weeks episode of our new podcast, Hit Reply, is all about launching&lt;/a&gt; (sound of that, get it, get it?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week we launched a new project that we’ve been discussing for a couple months, our first ever podcast, &lt;a href="http://hitreply.co/"&gt;Hit Reply&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hit Reply is a podcast that gives you an inside view on what it’s like to start a startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past two years, we’ve spent our evenings, weekends and holidays building and launching stuff. Before that, we weren’t very good at launching. In fact, we were awful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since doubling down on shipping side projects, &lt;a href="https://www.producthunt.com/@fredrivett/collections/things-i-ve-made"&gt;we’ve launched 9 in the last 2 years&lt;/a&gt;. Hit Reply, is our 10th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hit Reply is a bit different to the rest. Most projects have one main "we’re here!" launch, when the curtain comes down and the masses (hopefully) swell in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hit Reply though, is a podcast. We’ll be releasing a new episode &lt;em&gt;every week&lt;/em&gt;. Every Tuesday, we get another shot at another little release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Podcasts have been growing in popularity. New podcast episodes can now vie for a place on &lt;a href="http://www.producthunt.com/"&gt;Product Hunt’s homepage&lt;/a&gt;. As well as that, lots of the tech folks over at &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/"&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; listen to podcasts. A fact that we hadn’t quite fully realised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday the countdown to our first episode had just ticked over to &lt;em&gt;0 days, 0 hours, 0 minutes&lt;/em&gt;. It wasn’t live yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the week off work, and I’d had quite a relaxed morning, going through my new morning routine. 10 minutes meditation. 5 minutes free flow writing. 10 ideas. Exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d underestimated how long it would take to make the final edits to our first episode, and the tweaks that we’d need to make to the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About two and a half hours after our scheduled launch time, we were ready. &lt;a href="http://hitreply.co/"&gt;Episode 0: Yet Another Startup Podcast?&lt;/a&gt; was live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sent out our email to our weekly list, and that was that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, a little later than planned, we submitted our first little episode to Product Hunt. We were keen to see how much traffic Product Hunt sent to podcast episodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within half an hour or so, it was doing relatively well, even competing with YCombinator’s interview with Jessica Livingston (spoiler: they won).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a sort of side note, we submitted the episode to Hacker News. For us, Hacker News is much more of a mystery. Due to the free-for-all nature and size of the system, we’re never quite sure what will happen when we submit something to Hacker News. You can easily get lost in the masses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We submitted it, and left it at that. A few minutes later we started to see some upvotes trickle in. Who was that? People were upvoting &lt;em&gt;our podcast?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About fifteen minutes in, I stumbled onto the homepage by accident. Wait, what’s going on? We’re #4 on the homepage? This can’t be right!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Erm erm erm erm erm erm erm
We’re 4th on HN homepage? Am i reading this wrong?
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FredRivett/status/770987008793702400"&gt;Tweet on the Twitters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It was right.&lt;/em&gt; We were 4th on the Hacker News homepage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then 3rd 😦&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We’re now 3rd. THIRD. ON THE HACKERNEWS HOMEPAGE.
I don’t know whats happening anymore.
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FredRivett/status/770987971772375040"&gt;Another tweet hits the twitters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then 2nd 😱&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How is this getting evening happening
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FredRivett/status/770988331584851968"&gt;Tweets keep rollin'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our little podcast was second on Hacker News.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few minutes, it began to slide back down a few slots, and sat most of the day between 5th and 7th. A pretty handy place to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what did we learn from this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="launch-early"&gt;Launch early&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 80/20 rule states that, for many events, roughly 80% of the effects come from 20% of the causes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This rule applies to launching too. We can all get to a point where we have a website with our first episode recorded. &lt;strong&gt;It’s often the feeling that you need to have all your ducks in a row that leads you to delay launching, oftentimes, forever.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason? &lt;em&gt;You’ll never have all your ducks in a row.&lt;/em&gt; There will always be things that could be done better. Never has there been a to-do list that’s actually empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to launching is to tick off the big wins. Get a website up. Record an episode with whatever equipment you have. Then share it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s really that simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We specifically took shortcuts to get Hit Reply to launch now. Our website is a bunch of simple PHP files that I knocked together. It’s a systemised mess. Over the long term it will slow us down a little, but we can tweak on the journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CSS is just CSS, not Sass, which I’d normally use. This was due to a roadblock that we’d hit in a previous project, that took a while to get around. Doing it this way wasn’t as nice or as fast to develop, but got the job done so we could move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We launched without being on iTunes. We weren’t even in apps like &lt;a href="http://www.shiftyjelly.com/pocketcasts/"&gt;Pocket Casts&lt;/a&gt;. People were wanting to subscribe on their favourite podcast app, and we weren’t there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Did we launch too early?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No. I don’t think so. We had to get the ball rolling with the podcast, we knew it was time to launch. We planned to submit our podcast to iTunes after a few episodes, and honestly hadn’t heard of Pocket Casts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We forgot to add an RSS feed for people to use to subscribe on their platforms, but soon corrected this with some quick changes on launch day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Equally, with the unexpected masses flooding in, we added a quick &lt;a href="https://realtimeusers.bycontrast.co/"&gt;real time user counter&lt;/a&gt;, a project we’d worked on a couple months before, to the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FredRivett/status/770991865135005697"&gt;https://twitter.com/FredRivett/status/770991865135005697&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="where-are-we-at-now"&gt;Where are we at now?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, in the aftermath of the launch, what was the result?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The podcast episode has had over &lt;a href="http://hitreply.co/ep/0/yet-another-startup-podcast/"&gt;950 plays&lt;/a&gt;, far more than we could have hoped for our initial launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/hitreplypod"&gt;twitter account&lt;/a&gt; has its first 21 followers (thanks). A small start, but nice nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve had some great feedback and we now know that some people are interested in listening. This is a big plus and one of the key questions to ask yourself when you launch, does anyone care?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But one of the biggest gains, &lt;a href="http://hitreply.co/"&gt;our email list&lt;/a&gt; has had 57 new sign ups, boosting it up from 202 subscribers to 259. That’s a nice healthy jump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="where-do-we-go-from-here"&gt;Where do we go from here?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now’s where the real challenge kicks in. Shipping something is a milestone, an achievement of sorts. Our previous projects were the result of a challenge we set ourselves to get better at shipping stuff, but this is an ongoing project. Each week, a new episode. Consistency here is key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to see how this grows. Our first ‘proper’ episode, &lt;a href="https://hitreply.co/1"&gt;Episode 1, is all about launching&lt;/a&gt;. Give it a listen if you’ve got a mo, and if you do, please &lt;strong&gt;Hit Reply&lt;/strong&gt; and let us know what you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to keep up to date with the podcast? Get a &lt;a href="http://hitreply.co/"&gt;small, simple email every Tuesday announcing the new episode&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="http://feeds.soundcloud.com/users/soundcloud:users:245437295/sounds.rss"&gt;subscribe to our RSS&lt;/a&gt; in your favourite podcast player.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Healthy Pressure</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/08/29/healthy-pressure/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/08/29/healthy-pressure/</id>
    <published>2016-08-29T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-08-30T14:47:12+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Pressure is healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Healthy pressure is, at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without pressure we wouldn’t have diamonds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pressure can keep us on track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can push us to go further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/the-mission/a-breakthrough-is-nothing-without-the-followthrough-87021be7f9b5#.xb7cplqvi"&gt;To follow through&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a part of a mastermind, and every week there’s a pressure to answer the question, "what did you do last week". That pressure is healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have internal pressure. "You talk about startups a lot, you better back up that chat with some action". This pressure is healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every day I get home from my day job late at night and feel tired, with a long to-do list ahead of me. I remember what I’m trying to do and what my future looks like. This pressure is healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I share my goals in public. This pressure is healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all pressure is healthy. Sometimes it can weigh us down rather than spur us on. In those cases, you’ve gotta throw that pressure off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What pressure are you under right now? Is it weighing you down, or pushing you on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throw off the heavy weights, but use some of that healthy pressure to push you forwards. Your future will be better as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Is Overrated</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/08/22/new-is-overrated/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/08/22/new-is-overrated/</id>
    <published>2016-08-22T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-08-30T14:47:14+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We'll always remember our first real lightbulb idea. For me it was late 2009, I was sitting at my desk, on a course that I soon realised wasn't really going to teach me anything that useful. Not that I knew everything – not at all – but the culture there wasn't exactly one of pushing you to be your best, they were just happy that we turned up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This day was different though. As I sat there, daydreaming (as I often do), I realised something – I love reading. I really wanted a place to keep tabs on what I'd read, and maybe add a quick review on what I thought. I'd also quite like a way of finding out what my friends were reading and what they recommend reading next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;"Oh! What if there was a Facebook for book readers! That'd be awesome!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="the-master-plan"&gt;The Master Plan&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening on the train home I rang &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mikeaag"&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt; to chat about the idea. We were both really excited about what it could be. We even came up with a super awesome codename (#blackhawk) so that no eavesdroppers would pick up on our idea and run off into the distance with our millions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then spent the next week writing up exactly what the site would do, what each page's purpose was and sketched out roughly how it would look. I had 6 or 7 pages of pure gold, or at least that's what I thought at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my plan in hand we agreed to meet up at a nearby pub. We sat in the garden next to a quiet stream with a good beer and talked it through. We spent a good couple of hours there going through the notes and discussing what the site would be. When we finished we both left excited about our first real idea, and soon got stuck into the design and development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a couple of months, we had an initial design, some code and a clearer view of the path ahead, including how we'd monetise the site. We were making progress, things were taking shape. Remarkably we were still just as excited as that day at the pub by the stream. What happened next definitely wasn't expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It goes without saying that when I had the idea, I did a quick Google to see if it already existed. You know, the 'Facebook for reading' search and then look at the top 3 results. But that's about as far as it went. &lt;em&gt;I wasn't looking for a competitor, so I didn't find one.&lt;/em&gt; We took this brief research as enough to say it hadn't been done and ploughed on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, now a couple months into development, Mike raised the question about whether this really hadn't been done before. We'd spent the last couple months working on this idea, but our initial research was limited at best. I told Mike that I’d done some research and hadn't found anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike did a quick Google. Oh crap. It's been done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there it was. Shelfari. Someone had done this already. We were late to the party. Very late as it turns out. Shelfari had launched 3 years earlier. And not only that, but they'd been acquired by Amazon too. Dammit. This idea &lt;em&gt;was awesome&lt;/em&gt;. But we'd missed the boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That sucked. We'd dreamed of our idea for months now and invested a good amount of time and effort into it. But it had been done, the dream was over, time to move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back on it, there were a number of issues with our approach. First, there was the whole OTT &lt;em&gt;list all the must have launch features&lt;/em&gt;. Then there was the locking ourselves away for months on end with our secretive idea, hoping one day we would be ready for the big unveil and that everyone would love it as much as we did. But the biggest issue was the fact that we gave up after finding out it had been done already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then we’ve learnt an important lesson:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;New isn’t important. Better is. Significantly better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="how-can-we-make-this-better"&gt;How can we make this better?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When considering a problem to solve, or an idea to work on, we shouldn’t be asking "are we the first to do this?" but “how is this problem currently being solved? How can we solve it &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt;?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new twist? A new package? Reworking a successful formula to be more applicable? More frictionless? Easier to access?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an idea to be worth working on you need to see the core of the problem already being solved, with at least some success. If your idea is going to be successful it will already have been done, somewhere, somehow. Your job is reshaping, repackaging and restarting it to capture a different need than currently applied to, or better capture an existing one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing other people already working on a similar problem isn’t just a non-issue, it's essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="whats-the-key-job-your-users-are-trying-to-get-done"&gt;What’s the key job your users are trying to get done?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://blog.intercom.io/using-job-stories-design-features-ui-ux/"&gt;Jobs To Be Done (JTBD) framework&lt;/a&gt; forms everything around one question, "what job is our user trying to get done here?". Are they trying to see their notifications so they can make sure they haven’t missed a message about an item they’re selling? It cuts to the core of what’s going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The principles behind the JTBD framework can be applied to us when we’re working out whether an idea has legs. We should be looking to boil our core problem down to one key &lt;em&gt;job to be done&lt;/em&gt;. Once we have this job, we can search to find out how people are solving this problem already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you’re looking to create a new app that scans and stores receipts, then you should be looking at how people are using tools like Evernote to solve this problem already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How are they using Evernote to keep track? Why are they using Evernote? What steps do they have to take? What’s good about this solution? What’s bad?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mijustin"&gt;Justin Jackson&lt;/a&gt; shares one way of finding answers to these questions: searching the places where people will likely be complaining about the issues they find. A great place to start is on Twitter. Searches like "Evernote problem" will give you a great starting point on some of the issues people are facing with Evernote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If people aren’t trying to solve this problem already, and dissatisfied with their solution, then this isn’t a problem worth solving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="for-us-we-want-to-help-businesses-know-where-their-money-is-going"&gt;For us, we want to help businesses know where their money is going.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other day I was chatting to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sethlouey"&gt;Seth Louey&lt;/a&gt; about the problem we’re trying to solve with &lt;a href="https://prodigo.co/"&gt;Prodigo&lt;/a&gt;, seeing whether he experienced the problem and if he did, how he currently solved it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seth did have this problem, and pointed us to the tool he was currently using. From there we found other similar solutions, also trying to solve the problem of tracking where you’re spending your money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My initial reaction was "oh it’s been done. Why are we working on this again?".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I still want to be the genius who sweeps in with an amazing solution to a problem that no-one has ever thought of and will totally redefine a whole industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally I want to feel like I’m the only one clever enough to have thought about this problem and proposed such an amazing solution. I want a blank space, I don’t want competitors already trying to solve this problem. I want it easy. Glorious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully it was at this point I remembered our previous experience with our ‘Facebook for book readers’ idea, and what we’ve learnt since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that people are already trying to solve this problem isn’t a problem, it’s essential if we’re to have any success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only reason to look at completion is to find out 'do people care about this?’. Then go on and solve it better than anyone else for your audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s what we’re going to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Super Powerful</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/08/11/super-powerful/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/08/11/super-powerful/</id>
    <published>2016-08-11T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-08-21T12:05:34+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It had happened again. We had failed, again. Just over two years ago, we had tried to create a website builder specifically aimed at plumbers. But after working on it for over three months, we threw in the towel. Yet again we'd failed to launch anything at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why were we so hopeless at launching?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="tell-someone"&gt;Tell Someone&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting goals can be powerful. You set your mind on getting into shape each new year, and for the first few weeks you do quite well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then, your progress falls away, the habit doesn't stick and you go back to your old ways. Until next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can we increase our chances of following through on our goals? Thankfully there's one relatively simple step you can take that's proven to significantly increase your chances of following through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tell someone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sharing your goal with others is powerful. As soon as you tell someone you're going to do something, your inner desire to be true to your word kicks in. This inner drive then competes with your procrastinating, lazy, Homer Simpson drive, and oftentimes wins, leading you to override your old habits and achieve your goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The science backs this up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;"Prompting people to monitor their progress can help them to achieve their goals, but some methods of monitoring are better than others. Specifically, we would recommend that people be encouraged to record, report or make public what they find out as they assess their progress."
&lt;cite&gt;Psychological Bulletin, Vol 142(2), Feb 2016, 198-229.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="regular-public-goals-are-super-powerful"&gt;Regular public goals are super powerful&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nbashaw"&gt;Nathan Bashaw&lt;/a&gt; shared a video where he talked about &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PS6-B_eFF-Q"&gt;the power of regular, public goals&lt;/a&gt; and it really resonated with me. He explains how not only are regular, public goals beneficial for you, but they also help to set expectations for your audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your audience knows that each week or month you’re going to deliver, they know you’re taking this seriously, and can decide whether they want to get involved. Much better than simply saying "sign up to hear when I’ve got something to say."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the key:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Regular goals are powerful, public goals are powerful and regular, public goals are &lt;em&gt;super powerful&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, this was a key lesson we had to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="how-we-went-from-never-launching-to-launching-six-projects-in-eight-months-due-to-regular-public-goals"&gt;How we went from never launching to launching six projects in eight months due to regular public goals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important changes we made after our latest failure a couple years back was to get serious with deadlines. To stop messing around working on projects with no real end in sight, but instead to set short-term, regular, attainable deadlines for shipping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We'd grown so tired of continually failing to launch that we were desperate. We knew this was a lesson that we had to ingrain deep into the core of how we worked, so rather than aim to launch one project in one month, we set ourselves the goal of launching &lt;a href="https://blog.wearecontrast.com/introducing-sixbysix-217d608362#.jeqjudq9a"&gt;six projects in six months&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of setting this goal we decided to share our progress, blogging regularly about how we were getting on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, these two ingredients, setting regular goals and sharing them, were the single biggest changes we made, and they have had a huge impact on our productivity since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since setting that goal we've launched &lt;a href="https://wearecontrast.com/"&gt;9 new projects&lt;/a&gt;, including &lt;a href="https://learningtolaunch.co/"&gt;a book that shares what we learnt from the whole process&lt;/a&gt;, nearly all of that whilst working full-time jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We're now able to launch &lt;a href="https://blog.wearecontrast.com/make-stuff-ff82f78cf5a9#.i7ilu5kan"&gt;new side projects from scratch over a weekend&lt;/a&gt; when previously we'd spend months and have nothing to show for it at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re nothing special. Others have done this with far greater success than us. Just look at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/levelsio"&gt;Pieter Levels&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Levels set himself a goal to launch &lt;a href="https://levels.io/12-startups-12-months/"&gt;12 startups in 12 months&lt;/a&gt; a few months before we set out on our goal. How'd he do? He's now on ~$30k MRR from these projects. Not bad if you ask me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can't speak for Levels, but I know for us, the combination of setting regular goals and sharing them publicly drastically increased our output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regular public goals have been super powerful.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="but-now-its-time-to-up-my-game"&gt;But now, it’s time to up my game&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a few months and here I am, ready to take the next step. To step out with my latest, regular, public goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal this time? Writing. I want to write more. As well as this, Mike and I are also starting a new podcast in the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's no good saying we'll podcast when we want – we have to set ourselves regular goals. The same goes with my writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's why, for both these goals, we're committing to shipping weekly. Every week we'll ship a podcast episode. Every week, I'll ship a new blog post. Every week, we'll have people waiting to receive our &lt;a href="https://wearecontrast.com/"&gt;weekly email in their inbox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here I am, telling you. Telling you we're about to do something we've never done before, and do it regularly. Pretty intimidated by that fact, as I write this on my train home from my day job. Scared we'll flop publicly and make a fool of ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I know the power of regular public goals, so I'll harness it for all its worth. It's time to step out again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="where-do-you-want-to-be"&gt;Where do you want to be?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where do you want to be in six months time? What do you need to change in order to get there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's time to get serious. I challenge you: set at least one regular, attainable goal this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write a blog post &lt;em&gt;and share it&lt;/em&gt;. Or if that's too much, hit reply to this post and let &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd love to hear it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
